<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/includes/blog-feed/atom.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Third-Party Claims Archives | Newburgh New York Workers' Compensation Law Blog]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/third-party-claims/" />
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/third-party-claims/atom.xml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2013-03-21:/blog/81520</id>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:26Z</updated>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[This is the Third-Party Claims archive for Newburgh New York Workers' Compensation Law Blog.]]></subtitle>
  <generator uri="http://www.sixapart.com/movabletype/">Movable Type Enterprise</generator>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Workers injured in Oct. bucket truck fall in Williamsville to sue]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2013/01/workers-injured-in-oct-bucket-truck-fall-in-williamsville-to-sue.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2013:/blog//81520.3244335</id>
  <published>2013-01-07T13:02:24Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:26Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[On Oct. 1 of last year, two Town of Amherst workers were taking down a banner above Main Street in Williamsville. They were standing on the platform of an elevated platform truck on that ordinary Monday morning when the top...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Third-Party Claims" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="brokenbones" label="Broken Bones" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="fallsfromheights" label="Falls from Heights" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="newyork" label="New York" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="thirdpartyclaims" label="Third-Party Claims" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="workrelatedinjuries" label="Work-Related Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="workerscompensation" label="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>On Oct. 1 of last year, two Town of Amherst workers were taking down a banner above Main Street in Williamsville. They were standing on the platform of an elevated platform truck on that ordinary Monday morning when the top of a semi-trailer struck the boom and both men were ejected and flung to the pavement 20 feet below.</p> <p>Both men were seriously injured and were transported to Erie County Medical Center. They survived, but suffered multiple injuries, including broken bones, according to authorities.</p> <p>The truck driver was accompanied by a woman and a child and was on his way back to Syracuse. Press reports do not indicate whether he was considered at fault in the accident,</p> <p>One woman, whose second-floor office was eye-level with the men's work platform lifted her head to the sound of the semi-truck striking the platform truck and saw the fallen men below, just before emergency workers arrived. She was relieved to see one of them move his leg and arm.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>The two men worked for the Town of Amherst's signal division. While compensation for injured workers employed by municipalities is somewhat different than the workers' compensation system for private employers, they likely received benefits through that program.</p> <p>However, they have now filed third-party claims against the Village of Williamsville and the Town of Amherst for failing to provide a safe work environment.</p> <p>In workers' compensation cases, there are many situations in which third parties -- parties other than the employer -- are partially responsible for the accident. In such cases, it is often possible to file third-party liability claims to hold parties such as subcontractors, vendors, municipalities and landowners to account for their negligence.</p> <p>Not only does this allow injured workers to seek appropriate compensation, but it also allows society to hold financially responsible those whose negligence or wrongdoing causes injury to others.</p> <p><strong>Sources:</strong></p> <ul> <li>WIVB-TV, "Workers injured changing banner to sue," Luke Smith, Jan. 3, 2013</li> <li>WIVB-TV, "Crash ejects workers from bucket truck," Emily Lenihan, Oct. 1, 2012</li></ul> <p>Our law firm helps injured people file workers' compensation claims along with <a href="/Workers-Compensation/Additional-Claims-Beyond-Workers-Comp.shtml">third-party liability claims</a> against those responsible for accidents and injuries. For more information, please see our website.</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--third-party-claims-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Workers' Comp Insurers Pay New York State $120 Million Settlement]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2011/01/workers-comp-insurers-pay-new-york-state-120-million-settlement.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2011:/blog//81520.3244302</id>
  <published>2011-01-31T12:03:30Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:22Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Four prominent workers' compensation insurance companies settled a lawsuit brought against them by the State of New York. The State alleged that the insurance companies Zurich Financial Services, Ace Ltd., Pennsylvania Manufacturers and CNA charged excess workers' comp surcharges. The...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Third-Party Claims" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
    <category term="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="claimsadjusters" label="Claims Adjusters" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="newyork" label="New York" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="workerscomplawsuit" label="Workers' Comp Lawsuit" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="workerscompensation" label="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Four prominent workers' compensation insurance companies settled a lawsuit brought against them by the State of New York. The State alleged that the insurance companies Zurich Financial Services, Ace Ltd., Pennsylvania Manufacturers and CNA charged excess workers' comp surcharges.</p> <p>The insurance companies claimed that NY Laws conflicted, creating confusion and the alleged excess surcharges. Additional <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/New-York-State-Workers-Compensation-Laws/">New York State workers' compensation laws</a> have been passed in recent years to eliminate the confusion, but New York State filed a suit seeking money from surcharges accumulated from 2000 to 2008. The parties reached an agreement earlier this month, with the four companies paying out different amounts reaching a sum of $120 million.</p> <p><strong>The NY Workers' Compensation Industry</strong></p> <p>The State's workers' comp industry is worth big money - nearly $6 billion each year. Unfortunately, some entities compromise their integrity in order to maximize their profits. In New York, one in six claims is disputed by the insurance carrier, for what could be one of several reasons.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Admittedly, some workers' compensation claims are fraudulent. Sometimes these cases make headlines, where a supposedly disabled person is caught performing hard labor such as landscaping, but not before collecting hundreds of thousands of dollars in workers' compensation benefits.</p> <p>However, the vast majority of workers' compensation claims have merit. Even so, the most honest claimants may still be subjected to electronic surveillance by a claims adjuster or third-party adjuster. They do not want to pay out big claims unless they have to, and they often put up a fight by denying workers' compensation claims.</p> <p><strong>Ensure your Claim gets Treated Fairly</strong></p> <p>New York workers' comp claimants may get their claims wrongfully denied or delayed. A workers' comp attorney can fight to ensure your claim gets treated fairly and expeditiously. A lawyer can also scrutinize other avenues to recovery, such as third-party claims and <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Social-Security-Disability-Insurance-SSDI/">social security disability insurance</a>.</p> <p>Source: Seer Press News</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--third-party-claims-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Horrific Construction-Site Accident Leads to Over $1 Million for Victim]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2010/10/horrific-construction-site-accident-leads-to-over-1-million-for-victim.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2010:/blog//81520.3244299</id>
  <published>2010-10-14T16:57:55Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:22Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[For most people, $1,141,734 seems like an unimaginable amount of money. Unfortunately, construction worker Jose Rivera didn't win the lottery - far from it, in fact. Rivera fell 30 feet through an open elevator shaft, fracturing his spine, ribs, and...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Third-Party Claims" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
    <category term="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="constructionaccidents" label="Construction Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="fallsfromheights" label="Falls from Heights" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="thirdpartyclaims" label="Third-Party Claims" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="workerscompensation" label="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>For most people, $1,141,734 seems like an unimaginable amount of money. Unfortunately, construction worker Jose Rivera didn't win the lottery - far from it, in fact.</p> <p>Rivera fell 30 feet through an open elevator shaft, fracturing his spine, ribs, and shoulder. So far he has undergone two surgeries, with the potential for more down the road.</p> <p>At first glance, some may think that it's ridiculous that a man was awarded such a large sum for his own carelessness or clumsiness. However, a closer look reveals that Rivera's nearly fatal fall was due to a third party's failure to do their job - not the fault of a man who was diligently going about his own work.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Dravins Development Group, Inc. was deemed responsible for providing notice to construction-site workers about the open elevator shaft, and was also supposed to use a barricade, or some other preventative method, to avoid potential falls. Since they failed to provide adequate notice and follow the proper safety protocol, Rivera suffered a <a href="/Construction-Accident-Injuries/Falls-from-Heights.shtml">devastating fall</a><b> </b>and will likely have to deal with painful, crippling injuries for the rest of his life.</p> <p><b>Third-Party Claims for Injured Workers</b></p> <p>Under New York law, an injured worker in Rivera's position could recover money for his injuries through the state's workers' compensation benefits. Additionally, the construction worker could also sue any responsible party, outside of his own employer, in what is known as a third-party claim.</p> <p><a href="/Workers-Compensation/Can-I-Sue.shtml">Third-party claims</a> allow injured workers to hold parties such as general contractors, subcontractors and equipment manufacturers liable when their actions create, or contribute to, a work injury.</p> <p>The third-party claim is an important tool for seriously injured workers to recover additional money when they are the unfortunate victim of another party's negligence. Although no amount of money can replace the loss of one's physical well-being, it can help to provide financial security for the injured victim.</p> <p>Source: <a target="_blank" href="http://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/114173388-judgment-obtained-for-victim-of-construction-site-injury-104092368.html">PR Newswire</a></p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--third-party-claims-->
</entry>

</feed>