<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/includes/blog-feed/atom.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Workplace Illness Archives | Newburgh New York Workers' Compensation Law Blog]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/workplace-illness/" />
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/workplace-illness/atom.xml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2013-03-21:/blog/701</id>
  <updated>2018-04-17T11:07:53Z</updated>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[This is the Workplace Illness archive for Newburgh New York Workers' Compensation Law Blog.]]></subtitle>
  <generator uri="http://www.sixapart.com/movabletype/">Movable Type Enterprise</generator>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Will your workplace illness expenses be compensable?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/04/will-your-workplace-illness-expenses-be-compensable.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//701.3231279</id>
  <published>2018-04-17T11:08:53Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-17T11:07:53Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Employees in various industries in New York are exposed to hazards in their workplaces that could be detrimental to their health. Sometimes a workplace illness develops over time, while others are immediately evident. Regardless, the victims might be unsure of...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceillness" label="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Employees in various industries in New York are exposed to hazards in their workplaces that could be detrimental to their health. Sometimes a <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">workplace illness</a> develops over time, while others are immediately evident. Regardless, the victims might be unsure of whether the workers' compensation insurance program will cover their particular occupational diseases.</p> <p>Some of the more common workplace illnesses include respiratory conditions that follow exposure to hazardous chemicals and biological agents, fumes, vapors, gases or dust. Resulting diseases include asbestosis, silicosis, beryllium disease, farmers' lung, occupational asthma, tuberculosis and many more. While these enter the workers' bodies through inhalation, skin disorders and diseases develop from contact or absorption of chemicals and other substances through the skin. It can cause eczema, contact dermatitis, friction blisters, oil acne, skin inflammation and chrome ulcers.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Exposure to excessive noise levels in the workplace can cause hearing loss, which is regarded as an occupational illness, although it's relation to a particular workplace could be difficult to prove because it might only become apparent after slow deterioration over many years. Then there is poisoning, which leads to the presence of toxic substances in the bodily fluids, tissues, blood or breath of a worker who either ingested or absorbed it through inhalation or the skin. Poisonous elements include metals such as mercury, lead, arsenic and cadmium or hydrogen sulfide, carbon monoxide and other gases. Also, organic solvents such as benzol and benzene, insecticides, and chemicals like formaldehyde can be poisonous.</p> <p>While these are some of the most frequently claimed occupational illnesses, the list of additional conditions that are covered by the workers' compensation system in New York is almost endless. Any worker who believes that his or her condition is a workplace illness can discuss it with an experienced workers' compensation attorney who can determine eligibility for benefits. The lawyer can also assist with the complex administrative and legal proceedings of the claims process.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>bls.gov, "<a href="https://www.bls.gov/iif/oshdef.htm" target="_blank">Occupational Safety and Health Definitions</a>", Accessed on April 13, 2018</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-illness-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Beryllium exposure enforcement might prevent workplace illness]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/03/beryllium-exposure-enforcement-might-prevent-workplace-illness.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//701.3179134</id>
  <published>2018-03-14T11:05:56Z</published>
  <updated>2018-03-14T11:04:56Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[The International Agency for Research on Cancer has declared beryllium as a carcinogen that can cause lung cancer. This is a severe occupational hazard, and the Occupational Safety and Health Administration announced the development of standards to protect workers from...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceillness" label="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>The International Agency for Research on Cancer has declared beryllium as a carcinogen that can cause lung cancer. This is a severe occupational hazard, and the Occupational Safety and Health Administration announced the development of standards to protect workers from contracting this <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">workplace illness</a>. Although March 12, 2018, was the set enforcement date, it was postponed to May 11 to give stakeholders in New York and other states the opportunity to study their obligations and to ensure consistency in OSHA inspections.</p> <p>The enforcement will involve reduced permissible 8-hour and 15-minute exposure limits for workers in the shipyard and construction industries. Beryllium exposure in construction occurs among welders, roofers, metal recyclers, metal fabricators and abrasive blasters. Airborne beryllium can be inhaled, and victims may develop chronic beryllium disease, which is a lung condition. However, exposure to beryllium solutions, fumes, dust or mist can also be absorbed through workers' skins, and it could cause cancer.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Workers who develop symptoms like shortness of breath, inexplicable coughing, weight loss, fatigue, night sweats and fever will want to seek medical care and specific evaluation of the effects of beryllium exposure. If not treated timely, chronic beryllium disease can develop into a more severe chronic obstructive lung disorder. Any of these diseases can adversely affect the worker's quality of life and even decrease life expectancy.</p> <p>Construction workers in New York may find comfort in knowing that the workers' compensation insurance program will likely cover the medical expenses for treatment of any workplace illness. An experienced workers' compensation attorney can provide the necessary support to get the appropriate care. The lawyer can also assist with the navigation of a benefits claim for coverage of medical costs and lost income.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>constructionequipment.com, "<a href="https://www.constructionequipment.com/osha-begins-beryllium-standard-enforcement-may-11" target="_blank">OSHA Begins Beryllium Standard Enforcement May 11</a>", March 5, 2018</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-illness-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[4 primary hazards that cause workplace illness and injury]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/01/4-primary-hazards-that-cause-workplace-illness-and-injury.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//701.3092132</id>
  <published>2018-01-15T16:30:56Z</published>
  <updated>2018-01-15T16:29:56Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Employees in New York may face a variety of dangerous situations every day. Safety authorities expect employers to protect workers against workplace illness or injury. However, regardless of the industry in which a person is employed, he or she may...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceillness" label="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Employees in New York may face a variety of dangerous situations every day. Safety authorities expect employers to protect workers against <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">workplace illness</a> or injury. However, regardless of the industry in which a person is employed, he or she may be exposed to any of the four common types of occupational hazards.</p> <p>Chemical hazards are typically posed by flammable, toxic or carcinogenic products that can damage organs and tissues. Biological hazards include parasites and microorganisms that can cause allergies and infections. Both these hazards can affect workers through skin contact, open wounds, inhalation and consumption. Employers must protect workers by providing the necessary personal protective equipment such as gloves and other protective clothing, safety glasses and respirators.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>An endless list of physical hazards exist across all industries, and safety guidelines are provided by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration. Employers can protect workers from harm by compliance with safety regulations and by providing the appropriate personal protective equipment. However, PPE cannot protect employees from psychological hazards. These are caused by stress and fear brought about by violence in the workplace, work overload, lack of support and more.</p> <p>Regardless of the type of occupational hazard that caused a workplace illness or injury, the victim may pursue financial relief through the New York workers' compensation insurance program. Benefits typically cover medical expenses and a percentage of lost income based on the victim's average weekly wage. An experienced attorney can provide the necessary support and guidance with the complicated legal and administrative procedures of the claims process.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>woman.thenest.com, "<a href="https://woman.thenest.com/four-categories-workplace-hazards-10062.html" target="_blank">Four Categories of Workplace Hazards</a>", Billie Nordmeyer, Accessed on Jan. 12, 2018</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-illness-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Workplace illness: Cold stress threatens outdoor workers]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/11/workplace-illness-cold-stress-threatens-outdoor-workers.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//701.2940410</id>
  <published>2017-11-15T11:48:04Z</published>
  <updated>2017-11-15T11:47:04Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[At the start of every winter, New York workers who have to work outdoors will likely feel anxious about the impact their work environments will have on their health. Cold stress is a workplace illness that can be fatal if...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceillness" label="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>At the start of every winter, New York workers who have to work outdoors will likely feel anxious about the impact their work environments will have on their health. Cold stress is a <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">workplace illness</a> that can be fatal if not treated promptly. This condition is caused by the environmental cold that affects workers who are exposed to air temperatures that are also cold. Cold stress risks are even higher when wind speeds increase because it increases the chill factor by making the air temperature feel colder against the skin.</p> <p>Workers who are frequently at risk of suffering cold stress include snow cleanup crews, recreational workers, construction crews, firefighters and police officers. Other occupations in which workers are typically exposed to extreme cold include transportation, baggage handlers, transit workers, oil and gas industry support workers and landscapers. However, many other workers spend long hours exposed to environmentally cold conditions.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>The most prevalent risk factors that could cause cold stress include improper clothing, dampness, wetness and exhaustion. Furthermore, a worker's existing health condition will also play a role in his or her risk level. Predisposing hypertension, diabetes and hypothyroidism will significantly increase a worker's chances of suffering cold stress. Hypothermia, trench foot and frostbite are all types of cold stress that can cause long-term health problems, and in severe cases, it can be fatal.</p> <p>New York employees who are suffering the consequences of exposure to environmental cold that led to cold stress will likely have to cope with mounting medical bills. Furthermore, they might even have to deal with lost wages if the workplace illness caused days off work. With the help of an experienced workers' compensation attorney, financial assistance may&nbsp;be pursued by filing workers' compensation benefits claims.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>osha.gov, "<a href="https://www.osha.gov/dts/weather/winter_weather/windchill.html" target="_blank">Cold Stress</a>", Accessed on Nov. 10, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-illness-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Workplace illness: New silica rules good news for workers]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/10/workplace-illness-new-silica-rules-good-news-for-workers.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//701.2884563</id>
  <published>2017-10-30T21:31:48Z</published>
  <updated>2017-10-30T21:30:48Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Employees in different industries in New York may be happy to learn that employers who tried to stop the new silica rule were unsuccessful. Industry leaders who dispute the need for regulations that are stricter asked a federal appeals court...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceillness" label="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Employees in different industries in New York may be happy to learn that employers who tried to stop the new silica rule were unsuccessful. Industry leaders who dispute the need for regulations that are stricter asked a federal appeals court to prevent implementation, but a panel of judges found that the Occupational Safety and Health Administration offered adequate evidence to motivate the enforcement of the new rules. The safety agency claims the new precautions will prevent those who are exposed to silica from contracting a potentially deadly <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">workplace illness</a> called silicosis.</p> <p>The new silica rules require employers to limit exposure to dust to much lower levels than previously. After postponing the effective date of implementation by 90 days, OSHA gave a further grace period of 30 days, during which time regional administrators and construction companies received counseling. Additional assistance is provided through guidance related to inspections and citations that will apply.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Some of those who are against the new rules claim the cost burden as justification for their arguments, while others have already taken several steps to comply. Furthermore, manufacturers of equipment have shown their support by designing additional dust-capturing products. Each industry has unique challenges about the implementation of the new rules, but OSHA will continue to provide assistance.</p> <p>Silicosis is a devastating illness that can severely hamper an affected worker's quality of life -- if they survive the deadly accumulation of crystalline silica particles in their lungs. Although the new rule might prevent future damage to the health of workers, those who are already silicosis sufferers may seek financial assistance through the New York workers' compensation insurance system. Proving a workplace illness that developed over time to be job-related could be challenging, and the best person to navigate such a claim might be an experienced workers' compensation attorney.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>constructiondive.com, "<a href="https://www.constructiondive.com/news/oshas-silica-rule-now-fully-enforced/507913/" target="_blank">OSHA's silica rule now fully enforced</a>", Mary Tyler March, Oct. 23, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-illness-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Toluene exposure can cause workplace illness]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/10/toluene-exposure-can-cause-workplace-illness.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//701.2829778</id>
  <published>2017-10-17T16:18:09Z</published>
  <updated>2017-10-17T16:17:09Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[New York employees in various occupations may be exposed to hazardous chemicals without even knowing about it. Employers are responsible for the health and safety of employees. Workers must be informed of dangers they will face while working, including hazards...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceillness" label="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>New York employees in various occupations may be exposed to hazardous chemicals without even knowing about it. Employers are responsible for the health and safety of employees. Workers must be informed of dangers they will face while working, including hazards that can cause <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">workplace illness</a>. However, safety training related to exposure to chemicals is often neglected, sometimes with tragic consequences.</p> <p>One such hazard is toluene, which is an ingredient in many paints, adhesives and metal cleaners. It often goes unnoticed because it is clear and colorless. At room temperature, it vaporizes upon exposure to air. The Occupational Safety and Health Administration notes that it can be recognized by its strong sweet smell once it has evaporated.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>The symptoms to look out for include being tired, numbness in feet and hands, trouble sleeping and slow reactions. In women, it can also adversely affect their reproductive systems and lead to loss of pregnancy. OSHA recommends substituting toluene-containing products with water-based products. Safety authorities say toluene-based products must only be used when no substitute is available, and then spray application must be avoided. Proper ventilation is essential whenever this hazardous chemical is applied.</p> <p>Workers in New York who are adversely affected by hazardous chemicals may find that the symptoms of a resulting workplace illness can develop over time. In such cases, it could be a challenge to prove that the condition is work-related. This is where the help of an experienced workers' compensation attorney can be invaluable. A lawyer can navigate the claims process and make sure the necessary medical proof is obtained to document&nbsp;a benefits claim for coverage of medical expenses and lost income.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>safetyandhealthmagazine.com, "<a href="http://www.safetyandhealthmagazine.com/articles/16047-avoid-toluene-exposure" target="_blank">Avoid toluene exposure</a>", Oct. 17, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-illness-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Carbon monoxide exposure can cause serious workplace illness]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/09/carbon-monoxide-exposure-can-cause-serious-workplace-illness.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//701.2772797</id>
  <published>2017-09-21T15:17:01Z</published>
  <updated>2017-09-21T15:16:01Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[New York workers in industrial facilities typically have to face multiple safety hazards in the line of duty. Compliance with safety regulations is one way of preventing an on-the-job injury or a workplace illness. Employers are responsible for the health...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceillness" label="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>New York workers in industrial facilities typically have to face multiple safety hazards in the line of duty. Compliance with safety regulations is one way of preventing an on-the-job injury or a <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">workplace illness</a>. Employers are responsible for the health and safety of employees. The National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health&nbsp;recently reported that noncompliance&nbsp;with rules related to carbon monoxide exposure could lead to fatalities.</p> <p>Authorities say gasoline-powered equipment and tools must never be operated indoors, not even in semi-enclosed spaces. Also, open windows and doors will not provide enough ventilation to prevent workers suffering carbon monoxide poisoning. When such equipment is operated outside, it is important to keep it away from air intakes by which CO can be carried into buildings.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Employees must receive proper training to teach them to identify any signs of CO exposure because the gas is colorless and odorless. Carbon monoxide exposure causes a headache, weakness, dizziness, nausea, visual disturbance and loss of consciousness. An exposed worker can be overwhelmed within minutes, so if any symptoms are noticed, action must not be delayed.</p> <p>Any New York employee who is exposed to carbon monoxide or suffers any other workplace illness can seek financial assistance with medical expenses and lost income. He or she can file a workers' compensation benefits claim with the company's insurance provider. Many employees choose to utilize the services of an experienced workers' compensation attorney to guide them through the claims process because proving that an illness is work-related could be quite a challenge.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>safetyandhealthmagazine.com, "<a href="http://www.safetyandhealthmagazine.com/articles/10118-dont-be-overcome-by-carbon-monoxide" target="_blank">Don't be overcome by carbon monoxide</a>", Sept. 16, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-illness-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Safety training can prevent workplace accidents involving teens]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/07/safety-training-can-prevent-workplace-accidents-involving-teens.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//701.2698146</id>
  <published>2017-07-31T20:18:28Z</published>
  <updated>2017-07-31T20:17:28Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[This is the time of the year when many young workers enter the New York workforce -- as permanent employees in their first jobs, or teens taking on temp jobs for the summer. Every year there are reports of teen...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceillness" label="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>This is the time of the year when many young workers enter the New York workforce -- as permanent employees in their first jobs, or teens taking on temp jobs for the summer. Every year there are reports of teen workers who die in tragic <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">workplace accidents</a> within days of starting employment. In most cases, these deaths result from a lack of safety training and/or inadequate supervision.</p> <p>Employers don't always realize that the combination of youth, inexperience and a sense of invincibility makes teenage workers vulnerable. To prevent such tragedies, safety authorities say that teen workers must be fully briefed on their duties and the potential safety risks before they are allocated any tasks. Furthermore, even if they will only be there for the summer, full safety training must be provided.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Employers must also allocate supervisors to monitor young workers -- preferably individuals who can communicate well with teenagers while they are also committed to safety in the work environment. Pairing young workers with experienced employees who are slightly older but responsible enough to provide valuable on-the-job training can teach them to comply with safety regulations from a young age. It is also important to teach them how to recognize hazards in the workplace.</p> <p>Authorities further remind New York employers that it is their responsibility to make sure teen workers do not operate machines and equipment that are unsafe and illegal for use under a certain age. Teenagers typically have inquiring minds, and encouraging them to ask questions and get involved in creating safer environments might help to prevent tragic workplace accidents. Young workers must also be trained in the procedures to follow if they were injured at work, to ensure timely filing of reports and claims with the workers' compensation insurance system.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>safetyandhealthmagazine.com, "<a href="http://www.safetyandhealthmagazine.com/articles/protect-your-teen-workers-2" target="_blank">Protect your teen workers</a>", Accessed on July 22, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-illness-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Claims for workplace illness compensation rejected]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/02/claims-for-workplace-illness-compensation-rejected.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//701.2481053</id>
  <published>2017-02-22T23:01:57Z</published>
  <updated>2017-02-22T23:00:57Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Former employees at a gun range in a neighboring state say they were exposed to a dangerous workplace environment. Lead is a known workplace illness hazard in facilities in which workers have to handle firearms and ammunition. The owner of...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceillness" label="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Former employees at a gun range in a neighboring state say they were exposed to a dangerous workplace environment. Lead is a known workplace illness hazard in facilities in which workers have to handle firearms and ammunition. The owner of the now-closed business made headlines when police caught him with a vehicle filled with weapons outside New York City last year. His arrest prompted the Occupational Safety and Health Administration to investigate the business.</p> <p>That investigation led to 35 safety violations, many of which involved excessively high lead levels in the facility. The workers claim to have suffered illnesses caused by exposure to lead. One former employee says he received some <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">workers' compensation benefits</a>, but it covered only some of his medical expenses. His doctor now refuses to continue treatment until unpaid bills are settled.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>The workers are unhappy because they claim they were never informed about the hazards they faced every day, nor did they know the proper procedures for safe handling of the spent shells. The workers demand an investigation and payment of their claims for medical expenses. They claim their ongoing health problems include chronic headaches and joint pain, and one former employee says the lead exposure caused his teeth to break.</p> <p>Sometimes it is difficult to prove that an illness is job-related.&nbsp; New York employees whose workers' compensation claims for workplace illness or injuries are denied or rejected need not give up. A seasoned workers' comp attorney can provide the necessary guidance in filing an appeal. A skilled lawyer can fight for the right of the employee and work to obtain fair compensation to cover medical costs and lost wages.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>wfmz.com, "<a href="http://www.wfmz.com/news/lehigh-valley/former-cramsey-employees-describe-poisonous-work-environment/332502629" target="_blank">Former Cramsey employees describe poisonous work environment</a>", Emma Wright, Feb. 13, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-illness-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Welding industry hazards can cause serious workplace illness]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/02/welding-industry-hazards-can-cause-serious-workplace-illness.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//701.2467439</id>
  <published>2017-02-14T13:47:28Z</published>
  <updated>2017-02-14T13:46:28Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Employees in New York in occupations that involve welding, brazing and cutting are part of over 500,000 workers in the tri-state region surrounding New York City who face serious health risks if they work without proper safety gear. The danger...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceillness" label="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Employees in New York in occupations that involve welding, brazing and cutting are part of over 500,000 workers in the tri-state region surrounding New York City who face serious health risks if they work without proper safety gear. The danger posed by this industry comes in the form of gases and fumes that could be hazardous. Welding activities produce visible smoke -- in the welder's breathing space -- containing harmful gas byproducts and metal fumes that can cause <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">workplace illness</a>.</p> <p>The metals that can bring about dangerous fumes when welded include aluminum, copper, lead, iron, manganese, tin, silver, nickel and many others. The gases produced that may cause respiratory illnesses include argon, carbon monoxide, carbon dioxide, helium, nitric oxide, nitrogen and more. Only unprotected workers are at risk of inhaling theses hazardous gases and fumes, and illness is preventable if all employers would provide adequate respirators that fit properly.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Employers who fail to provide the required respiratory protection will expose employees to various occupational illnesses that may include respiratory irritation that could lead to asphyxiation, stomach ulcers, various cancer types and more. The Occupational Safety and Health Administration has strict regulations in place to protect employees from the hazards of welding fumes and gases. However, despite facing citations and penalties, some business owners continue to disregard employee health and safety.</p> <p>New York workers who are suffering the consequences of a workplace illness may need long-term medical care and may have to deal with the loss of income. Fortunately, the state's workers' compensation insurance system provides benefits to cover the costs of medical treatment and wage losses. Some employees choose to seek the support and guidance of an experienced workers' compensation attorney to pursue maximum compensation for them.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>environmental-expert.com, "<a href="https://www.environmental-expert.com/news/new-york-firm-protects-workers-from-exposure-hazards-to-welding-fumes-691492" target="_blank">New York Firm Protects Workers from Exposure Hazards to Welding Fumes</a>", Feb. 6, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-illness-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Workplace Illness: New York nonprofit exposed workers to asbestos]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2016/11/workplace-illness-new-york-nonprofit-exposed-workers-to-asbestos.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2016:/blog//701.2324629</id>
  <published>2016-11-14T17:31:53Z</published>
  <updated>2016-11-14T17:30:53Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Asbestos abatement is known to pose severe health hazards to workers in New York and elsewhere. Exposure to asbestos can cause an employee to suffer a workplace illness that can have grave consequences. A nonprofit organization in Auburn recently paid...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceillness" label="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Asbestos abatement is known to pose severe health hazards to workers in New York and elsewhere. Exposure to asbestos can cause an employee to suffer a <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">workplace illness</a> that can have grave consequences. A nonprofit organization in Auburn recently paid a stiff penalty after the Occupational Safety and Health Administration investigated its compliance with safety regulations in areas where&nbsp;asbestos was present.</p> <p>A spokesperson for the organization says they identified the presence of asbestos in floor tiles during an office renovation project in June. However, OSHA says the organization failed to arrange an assessment of asbestos exposure by a competent person. Federal inspectors determined that the company exposed four employees to asbestos during the project.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>The chief executive officer of the organization says they conducted air quality tests that did not indicate any threat of asbestos particles in the air. They believed that the asbestos dust never became airborne and, for that reason, it posed no danger to workers. He also claims that none of the workers complained of feeling sick while they were removing the tiles.</p> <p>However, the workplace illness that is typically associated with asbestos exposure is not necessarily immediately evident, and it can develop into permanent lung damage. Workers in New York who experience unusual shortness of breath and coughing may benefit from proper medical evaluations to determine whether they might be suffering the consequences of asbestos exposure. Long-term care can be costly, and victims of this illness may pursue financial relief by filing benefits claims with the workers' compensation insurance program for coverage of medical expenses and lost income.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>auburnpub.com, "<a href="http://auburnpub.com/news/local/osha-cites-and-fines-cayuga-centers-for-improper-asbestos-removal/article_9c47d17b-3f38-5b93-ba8b-4c811f0a41ee.html" target="_blank">OSHA cites and fines Cayuga Centers for improper asbestos removal</a>", Gwendolyn Craig, Nov. 11, 2016</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-illness-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Workplace illness prevalent for female day laborers in New York]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2016/09/workplace-illness-prevalent-for-female-day-laborers-in-new-york.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2016:/blog//701.2240974</id>
  <published>2016-09-26T13:49:46Z</published>
  <updated>2016-09-26T13:48:46Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[An advocacy group in Brooklyn published the results of a new study that examined the difficulties faced by female day laborers in New York. The study found that 75 percent of the women who work as day laborers are the...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceillness" label="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>An advocacy group in Brooklyn published the results of a new study that examined the difficulties faced by female day laborers in New York. The study found that 75 percent of the women who work as day laborers are the primary breadwinners for their dependents. Along with looking into their levels of remuneration and other wage and hour law issues, vulnerability related to <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">workplace illness</a> and injuries was also studied.</p> <p>An alarming fact that came to light is that 65 percent of these women do not have access to health care. Furthermore, illnesses related to their work were reported by 71 percent of the women. A large number of the said conditions resulted from exposure to dangerous chemical cleaning materials. Chronic pain was also reported by women who were forced to clean floors on their hands and knees.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Although many of the women who took part in the study are domestic cleaners, a large percentage are employed as industrial office cleaners or even in the construction industry. The cleaning duties on construction sites are often carried out by women. The advocacy group underscored the fact that these individuals deserve the same concern for their health and safety as all other workers.</p> <p>Any female worker who suffers a workplace illness or injury has the same right to medical care and workers' compensation benefits as her male counterparts. Benefits claims may be filed with the New York workers' compensation insurance system to relieve the financial burden of medical expenses. Furthermore, lost wages may also be compensated, and such benefits will be based upon a percentage of the worker's average weekly wage.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>brooklyneagle.com, "<a href="http://www.brooklyneagle.com/articles/2016/8/19/new-study-looks-plight-women-day-laborers" target="_blank">New study looks at plight of women day laborers</a>", Paula Katinas, Accessed on Sept. 23, 2016</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-illness-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Older workers: Value and issues]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2016/08/older-workers-value-and-issues.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2016:/blog//701.2207255</id>
  <published>2016-08-30T18:57:34Z</published>
  <updated>2017-06-22T05:47:26Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[It was the nation's biggest generation: the Baby Boom. The post-World War II generation is graying, with many of its members approaching retirement age. Many Boomers enjoy work or have financial reasons to keep their careers going, however. They aren't...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceillness" label="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>It was the nation's biggest generation: the Baby Boom. The post-World War II generation is graying, with many of its members approaching retirement age.</p> <p>Many Boomers enjoy work or have financial reasons to keep their careers going, however. They aren't ready to retire, and because many employers want the experience and knowledge older workers possess, there is demand for Boomers in the job market.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Because the Baby Boom generation is older, its members come to work with skills, but also a need for a bit of understanding from employers. A study by Safety National Casualty Corporation found that the average <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">workers' compensation claim</a> for workers older than 45 is 73 percent higher than for younger workers.</p> <p>With a graying working population, it's worth diving into the numbers. Just over two-thirds of all 55- to 64-year-olds will be in the work force in 2022. For people between 65 and 74, a little more than a third will be working.</p> <p>These experienced, knowledgeable workers do take longer to heal from workplace injuries and illnesses, however. According to a recent media report, aging skin can take up to 4 times longer to heal.</p> <p>Plus, older workers are more likely to have chronic health issues that might interfere with their ability to work at times or that can complicate or delay recovery from injury or illness.</p> <p>Regardless, Boomers are valuable employees and as such are likely to continue to be prized by employers. When an injured or ill employee is denied deserved workers' compensation benefits, they can appeal with the help of an experienced Newburgh workers' comp attorney.</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-illness-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[New York workers suffer mercury exposure]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2016/08/new-york-workers-suffer-mercury-exposure.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2016:/blog//701.2186235</id>
  <published>2016-08-16T15:36:15Z</published>
  <updated>2016-08-16T15:35:15Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Occupational Safety and Health Administration inspectors often drop in on businesses unannounced to look for workplace safety hazards. Sometimes, though, OSHA inspections are carried out because an employee has filed a complaint about work conditions. Employees of a hazardous materials...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceillness" label="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Occupational Safety and Health Administration inspectors often drop in on businesses unannounced to look for workplace safety hazards. Sometimes, though, OSHA inspections are carried out because an employee has filed a complaint about work conditions.</p> <p>Employees of a hazardous materials remediation contractor located less than two hours due north of Newburgh filed a complaint with OSHA. The workers said they were being exposed to mercury at a Superfund site in Schenectady.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>As you likely know, exposure to high levels of mercury can lead to damage to a person's brain, heart, lungs, kidneys and immune system. <a href="http://www.medicinenet.com/mercury_poisoning/article.htm" target="_blank" >Medicine.net says</a> symptoms of mercury poisoning include a loss of coordination, and impairment of vision, speech, walking and hearing, as well as muscle weakness.</p> <p>The workers cleaning up the Superfund site were removing both liquid mercury and soil and wood contaminated with mercury.</p> <p>OSHA found that several workers had been exposed to excessive levels of mercury through inhalation or absorption through their skin. Inspectors also found that workers had symptoms consistent with mercury exposure, including tremors, neurological impairments, skin damage and fatigue, among others.</p> <p>OSHA said in <a href="https://www.osha.gov/pls/oshaweb/owadisp.show_document?p_table=NEWS_RELEASES&p_id=32946" target="_blank" >a statement</a> that the employer, Environmental Remediation Services Inc., failed to provide essential items such as protective equipment and ventilation. The firm also failed to monitor possible exposure to the concentrated toxin. The federal agency issued 13 citations for serious and willful violations of safety standards and proposed a fine of $142,000.</p> <p>Workers who are exposed to toxic substances on the job, or who suffer injuries in the workplace, are typically due workers' compensation benefits. Those employees denied deserved benefits can speak with <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workers-Compensation/Am-I-Eligible-for-Workers-Compensation.shtml" >a workers' comp attorney</a> about an appeal.</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-illness-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Know Your Workplace Safety Rights]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2016/06/know-your-workplace-safety-rights.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2016:/blog//701.2099282</id>
  <published>2016-06-13T18:52:25Z</published>
  <updated>2016-06-13T18:51:25Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[The U.S. Constitution and its Bill of Rights are revered as powerful, articulate descriptions of the rights we all possess. The United States Department of Labor wants you to know that your rights don't stop at freedom of speech or...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceillness" label="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>The U.S. Constitution and its Bill of Rights are revered as powerful, articulate descriptions of the rights we all possess. The United States Department of Labor wants you to know that your rights don't stop at freedom of speech or freedom of the press, however.</p> <p>You have rights in the workplace, too. The Labor Department says in clear terms that you have the right, under federal law, to <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workers-Compensation/Am-I-Eligible-for-Workers-Compensation.shtml" >a safe workplace</a>. "Your employer must provide a workplace free of known health and safety hazards," the department says.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>And if you have concerns about safety hazards where you work, you also have the right to express those concerns without fear of retaliation.</p> <p>Your other workplace rights include:</p> <ul> <li>Training in a language you understand</li> <li>You must be provided required safety gear (gloves, helmet, harness, etc.)</li> <li>Protection from toxic chemicals</li> <li>Machines that are safe to operate</li> <li>Be able to report a job-related injury or illness</li> <li>Be allowed to see records of job-related injuries and illnesses</li> </ul> <p>Just as you have a right to a safe workplace, your <a href="https://www.osha.gov/workers/index.html" target="_blank" >employer has a responsibility</a> to provide a safe place to work.</p> <p>OSHA also encourages businesses to create injury and illness prevention plans. The agency said not only do such plans benefits workers, but they benefit the employers as well.<br /><br />When a work-related illness or injury occurs, you also have the right to New York workers' compensation. Unfortunately, there are employers and insurers who will try to deny you earned and deserved workers' comp. In those situations, you can speak to a Newburgh attorney experienced in workers' compensation appeals.</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-illness-->
</entry>

</feed>