<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/includes/blog-feed/atom.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Workplace Injuries Archives | Newburgh New York Workers' Compensation Law Blog]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/workplace-injuries-1/" />
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/workplace-injuries-1/atom.xml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2013-03-21:/blog/81520</id>
  <updated>2018-06-28T14:25:21Z</updated>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[This is the Workplace Injuries archive for Newburgh New York Workers' Compensation Law Blog.]]></subtitle>
  <generator uri="http://www.sixapart.com/movabletype/">Movable Type Enterprise</generator>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Workers investigating gas leak suffer burns in workplace accident]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/06/workers-investigating-gas-leak-suffer-burns-in-workplace-accident.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3324157</id>
  <published>2018-06-28T14:26:21Z</published>
  <updated>2018-06-28T14:25:21Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Keeping New York State running effectively and efficiently requires workers performing maintenance, repairs and construction. While these workers are generally competent and do their jobs safely, there remains an inherent danger in any task they are required to do....]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceinjuries" label="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Keeping New York State running effectively and efficiently requires workers performing maintenance, repairs and construction. While these workers are generally competent and do their jobs safely, there remains an inherent danger in any task they are required to do. This is especially true when working with electrical and explosive materials. Those who are in an accident in these circumstances can face burns and other types of on-the-job injury. With the medical expenses and long-term damage that can result, workers' compensation and a legal filing are often the only available ways to cover what they lost.</p> <p>An explosion led to <a href="https://www.nbcnewyork.com/news/local/Manhole-Explode-Fire-Brooklyn-NYC-Injuries-NYPD-FDNY-Investigation-486232661.html" target="_blank">three utility workers being burned</a>. A gas leak is believed to have been the cause. The incident occurred in the early morning hours at around 1 a.m. The workers are employed by National Grid. After the explosion, the men were taken to the hospital for treatment. They were said to have minor burns. A spokesperson for the company stated that the workers were there to investigate a potential gas leak. As they dug, there was a spark and the subsequent explosion. Work in the area is ongoing to determine the source of the gas leak.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Burns can have a major impact on a worker's life. These can cause scars, damage to nerves, the body part being limited or outright useless and even result in infections and death. Even minor burns can have a negative effect on a person's life and ability to work. There will be medical costs, hospitalization and the potential issues getting back to work. Workers' compensation can help to cover the worker for the treatment and for the time missed on the job. If there are costs that are not paid, a legal filing can be pursued.</p> <p>For these workers, despite the reports that the burns were minor, they could still deal with long-term problems due to this accident. Regardless, for the medical expenses, lost wages and other problems that can and will come up due to this explosion, they should make certain they get the maximum benefits with help from a legal professional experienced in helping <a href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/Burns-and-Electrocution.shtml">injured workers</a>.</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-injuries-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Slip-and-fall workplace accidents cause 95M lost workdays a year]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/04/slip-and-fall-workplace-accidents-cause-95m-lost-workdays-a-year.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3244604</id>
  <published>2018-04-11T11:03:21Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:52Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Workers in all industries in New York are exposed to the risks of slip-and-fall incidents, and many employers fail to recognize the fact that a bad landing after such a fall can cause catastrophic injuries, such as traumatic brain injuries...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceinjuries" label="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Workers in all industries in New York are exposed to the risks of slip-and-fall incidents, and many employers fail to recognize the fact that a bad landing after such a fall can cause catastrophic injuries, such as traumatic brain injuries and even death. Every business owner must have a fall prevention program in place, and employees must receive safety training to ensure they understand that preventing or cleaning up spillages or debris that can cause falls is the responsibility of all. Furthermore, workers must learn what to do regarding&nbsp;such <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">workplace accidents</a>.</p> <p>Slips and trips that lead to falls are said to be the primary causes of occupational injuries. Statistics reported by the U.S. Department of Labor, the Bureau of Labor Statistics and the National Safety Council indicate that over 95 million lost workdays follow slip-and-fall accidents in the workplace every year. They say the number of daily fall accidents nationwide is as many as 25,000, costing an estimated $70 billion in workers' compensation and medical expenses annually.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>These numbers are alarming if one considers that such accidents are entirely preventable. A safety plan that includes maintenance and repair to ensure even walking surfaces and no loose or frayed carpeting, cleanup of spills, leaks and any standing water, and avoiding the use of slippery polishes on floors will go a long way in keeping workers on their feet. Further obstacles like clutter, debris, power cords and other random objects on the floor can cause falls with devastating consequences.</p> <p>Although the ideal work environment will be free of any of these hazards, the reality is that most New York workers will continue to face dangerous on-the-job circumstances. Fortunately, victims of workplace accidents need not suffer the financial consequences of their injuries without help. The workers' compensation insurance program provides benefits to cover medical expenses and lost wages, and resources are available to help with the navigation of benefits claims.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>4-m.com, "<a href="http://www.4-m.com/blog/article/5-ways-to-prevent-slips-trips-and-falls-in-the-workplace" target="_blank">5 Ways to Prevent Slips, Trips and Falls in the Workplace</a>", April 3, 2018</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-injuries-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Injured workers at dairy expose employer's safety violations]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/04/injured-workers-at-dairy-expose-employers-safety-violations.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3244603</id>
  <published>2018-04-03T19:16:45Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:52Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[A spokesperson for an area office of the Occupational Safety and Health Administration says all workplace injuries can be prevented. However, as long as employers fail to provide adequate training and appropriate personal protective equipment, there will be reports of...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceinjuries" label="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>A spokesperson for an area office of the Occupational Safety and Health Administration says all workplace injuries can be prevented. However, as long as employers fail to provide adequate training and appropriate personal protective equipment, there will be reports of <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">injured workers</a>. His remark came after the agency proposed a penalty of more than $140,000 for safety violations at a New York dairy.</p> <p>Reportedly, OSHA inspected the dairy in Jan. 2017 when compliance inspectors determined that employees worked without any personal protective equipment, and they also lacked the training to teach them about the hazards of their jobs. This investigation followed reports of several workers suffering serious burn wounds. These were caused by exposure to milk at temperatures exceeding 150 degrees Fahrenheit.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>The safety agency returned to the dairy in November last year to check whether the necessary safety precautions have been put in place as ordered. However, despite the fact that this employer had been cited for similar violations on three different occasions over the previous 14 months, the business owner continued to disregard employee safety. Furthermore, it was found that employee injuries were also not recorded and reported to OSHA in the prescribed manner.</p> <p>The fact that an employer can have no regard for the safety of those who bring in the money is unacceptable. Burn wounds can cause permanent scars and leave a victim with severe health problems. Fortunately, injured workers are entitled to claim benefits from the New York workers' compensation insurance program. An experienced workers' compensation attorney can assist with the claims process to help pursue maximum benefits.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>ehstoday.com, "<a href="http://www.ehstoday.com/ppe/dairy-manufacturer-fined-after-workers-suffer-severe-burns" target="_blank">Dairy Manufacturer Fined After Workers Suffer Severe Burns</a>", March 21, 2018</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-injuries-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Workplace accidents: Window frame pins construction worker]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/03/workplace-accidents-window-frame-pins-construction-worker.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3244598</id>
  <published>2018-03-06T15:54:46Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:51Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Constructions sites in New York and elsewhere will always pose multiple safety hazards. Workplace accidents in this industry often occur when heavy objects strike workers. While this is a known hazard, employers may fail to provide adequate safety training to...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceinjuries" label="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Constructions sites in New York and elsewhere will always pose multiple safety hazards. Workplace accidents in this industry often occur when heavy objects strike workers. While this is a known hazard, employers may fail to provide adequate safety training to teach employees how to avoid such injuries.</p> <p>A construction site in a neighboring state was issued a stop-work order after a 45-year-old worker was severely injured shortly after 7:30 a.m. on a recent Monday. Paramedics and firefighters responded to a scene at a building that is being renovated. Reportedly, the worker was pinned by a window frame that fell on him.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Rescue workers say a shifting load likely caused the five-by-eight foot fourth-floor window frame to fall. The injured worker suffered severe injuries to his back and leg, and he was rushed to a medical facility. The local building department stopped all work at the site pending an inspection by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration.</p> <p>When New York construction workers are injured in workplace accidents, the medical bills and sudden loss of income may be overwhelming. Fortunately, financial assistance can be obtained through the workers' compensation insurance system of the state. Benefits claims can be filed for coverage of medical expenses such as doctor and hospital fees along with therapy sessions and even transportation to and from doctors. The benefits will also include a portion of lost wages for <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">injured workers</a> who are unable to report for work for an extended period. The help of an experienced workers' compensation attorney can simplify the complicated claims process.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>sentinelandenterprise.com, "<a href="http://www.sentinelandenterprise.com/breakingnews/ci_31712552/man-injured-construction-accident-at-fitchburgs-former-sanitoy" target="_blank">Man injured in construction accident at Fitchburg's former Sanitoy Mill</a>", Elizabeth Dobbins, March 6, 2018</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-injuries-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Injured workers: EMS industry has high rate of workplace injuries]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/02/injured-workers-ems-industry-has-high-rate-of-workplace-injuries.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3244596</id>
  <published>2018-02-20T19:55:13Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:51Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[According to the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, emergency medical workers lose three times more work days than other employees in the general workforce. After a four-year study, NIOSH revealed that over 22,000 injured workers in this industry...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceinjuries" label="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>According to the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, emergency medical workers lose three times more work days than other employees in the general workforce. After a four-year study, NIOSH revealed that over 22,000 <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">injured workers</a> in this industry receive emergency room treatment each year nationwide, including in New York. The data also showed that those who are most often injured are full-time EMS workers whose experience does not exceed 10 years.</p> <p>Furthermore, most injuries occur during 911 responses and are often suffered during transport and patient care. Repetitive body motions, awkward postures and excessive physical effort cause musculoskeletal injuries, with necks and backs mostly affected. Other causes for injuries include harmful substance exposure, slips, trips and falls, auto accidents and assaults.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Safety authorities recommend sufficient rest, exercise and healthy eating along with access to mental health services for EMS workers. Employers must provide the necessary personal protective equipment to prevent exposure to blood-borne pathogens. Wearing appropriate shoes could avert slip or trip-and-fall accidents, and training in emergency vehicle operation must be provided.</p> <p>EMS workers in New York may suffer long-term health consequences. However, financial assistance is available through the workers' compensation insurance program. Navigating the complicated administrative and legal proceedings of the claims process can be overwhelming for injured workers. However, the support and guidance of an experienced workers' compensation attorney are available. Workers are typically entitled to coverage of medical expenses along with lost wages for those whose hospitalization or recuperation period prevented them from returning to work for some time.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>safetyandhealthmagazine.com, "<a href="http://www.safetyandhealthmagazine.com/articles/16133-ems-workers-face-higher-occupational-injury-rates-niosh-says" target="_blank">EMS workers face higher occupational injury rates, NIOSH says</a>", Accessed on Feb. 16, 2018</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-injuries-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[New York workplace accidents prevalent during snow removal]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/01/new-york-workplace-accidents-prevalent-during-snow-removal.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3244589</id>
  <published>2018-01-03T14:23:41Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:51Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[New York experienced an excessively cold December, and with large amounts of snow comes the dangers associated with snow removal. The Occupational Safety and Health Administration reminded employers and workers of the necessary precautions to prevent workplace accidents. This is...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceinjuries" label="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>New York experienced an excessively cold December, and with large amounts of snow comes the dangers associated with snow removal. The Occupational Safety and Health Administration reminded employers and workers of the necessary precautions to prevent <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">workplace accidents</a>. This is a task that can cause serious injuries or worse without the proper safeguards. Violations of safety regulations may lead to entrapment under snow that may cause suffocation, and damaged power lines could cause electrocution.</p> <p>Elevated surfaces such as rooftops are particularly perilous because the additional weight of the snow, and the workers' weights may be too much for the structure to bear. For this reason, the snow load must be evaluated before workers access the roof. Appropriate snow removal techniques must be followed, such as the uniform removal across the roof area to avoid piles of snow that may cause too much weight in small areas.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>When workers use drag lines or snow rakes to clear roofs from ground level, it is essential to avoid removing large amounts of snow at a time. Workers on the ground can be buried under snow if they do not remove the snow in small amounts. Each worker must be equipped with personal protective equipment such as head and eye protection along with gloves. OSHA says further hazards are posed by mechanical equipment such as snowblowers, and other typical injuries include hypothermia, frostbite, overexertion and musculoskeletal injuries.</p> <p>Employees who have suffered injuries in workplace accidents during snow removal or other activities will be well advised to get the necessary medical care and report the injury to their employers as soon as possible. This can set the wheels in motion for a benefits claim with the New York workers' compensation insurance program. Experienced legal counsel is available to assist with the navigation of the claims process for coverage of medical expenses and lost wages.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>triblive.com, "<a href="http://triblive.com/local/regional/13117389-74/osha-offers-tips-to-guard-against-snow-removal-hazards" target="_blank">OSHA offers tips to guard against snow-removal hazards</a>", Jeff Himler, Dec. 27, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-injuries-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Safety violations at supermarkets can cause workplace accidents]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/11/safety-violations-at-supermarkets-can-cause-workplace-accidents.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244583</id>
  <published>2017-11-21T14:21:43Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:50Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Employers in New York and other states must prioritize employee safety at all times. The Occupational Safety and Health Administration recently reported its concern over the ongoing noncompliance with safety regulations that inspectors found at three Fair Trades Supermarkets in...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceinjuries" label="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Employers in New York and other states must prioritize employee safety at all times. The Occupational Safety and Health Administration recently reported its concern over the ongoing noncompliance with safety regulations that inspectors found at three Fair Trades Supermarkets in New York. An OSHA area director said the employees at these stores were exposed to several unaddressed safety hazards that could result in <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">workplace accidents</a>.</p> <p>During safety inspections at these locations, compliance officers found that workers were at risk of suffering eye injuries because they were not provided with safety information about the hazardous chemicals with which they work. Furthermore, there were no eyewash stations for incidents in which they were exposed to corrosive substances. Exit routes were not accessible, and employees were also exposed to several blades that were not protected by safety guards.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>The OSHA official said this is not the first time for this company to be cited for violations of safety regulations. In 2013, OSHA apparently issued citations for violations of a similar nature. For that reason, 10 of the citations issued this time were for repeat violations, and one was for a serious violation.</p> <p>New York workers who have suffered injuries in workplace accidents may be overwhelmed by mounting medical bills. Depending on the severity of their injuries, they may be temporarily disabled and suffer lost wages. However, they might find comfort in knowing that the workers' compensation insurance system is there to provide financial assistance. The claims procedures could be challenging, but an experienced workers' compensation attorney can help with the complicated administrative and legal steps required to get the benefits to which they are entitled.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>osha.gov, "<a href="https://www.osha.gov/news/newsreleases/region2/11092017" target="_blank">U.S. Department of Labor Again Cites Three Queens Supermarkets For Safety Violations</a>", Nov. 9, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-injuries-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Injured workers are entitled to workers' compensation benefits]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/09/injured-workers-are-entitled-to-workers-compensation-benefits.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244573</id>
  <published>2017-09-11T11:28:07Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:49Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[A spokesperson for the Transport Workers Union reported some of the details of a recent New York accident that involved an MTA bus. These are the types of incidents that could not only cause serious harm to passengers and property,...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceinjuries" label="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>A spokesperson for the Transport Workers Union reported some of the details of a recent New York accident that involved an MTA bus. These are the types of incidents that could not only cause serious harm to passengers and property, but they can also lead to critically <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">injured workers</a>. Fortunately, this incident that occurred in the early morning hours of a recent Tuesday involved no passengers.</p> <p>Reportedly, an MTA bus driver with 12 years of experience was hospitalized in a critical condition. The incident apparently happened when the driver parked the bus in Queens because he needed a bathroom break. However, after exiting, he noticed the bus starting to roll backward toward the gates of a nearby cemetery. He could not stop the bus by reaching through the driver's window and ran around to try entering the cab through the passenger side door.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>He failed in his attempt to get in and became crushed between a pole and the door of the bus. Another bus driver saw the unfolding catastrophe and managed to get into the bus to pull the brake to secure the bus. The injured driver was unconscious when he was admitted to the hospital, but his condition was reported as stable.</p> <p>A thorough investigation will likely reveal the reason for the bus rolling backward. However, regardless of who was at fault in a workplace accident, injured workers are entitled to pursue financial assistance with medical expenses and lost income. Benefits can be claimed from the New York workers' compensation insurance program, and the support and guidance of an experienced attorney are available.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>CBS New York, "<a href="http://newyork.cbslocal.com/2017/08/29/mta-bus-rolls-into-queens-cemetery/" target="_blank">Bus Driver Critical After Bus Rolls Into Cemetery Gates</a>", Aug. 29, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-injuries-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[What to do when workplace accidents are caused by third parties]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/08/what-to-do-when-workplace-accidents-are-caused-by-third-parties.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244570</id>
  <published>2017-08-23T15:18:28Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:49Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[When workers are injured on the job, parties other than the employer or a co-worker are sometimes responsible for the accident. When this happens in New York, the injured workers may be entitled to pursue personal injury lawsuits apart from...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceinjuries" label="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>When workers are injured on the job, parties other than the employer or a co-worker are sometimes responsible for the accident. When this happens in New York, the injured workers may be entitled to pursue personal injury lawsuits apart from their workers' compensation benefits claims. This could allow victims of <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">workplace accidents</a> to recover more than just medical expenses and lost income.</p> <p>An employee in a neighboring state recently filed a personal injury lawsuit against an independent contractor and two of his employees.&nbsp;He claims their negligence caused him to suffer multiple injuries. According to the complaint, the plaintiff was standing near a parking lot at his place of work when the contractor and his two employees caused a rubberized jet vac line that was tautly stretched to snap and strike his body and head.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>The plaintiff claims the actions of the defendants that led to the breakage in the jet line were negligent. Furthermore, the plaintiff alleges vicarious liability by the contractor who allegedly subjected one of the two employees to a pre-employment drug test but hired the man before obtaining the test results -- which turned out to be positive. The plaintiff alleges that he suffered serious injuries that led to spinal surgery, along with many other consequences related to brain, eye and nerve damage.</p> <p>The plaintiff's wife also filed a claim for loss of consortium. New York victims of workplace accidents that were caused by third parties may have many questions about how to go about filing workers' compensation claims and civil claims at the same time. The best way to approach this may be with the support and guidance of an experienced workers' compensation attorney who can explain the process and assist with the navigation of both proceedings.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>pennrecord.com, "<a href="http://pennrecord.com/stories/511180900-sewage-plant-chief-allegedly-suffers-spinal-injuries-in-workplace-accident-sues-contractor-and-two-of-its-employees" target="_blank">Sewage plant chief allegedly suffers spinal injuries in workplace accident, sues contractor and two of its employees</a>", Nicholas Malfitano, Aug. 15, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-injuries-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Electric shock will be covered by workers' compensation benefits]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/08/electric-shock-will-be-covered-by-workers-compensation-benefits.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244567</id>
  <published>2017-08-02T11:59:59Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:48Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[A power failure shortly before noon on a recent Wednesday occurred after residents of a New York town in Erie County heard a loud bang. They rushed outside to hear utility workers of National Grid screaming for someone to call...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceinjuries" label="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>A power failure shortly before noon on a recent Wednesday occurred after residents of a New York town in Erie County heard a loud bang. They rushed outside to hear utility workers of National Grid screaming for someone to call 911 for help. It was then determined that one employee had suffered an electric shock. Such injuries likely lead to <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">workers' compensation benefits</a> claims.</p> <p>According to a report by police, a lineman was working on the installation of a power pole when he suffered&nbsp;an electric shock. Paramedics transported him to a trauma center for treatment of his injuries. It is unknown what caused the worker to be shocked, and the company said a full investigation would be launched.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>The area remained without power for approximately five hours. Inspectors of the Occupational Safety and Health Administration arrived at the scene that afternoon to investigate the incident, while the local police department will conduct an independent investigation. OSHA said the victim would be questioned upon his release from the hospital.</p> <p>Any victims of work-related injuries in New York are entitled to claim workers' compensation benefits. After prompt reporting of a workplace accident, claim forms can be completed. There are time limits attached to the filing of benefits claims, and victims may find it helpful to secure the services of an experienced workers' compensation attorney who can proceed with the process while the victim is recuperating. Benefits typically cover medical expenses along with a portion of wage replacement for those whose injuries caused temporary disabilities.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>wivb.com, "<a href="http://wivb.com/2017/07/26/national-grid-worker-shocked-in-cheektowaga/" target="_blank">National Grid worker shocked in Cheektowaga</a>", Evan Anstey, July 26, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-injuries-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Some workplace accidents cause irreversible harm to exposed eyes]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/07/some-workplace-accidents-cause-irreversible-harm-to-exposed-eyes.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244565</id>
  <published>2017-07-18T15:14:44Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:48Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[A worker may say his injury happened in the blink of an eye. However, if properly fitted safety glasses protected those eyes, they could have blinked all day without being harmed. The U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics says the eyes...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceinjuries" label="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>A worker may say his injury happened in the blink of an eye. However, if properly fitted safety glasses protected those eyes, they could have blinked all day without being harmed. The U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics says the eyes of approximately 2,000 workers are damaged in <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">workplace accidents</a> every day, adding up to over 700,000 per year. Many of those occur in New York.</p> <p>The alarming fact is these type of eye injuries are so easy to prevent -- it takes only a pair of safety glasses. Unfortunately, many employers fail to enforce the use of them and allow employees to choose when to wear eye protection. However, even if workers are forced to wear safety glasses, the safety gear will not prevent eye injuries if they do not fit properly -- considering approximately 70 percent of reported eye injuries were caused by particles no bigger than a pin's head.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Common hazards that threaten eye safety include metal slivers, wood chips, dust particles and sand. These are carried by the wind, blown by equipment or falling from above the worker. In many cases, eyes are damaged by splashing fluids such as chemicals or grease, UV radiation, steam or objects dislodged from machinery.</p> <p>A survey by the BLS revealed that six out of every 10 victims of eye injuries suffered on the job failed to wear eye protection. Victims of workplace accidents are entitled to pursue financial recovery for medical expenses and lost wages -- sadly, in many of these cases, eyesight will not be recoverable. Victims can file benefits claims with the New York worker' compensation insurance program.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>chronicle.kennametal.com, "<a href="http://chronicle.kennametal.com/i-can-see-clearly-now-the-speck-is-gone-preventing-workplace-eye-injuries/" target="_blank">I Can See Clearly Now, the Speck Is Gone: Preventing Workplace Eye Injuries</a>", Accessed on July 15, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-injuries-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Workplace accidents: Eye protection vital PPE for landscapers]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/07/workplace-accidents-eye-protection-vital-ppe-for-landscapers.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244564</id>
  <published>2017-07-11T16:40:37Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:48Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Authorities say several of the safety hazards in the landscaping industry can cause severe damage to workers' eyes. Employers in this field can prevent many workplace accidents by providing employees with eye protection and by making sure that they wear...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceinjuries" label="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Authorities say several of the safety hazards in the landscaping industry can cause severe damage to workers' eyes. Employers in this field can prevent many workplace accidents by providing employees with eye protection and by making sure that they wear it. Along with the risk of getting dangerous chemicals in their eyes, there are the hazards posed by flying objects -- from stones to pieces of wood, twigs or bark.</p> <p>Data provided by the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics show that work-related eye injuries nationwide, including in New York, exceed 20,000 every year -- with many of them leading to several days off work. However, some such injuries can have devastating consequences. A 33-year-old landscaper explained how he almost lost sight in his right eye when he failed to wear eye protection while edging the sidewalk.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>A one-inch sized rock got kicked up and struck him in the eye, and his first thought was that he had lost his eye. Fortunately, this was not the case, but his ophthalmologist said the impact of the rock had caused compression of his eye and this triggered blood vessels to rupture in his iris. This caused hyphema, which could cause the loss of vision, cataracts, retinal detachment or glaucoma. To prevent further bleeding that could have caused one of these catastrophic conditions and surgery, the man had to rest his eye by staying very still for two weeks.</p> <p>The doctor said he was fortunate to receive prompt medical care that saved his eye. She says any job that involves working with a machine with an on-button requires the operator to wear eye protection. Any victims of such workplace accidents can seek recovery of medical expenses and lost wages by filing <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">workers' compensation benefits</a> claims with the New York insurance program.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>totallandscapecare.com, "<a href="http://www.totallandscapecare.com/green-industry-news/safety-watch-eye-protection/" target="_blank">Safety watch: Safety glasses need to part of PPE routine</a>", Jill Odom, July 10, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-injuries-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Using unmanned aircraft systems may prevent workplace accidents]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/06/using-unmanned-aircraft-systems-may-prevent-workplace-accidents.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244559</id>
  <published>2017-06-06T20:13:31Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:48Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Members of the workforce in New York may be interested in learning about the extensive use of unmanned aircraft systems (UAS) -- or drones -- in business applications nationwide. Research by the Association for Unmanned Vehicle Systems International supports the...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceinjuries" label="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Members of the workforce in New York may be interested in learning about the extensive use of unmanned aircraft systems (UAS) -- or drones -- in business applications nationwide. Research by the Association for Unmanned Vehicle Systems International supports the use of drones for various purposes in infrastructure industries, construction and emergency management along with oil, gas and mining operations. In many applications, drones are used to prevent <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">workplace accidents</a>.</p> <p>The New York-based facility of an international construction company started exploring the use of drones some years ago. The tests progressed with technology to a stage in which several applications have been identified to aid the goal of eliminating workplace hazards. The ability of UAS to photograph areas have proved to be of immense help in identifying hazards on job sites. Another advantage is the substantial cost savings that are brought about by using drones rather than specialist aerial photographers.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Any construction company can now have a trained employee deploy a drone to survey and photograph construction sites to identify potential hazards. This can be done as the project progresses and new dangers appear. A drone can access different areas of the building site at various stages -- something a manned aircraft could never do. Furthermore, rather than risking the life of an employee to enter a dangerous confined area, a drone could go in, send back images, measure air quality and provide the necessary information to make sure the necessary safety precautions are in place before sending workers into hazardous areas.</p> <p>The successful prevention of workplace accidents at the sites at which drones are used may encourage other business owners to do the same. However, injuries will likely continue to occur where employers choose not to prioritize employee safety. Injured victims can pursue financial help with unanticipated medical expenses and lost wages. Workers' compensation benefits are available through the company's insurance program, and the help of experienced attorneys is available.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>safetyandhealthmagazine.com, "<a href="http://www.safetyandhealthmagazine.com/articles/15626-when-drones-fly" target="_blank">When drones fly</a>", Kevin Druley, June 3, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-injuries-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Injured workers: Violence prevalent against New York nurses]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/05/injured-workers-violence-prevalent-against-new-york-nurses.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244556</id>
  <published>2017-05-17T16:22:01Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:47Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[The Violence Against Nurses Law became effective in Jan. 2010 when the New York Senate passed the legislation. A perpetrator who assaults a nurse could face felony charges for which the punishment upon conviction could be up to seven years...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceinjuries" label="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>The Violence Against Nurses Law became effective in Jan. 2010 when the New York Senate passed the legislation. A perpetrator who assaults a nurse could face felony charges for which the punishment upon conviction could be up to seven years behind bars. Sadly, such attacks remain prevalent, and concerned authorities say injured workers in hospitals should stop seeing it as part of the job.</p> <p>As recently as March, a nurse in an emergency room in a Staten Island hospital was punched by a patient before he proceeded to use a plastic wire to choke her. Another patient whose blood pressure was being checked punched a nurse in 2016, and in 2015, a man allegedly choked a nurse who was treating him. Furthermore, the New York State Nurses Association (NYSNA) says many assaults go unreported, as nurses are under the misconception that being spit on, punched and choked are par for the course.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>NYSNA says not only are nurses hit, beaten, shoved and kicked but they are also exposed verbal abuse, bullying and silent threats. These often go unreported because nurses fear retaliation. Training is offered at several hospitals to teach nurses how to handle such situations and how to protect themselves against attacks by patients.</p> <p>Injured workers in the nursing profession have a right to pursue <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">workers' compensation benefits</a> to cover medical expenses and lost wages. However, a consultation with an experienced New York workers' compensation attorney might be helpful. A lawyer can determine whether there are grounds for a civil lawsuit, which could be filed in conjunction with a workers' comp claim. Compensation received from workers' comp will have to be repaid if a civil court awards a monetary judgment; however, such an award might be considerably more than the workers' comp benefits.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>silive.com, "<a href="http://www.silive.com/news/2017/05/what_happens_when_those_who_he.html" target="_blank">'Just part of the job?' -- ER attacks a frightening reality for nurses</a>", Irene Spezzamonte, May 5. 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-injuries-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Study shows performance incentives cause workplace accidents]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/05/study-shows-performance-incentives-cause-workplace-accidents.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244555</id>
  <published>2017-05-10T19:12:47Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:47Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[It may come as no surprise to those in the New York workforce that many companies nationwide prioritize profits over worker safety. The combined research of two leading universities concludes&nbsp;that more workplace accidents occur at high-performing companies. The study used...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceinjuries" label="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>It may come as no surprise to those in the New York workforce that many companies nationwide prioritize profits over worker safety. The combined research of two leading universities concludes&nbsp;that more <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">workplace accidents</a> occur at high-performing companies. The study used data provided by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration along with the financial information of businesses.</p> <p>Those that show the highest injury rate are the companies whose financial performance meets or beats the expectations of financial analysts. It was found that these are companies at which management is incentivized to decrease production costs to bring about increased production output. It is easy to see how this form of motivation could jeopardize the safety of workers.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>The study shows that increased performance is achieved by cutting employee training and supervision. Furthermore, employees are asked to do more work in the same or fewer hours per day while overtime expenses are avoided where possible. Bigger workloads typically lead to safety protocols being disregarded. In some cases, the incentives are passed on to workers who are enticed by money to risk their lives.</p> <p>The same research revealed that employees at companies with a strong union presence are less likely to be involved in workplace accidents. Injured workers can seek financial assistance with medical expenses and lost wages and may be entitled to additional benefits upon proof of partial or permanent disabilities. This is accomplished in New York by filing claims for benefits through the workers' compensation insurance system, and an experienced workers' comp attorney is a valuable asset to help navigate the claims proceedings.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>safety.blr.com, "<a href="http://safety.blr.com/workplace-safety-news/safety-administration/safety-general/Are-your-managers-choosing-profits-over-protection/" target="_blank">Are your managers choosing profits over protection?</a>", May 3, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-injuries-1-->
</entry>

</feed>