<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/includes/blog-feed/atom.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Workers' Compensation Archives | Newburgh New York Workers' Compensation Law Blog]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/workers-compensation/" />
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/workers-compensation/atom.xml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2013-03-21:/blog/81520</id>
  <updated>2018-09-20T15:36:45Z</updated>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[This is the Workers' Compensation archive for Newburgh New York Workers' Compensation Law Blog.]]></subtitle>
  <generator uri="http://www.sixapart.com/movabletype/">Movable Type Enterprise</generator>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Can you get disability if it was not a workplace accident?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/09/can-you-get-disability-if-it-was-not-a-workplace-accident.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3444389</id>
  <published>2018-09-20T15:37:45Z</published>
  <updated>2018-09-20T15:36:45Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Workers in New York who suffer an injury or illness on the job will generally be able to get workers' compensation benefits. This is essential for people who cannot work and need payments to make ends meet and to...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workerscompensation" label="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Workers in New York who suffer an injury or illness on the job will generally be able to get workers' compensation benefits. This is essential for people who cannot work and need payments to make ends meet and to cover medical expenses. What they might not know is that they can also get disability benefits if the injury or illness took place off the job. This is under the umbrella of the Workers' Compensation Board. Understanding what benefits are available if they were <a href="http://www.wcb.ny.gov/content/main/TheBoard/disability-benefits-fact-sheet.pdf" target="_blank">injured off the job</a> and how to go about getting them is critical to the process.</p> <p>Since most employers are required to have disability insurance, workers who became injured or ill off the job can receive temporary cash benefits if their issues stop them from working. For cash, the worker will get half their average weekly wages with a maximum of $170 weekly. This is based on what they earned in the previous eight weeks until the final day they worked before being injured or getting ill. There will be Social Security taxes on these benefits.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Workers must wait seven days before getting the benefits. The payments will start on the eighth consecutive day in which they were disabled. The initial benefit payment will be due within four days following the fourteenth day. While the worker is disabled, the payments will come every two weeks. While the worker is receiving these payments, quitting the job for a reason that is not linked to the disability can impact the payments.</p> <p>A pregnant woman can get disability during maternity leave. Since disability can take place during pregnancy or post-childbirth, these benefits will be available. It is required that a physician or a certified nurse midwife certifies that the disability is in place. Should a claim be rejected, a worker has the right to ask for a review. The request must be sent to the Disability Benefits Bureau at the Workers' Compensation Board.</p> <p>Disability benefits can be crucial to making ends meet after a worker has suffered an injury or became ill off the job. Understanding the benefits available and the steps necessary in any situation is imperative. A law firm that is experienced in helping workers with disability and <a href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workers-Compensation/">workers' compensation</a> can try to help with a claim.</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workers-compensation-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[How does workers' compensation cover Schedule Loss of Use?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/08/how-does-workers-compensation-cover-schedule-loss-of-use.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3385289</id>
  <published>2018-08-09T15:22:51Z</published>
  <updated>2018-08-09T15:21:51Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Workers in New York who suffer workplace injuries should understand the different categories of loss their issues might fall into. Every workplace accident is different and can impact a person in a variety of ways. Depending on the circumstances,...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workerscompensation" label="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Workers in New York who suffer workplace injuries should understand the different categories of loss their issues might fall into. Every workplace accident is different and can impact a person in a variety of ways. Depending on the circumstances, the workers' compensation benefits can change. There can even be more benefits. Understanding these factors is imperative to a workers' compensation case, especially when there is disagreement or an outright dispute. This is specifically true in cases where there is a <a href="http://www.wcb.ny.gov/content/main/Workers/ScheduledLossUse.jsp" target="_blank">Schedule Loss of Use</a>.</p> <p>With Schedule Loss of Use, referred to as SLU, the injured worker will receive more cash than would otherwise be provided under workers' compensation. When the worker has suffered an injury that diminishes the ability to use a body part and he or she cannot return to the previous level of use, it is a permanent disability. Then there might be eligibility to get SLU. The worker can get this payment regardless of whether work time was missed or if there was a return to work.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>The following body part injuries could result in a person being eligible for SLU: hand, foot, facial injuries with scars, scalp, neck, toe, eye with vision loss, ear with hearing loss, leg, arm and finger. Also included are joints. A permanent injury can be burns in the second and third degree, a crush injury, severe nerve damage, dislocation, amputated limbs, fractures and more. The amount the person can get will vary based on the injury. For example, an injury to the arm will warrant 312 weeks in total. If there was 50 percent loss of use of the arm, 312 will be divided in half. The pay will be two-thirds of what the person earned per week and that will be paid for what would be earned in 156 weeks.</p> <p>To get SLU, it is necessary to receive a doctor's opinion as to when maximum medical improvement has been reached. For people who fall into this category, the additional pay can be vital to their future. To ensure that all the benefits available can be received and maximized often requires legal help. A law firm that understands all areas of <a href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/Loss-of-Use.shtml">workers' compensation benefits</a>, particularly SLU, may be of assistance.</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workers-compensation-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[What should I know about workers' comp for occupational disease?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/07/what-should-i-know-about-workers-comp-for-occupational-disease.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3367846</id>
  <published>2018-07-26T17:12:42Z</published>
  <updated>2018-07-26T17:11:42Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[New York State workers who suffer from an occupational disease should know that they can get workers' compensation benefits, just as a worker who suffered a physical injury can. However, it is imperative to understand that there are certain...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workerscompensation" label="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>New York State workers who suffer from an <a href="http://www.wcb.ny.gov/content/main/onthejob/OccDisease.jsp" target="_blank">occupational disease</a> should know that they can get workers' compensation benefits, just as a worker who suffered a physical injury can. However, it is imperative to understand that there are certain differences to consider when seeking those benefits. With an occupational disease, it must be an issue that has come about because of exposure to certain conditions on the job. It is vital to remember that the disease is required to have been produced naturally from the occupation itself.</p> <p>The workers' compensation benefits for an occupational disease are the same as they are for someone who was injured on the job. There is a different time limit when deciding to file the claim. It must be the later date of the following: two years from the date at which the disability came about; or two years from when the disabled worker knew or should have known that the disease came about because of the employment. The time limits are the same for family members if the worker has died. There can be a finding of disability if the person became ill and did not miss any work. A Workers' Compensation Law Judge will decide on the date at which the person became disabled.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>For people who have suffered occupational hearing loss, there are separate time limits. The worker has the choice of the following: three months from the date at which the worker was no longer working where the harmful noise is; or three months after leaving the employment where the noise was taking place. The last day of either of these three-month time frames will be the date at which the disability commenced. It is possible to file after the two years if it has been done within 90 days of the worker discovering that the hearing loss is because of the job.</p> <p>Often, people who have suffered an occupational disease will not even be aware that they are ill and can get <a href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workers-Compensation/">workers' compensation benefits</a>. In other instances, they miss the time limits for applying to get workers' compensation. When there is a belief that there is occupational disease, it is key to have legal assistance to pursue workers' compensation benefits. Calling immediately is a must.</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workers-compensation-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[What if my New York workers' compensation claim is controverted?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/07/what-if-my-new-york-workers-compensation-claim-is-controverted.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3346038</id>
  <published>2018-07-12T14:27:24Z</published>
  <updated>2018-07-12T14:26:24Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[People who are injured in a workplace accident will expect that their workers' compensation claim will be approved, and they will receive the benefits they are entitled to for treatment and wage coverage as they try to recover. However,...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workerscompensation" label="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>People who are injured in a workplace accident will expect that their workers' compensation claim will be approved, and they will receive the benefits they are entitled to for treatment and wage coverage as they try to recover. However, not all cases are immediately accepted at face value by the insurance company, and they will <a href="http://www.wcb.ny.gov/content/main/Employers/claimsprocess4.jsp" target="_blank">controvert a claim</a>. When a claim is controverted (denied) and the worker has legitimate injuries stemming from the work he or she was doing, it is important to know when this might take place and what to do about it.</p> <p>There are many reasons why the insurer can controvert the claim. They might say that the injury did not happen due to work, the employee's injuries are being exaggerated, the injuries happened on a second job and more. It is also possible that the employer will request that the insurance company controvert the employee's claim. Still, it is ultimately at the discretion of the employer as the insurer has responsibility for the claim's liability. It does not need to adhere to such a request from the employer.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>After the claim has been controverted, there will be a hearing so a Judge will listen to the arguments of both sides. The New York State Workers Compensation Board can have a hearing or require that the hearings be held before a Workers Compensation Law Judge.</p> <p>At the hearing, there can be testimony, depositions, medical reviews and assessment of other evidence to determine if the benefits should be provided. If the Judge decides that compensation should be provided, he or she will decide how much it should be and for how long it should last.</p> <p>When a worker is injured and the claim is controverted, it can be a worrisome time for the employee as it is venturing into the unknown as to how the case will be decided upon. Fortunately, there are options when the claim is controverted and it is possible to receive <a href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workers-Compensation/Why-Do-I-Need-a-Lawyer.shtml">workers' compensation benefits</a>. To ensure that the process goes smoothly and the worker's interests are protected, a law firm experienced in workers' compensation benefits should be contacted immediately.</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workers-compensation-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[What are disability classifications for workers' compensation?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/06/what-are-disability-classifications-for-workers-compensation.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3307421</id>
  <published>2018-06-14T17:45:20Z</published>
  <updated>2018-06-14T17:44:20Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Suffering workplace injuries in New York can cause concern for the worker and his or her family. The missed time on the job, lost wages, medical costs and uncertain future will inevitably lead to the worker seeking workers' compensation...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workerscompensation" label="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Suffering workplace injuries in New York can cause concern for the worker and his or her family. The missed time on the job, lost wages, medical costs and uncertain future will inevitably lead to the worker seeking workers' compensation to provide for them as they recover. If they are unable to recover, workers' compensation benefits can help with that too.</p> <p>However, workers are often unaware of the different <a href="http://www.wcb.ny.gov/content/main/TheBoard/indemnity-fact-sheet.pdf" target="_blank">disability classifications</a> in which their injuries are placed. Knowing these classifications and how it can affect their workers' compensation benefits is important in a claim and knowing how to proceed. The classifications are: Temporary Total Disability; Temporary Partial Disability; Permanent Total Disability; Permanent Partial Disability, Non-schedule Loss; Permanent Partial Disability, Schedule Loss; and Disfigurement.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Temporary Total Disability means that the person is unable to work and therefore cannot earn wages. The person will have the right to get the full wage benefit under workers' compensation. Temporary Partial Disability means that the worker has lost a certain amount of ability to work and can get full wages. The benefits the person receives will equal the determined percentage of the disability. Permanent Total Disability means that the worker has lost his or her ability to work and earn wages. These benefits will be continuous for the duration of the person's life.</p> <p>Permanent Partial Disability, Non-schedule Loss means that the person has lost a portion of the ability to work. There can be as much as 10 years of lost wage benefits. During those 10 years, if they are going to expire, the person might be able to get lifetime benefits if more than 75 percent of earning potential has been lost. There will be lifetime medical care. Permanent Partial Disability, Schedule Loss means there is loss of a body part, sight or hearing. There will be a total of weeks for which the worker will get benefits and the Workers' Compensation Board will determine its duration. Finally, Disfigurement means they have been disfigured on the face, head or neck. They can receive up to $20,000. This is contingent on the extent of the injury.</p> <p>When there is a workplace accident or a condition that came about because of the work, <a href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workers-Compensation/">workers' compensation</a> can be a vital part of making ends meet and receiving the necessary medical care. There are many different factors that are part of the workers' compensation process. Included is the classification of the worker's disability. When there is a problem with this or a disagreement regarding the classification that affects the benefits, having help from a workers' compensation attorney is imperative.</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workers-compensation-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[What if my workers' compensation claim is disputed?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/05/what-if-my-workers-compensation-claim-is-disputed.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3272242</id>
  <published>2018-05-18T04:53:50Z</published>
  <updated>2018-05-18T04:52:50Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[For New York State residents who are injured on the job or suffer a condition because of their work and it prevents them from working, workers' compensation benefits can be a lifeline. They can cover for lost wages, medical...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workerscompensation" label="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>For New York State residents who are injured on the job or suffer a condition because of their work and it prevents them from working, workers' compensation benefits can be a lifeline. They can cover for lost wages, medical expenses and more. However, there are times when there is a disagreement regarding the claim and it will be disputed. For those who file a workers' compensation claim and face a situation in which the insurer disputes it, it is critical to have legal assistance from an attorney who specializes in workers' compensation claims.</p> <p>If the insurer disputes the claim, it generally means that it does not agree that a work injury occurred, that it has not insured the employer, or there is another justification. Workers should understand that this does not mean that the case is over. The Workers' Compensation Board will have a hearing on the matter. At the hearing, a judge will examine the case with the medical records, wages the worker earned when working, and any other factor relevant to the claim. A decision will be made as to whether the worker should get workers' compensation or not.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Once the decision is made, the claimant or the insurer can file an appeal. It must be in writing and be done within 30 days of when the case was filed. The appeal will be reviewed by three Board members. It can be changed, rejected or there can be a request made for more hearings. While the case is in dispute, the claimant can ask to get disability benefits while it is heard.</p> <p>When the workers' compensation claim is disputed by the insurer, it can be a worrisome time for the claimant. The prospect of not getting the benefits can cause significant problems and the person might not know what to do if the claim is rejected. When seeking workers' compensation benefits, it is imperative to have legal help from the start to deal with any eventuality. A lawyer who is experienced in <a href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workers-Compensation/">workers' compensation benefits</a> should be contacted immediately.</p> <p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>wcb.ny.gov, "<a href="http://www.wcb.ny.gov/content/main/TheBoard/file-claim-fact-sheet.pdf" target="_blank">What to Expect When You File a Claim -- If Your Claim Is Disputed</a>," accessed on May 16, 2018</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workers-compensation-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Important guidelines involving workers' compensation]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/01/important-guidelines-involving-workers-compensation.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3244592</id>
  <published>2018-01-24T17:41:57Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:51Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Safety authorities say most workplace accidents are avoidable if prescribed safety regulations are followed. However, on-the-job injuries continue to happen, and employees are sometimes blamed for causing the accidents in which they were injured. Fortunately, the New York workers' compensation...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workerscompensation" label="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Safety authorities say most workplace accidents are avoidable if prescribed safety regulations are followed. However, on-the-job injuries continue to happen, and employees are sometimes blamed for causing the accidents in which they were injured. Fortunately, the New York <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workers-Compensation/">workers' compensation</a> program is a no-fault system, which provides benefits regardless of who was at fault.</p> <p>In exchange for this assurance, injured workers are expected to refrain from filing lawsuits against their employers. As with all legal matters, exceptions exist. Workers who can prove that intentional malice or gross negligence by their employers led to the incidents that caused their injuries might have grounds to file personal injury lawsuits in a civil court. Similarly, employers who believe that an employee was injured off-duty or that his or her willful misconduct caused the injuries may reject the benefits claim.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Reasons for rejected workers' compensation claims include proof that the injured worker was under the influence of drugs or alcohol at the time of the workplace accident. On-the-job injuries that resulted from horseplay or physical fighting may also lead to rejected claims. Claims for benefits for injuries that happened outside of working hours could be denied, but those that occurred at a company-sponsored event will qualify as job-related injuries. This will apply even if alcohol was involved at an occasion in which employee presence was mandatory.</p> <p>New York workers who have questions about their eligibility to file benefits claims may get answers from an experienced workers' compensation attorney. Those whose claims were denied may also find the assistance of a lawyer to be invaluable. By following the appropriate procedures, an attorney may be able to secure all the benefits to which an injured worker is entitled.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>FindLaw, "<a href="http://blogs.findlaw.com/injured/2014/10/can-you-still-get-workers-comp-if-you-were-at-fault.html" target="_blank">Can You Still Get Workers' Comp If You Were at Fault?</a>", Brett Snider, Accessed on Jan. 19, 2018</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workers-compensation-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[New workers' comp benefits guidelines see strong opposition]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/10/new-workers-comp-benefits-guidelines-see-strong-opposition.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244576</id>
  <published>2017-10-02T15:50:42Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:49Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Medical professionals and safety and health advocates expressed their opposition to the New York State Workers' Compensation Board's proposed altered guidelines at a recent press conference. Some say that the changes are merely measures for companies to cut costs, with...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workerscompensation" label="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Medical professionals and safety and health advocates expressed their opposition to the New York State Workers' Compensation Board's proposed altered guidelines at a recent press conference. Some say that the changes are merely measures for companies to cut costs, with injured employees paying for it in denied <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workers-Compensation/">benefits</a>. While safety authorities sought improved compensation for injured workers, the new proposal will see workplace injury victims considerably worse off.</p> <p>According to the new guidelines, only company-assigned physicians may provide care, regardless of their ability to communicate in a language understood by the injured worker. This doctor will have full power to recommend or suspend care and benefits at will. Many life-altering injuries will no longer be compensable, and the levels of coverage for several severe impairments will be slashed significantly.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>The existing Schedule Loss of Use awards will also cut the number of disabilities that will qualify for benefits. The safety advocates claim that compensation for legitimate injuries that have been paid under the workers' compensation system for years will no longer be covered. Furthermore, they claim workers will be denied assistance at times in which they are most vulnerable.</p> <p>It is not clear whether the calls for the withdrawal of the New York State Workers' Compensation Board's proposed new guidelines will be successful. In the future, injured workers might have to rely more and more on the skills of an experienced workers' compensation attorney to fight for their rights to benefits. No worker should be denied fair compensation after suffering a workplace injury.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>workerscompensation.com, "<a href="https://www.workerscompensation.com/news_read.php?id=27435" target="_blank">NY Workplace Safety And Health Advocates Demand Workers' Comp Board Withdraw Proposed Cuts To Protections And Benefits</a>", Sept. 27, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workers-compensation-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Can marijuana use affect workers' compensation benefits?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/02/can-marijuana-use-affect-workers-compensation-benefits.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244542</id>
  <published>2017-02-08T10:37:11Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:46Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[With marijuana now legalized for medicinal use in some states, including New York, the laws regulating it in the workplace may need some updating. Back in 2013, an employee of a juvenile center in another state injured his neck and...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workerscompensation" label="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>With marijuana now legalized for medicinal use in some states, including New York, the laws regulating it in the workplace may need some updating. Back in 2013, an employee of a juvenile center in another state injured his neck and shoulder while trying to subdue an aggressive youth. His <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workers-Compensation/">workers' compensation</a> benefits claim was questioned when blood tests revealed that he tested positive for marijuana.</p> <p>Reportedly, a drug test following the incident showed the presence of pot in his system, and so did a follow-up test on the next day. Although a court determined that the marijuana might not have been the major cause of the incident that caused the injuries, it rejected his claim for compensation. The worker appealed, claiming the court based its finding on only one sentence of the law, rather than applying the entire section in context.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Apparently, the law says no compensation will be paid to an employee who suffered injuries while impaired by alcohol or illegal chemicals or drugs. However, the preceding sentence provides that if a preponderance of the evidence establishes that the substance present in the employee's blood was not the primary cause of the injuries, then the claim will be compensable. The state's highest court reversed the denial of the claim and found the employee eligible for benefits.</p> <p>Many injured employees in New York whose benefits claims are denied seek the help of an experienced workers' compensation attorney. Having a skilled lawyer to fight for their rights may lead to the compensation to which they are entitled. Such a professional can guide injured workers through the claims process and assist with challenging legal barriers that may arise.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>safetynewsalert.com, "<a href="http://www.safetynewsalert.com/injured-at-work-tested-positive-for-pot-does-he-get-workers-comp/" target="_blank">Injured at work, positive test for pot: Does he get workers' comp?</a>", Fred Hosier, Accessed on Feb. 3, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workers-compensation-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Campaign to cut workers' compensation benefits stalls]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2016/09/campaign-to-cut-workers-compensation-benefits-stalls.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2016:/blog//81520.3244521</id>
  <published>2016-09-20T19:07:57Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:43Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Everyone is aware of the raucous presidential campaign that consumes more and more of the media's time and energy. Another important campaign is underway, however, garnering much less attention. It's the national campaign to revise state laws to enable businesses...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workerscompensation" label="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Everyone is aware of the raucous presidential campaign that consumes more and more of the media's time and energy. Another important campaign is underway, however, garnering much less attention.</p> <p>It's the national campaign to revise state laws to enable businesses to opt out of <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workers-Compensation/">workers' compensation insurance</a>. The employers would then get to decide on their own workers' comp plans. The movement recently stalled when Oklahoma's Supreme Court ruled that that state's version is unconstitutional.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Perhaps unsurprisingly, the nationwide campaign is being bankrolled by large retail chains (Wal-Mart, Hobby Lobby and Lowe's, for instance), as well as trucking companies, the oil and gas industry and health care corporations. Also probably not surprising: an analysis of the proposals by <a href="http://www.npr.org/2016/09/13/493805684/oklahomas-top-court-says-companies-cant-set-own-rules-for-injured-workers" target="_blank" >ProPublica and NPR</a> shows that the plans would reduce benefits and make it more difficult for injured workers to qualify for compensation.</p> <p>But courts are putting the brakes on the campaign. In addition to Oklahoma's top court's rejection of the proposal, the Florida Supreme Court struck down laws that limited temporary disability pay to two years and also reduced attorneys' fees.</p> <p>Similar caps were made law in West Virginia, California, North Dakota and Texas.</p> <p>The Oklahoma ruling means Texas is now the sole state allowing employers to get out of workers' comp. The court held that the opt-out clause created an uneven playing field with groups of workers receiving differing benefits, care and restrictions.</p> <p>Right now, the campaign has suffered a setback, but supporters vow to continue their fight.</p> <p>If you have suffered a workplace injury or work-related illness, a Newburgh workers' compensation attorney can help you appeal a denial of deserved benefits.</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workers-compensation-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Workers' compensation insurance rate rising]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2016/07/workers-compensation-insurance-rate-rising.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2016:/blog//81520.3244513</id>
  <published>2016-07-25T18:01:54Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:42Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[New York employers will face higher costs for workers' compensation insurance starting in October, the state Department of Financial Services has decided. The DFS approved an average 9.3 percent hike in the insurance rate; an increase that business owners are...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workerscompensation" label="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>New York employers will face higher costs for workers' compensation insurance starting in October, the state Department of Financial Services has decided. The DFS approved an average 9.3 percent hike in the insurance rate; an increase that business owners are not thrilled with, but acknowledge is needed, according to a recent news report.</p> <p>The DFS superintendent said insurers threatened that they might have to leave the state if their rates didn't go up to cover their costs.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Unsurprisingly, New York's business community expressed disappointment in the rate hike and in the workers' compensation system. Worker advocates point out that the system still does not fully address the needs of <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workers-Compensation/Workers-Compensation-Money-Benefits.shtml" >employees who are injured on the job</a> or are subjected to work-related illnesses.</p> <p><a href="http://www.timesunion.com/local/article/Workers-Compensation-rates-are-rising-8394607.php" target="_blank" >The Albany Times Union report</a> on the rate increase quotes a Long Island attorney said he is worried that workers' comp reforms pushed by business interests could simply be a way of cutting benefits.</p> <p>As you undoubtedly know, New York workers' compensation benefits include medical care and a partial replacement of lost wages.</p> <p>For people who are injured while on the job, every penny of those benefits is needed to pay for medical costs that can include hospitalization, surgeries, physical therapy and more. And wage replacement is needed to help injured employees pay for mortgages or rent, food, utilities and other essentials until they can recover from injury or illness and return to work.</p> <p>A skilled Albany workers' compensation attorney can help protect your rights to full and fair compensation.</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workers-compensation-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Getting the workers' comp benefits you need and deserve]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2016/07/getting-the-workers-comp-benefits-you-need-and-deserve.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2016:/blog//81520.3244512</id>
  <published>2016-07-14T16:44:38Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:42Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[From the employee's side, a workplace injury is often a mixture of pain, medical treatment, time away from the job and recovery. From the employer's side, the issues are more about one thing: money. When a New York worker is...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workerscompensation" label="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>From the employee's side, a workplace injury is often a mixture of pain, medical treatment, time away from the job and recovery. From the employer's side, the issues are more about one thing: money.</p> <p>When a New York worker is injured on the job, they are <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workers-Compensation/Workers-Compensation-Hearings-Appeals.shtml" >entitled to workers' compensation</a> to pay for medical care and to replace a portion of their lost wages. This part of the safety net is crucial to working people, enabling them to get the care they need and to continue providing for themselves and their families.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>A recent article at Business.com stresses that workers' compensation insurance is not an option for most employers. The required coverage protects the employer as well as the employee in cases of on-the-job injuries and occupational illnesses.</p> <p>Perhaps unsurprisingly, the <a href="http://www.business.com/human-resources/the-real-business-risks-of-workplace-injuries/" target="_blank" >article on a business site</a> laments the fact that workers have the right to get representation in workers' comp cases, including in appeals. "Some workers may resort to consulting with a workers' compensation attorney to ensure that they receive benefits, particularly when claims are contested."</p> <p>Yes, workers will often turn to an experienced attorney when workers' comp benefits are at stake. Those benefits can include money for a hospital stay, doctor's visits, surgeries, physical therapy, and lost wages. The benefits can quickly mount in situations in which the injuries are serious and time away from work is lengthy.</p> <p>In these situations in which the stakes are high, you can rest assured that the insurer and employer will be represented when a Workers' Compensation Board decision is appealed. With the help of a Newburgh workers' comp attorney, you can level the playing field and fight for the benefits you need and deserve.</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workers-compensation-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Workplace violence: All-too-common danger for nurses]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2016/06/workplace-violence-all-too-common-danger-for-nurses.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2016:/blog//81520.3244510</id>
  <published>2016-06-27T17:53:19Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:42Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Nurses from Newburgh to Napa — and everywhere in between — share concerns about safety in the workplace. For many nurses, workplace violence is a regular part of their workdays; a frightening reality that they must deal with every time...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workerscompensation" label="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Nurses from Newburgh to Napa — and everywhere in between — share concerns about safety in the workplace. For many nurses, workplace violence is a regular part of their workdays; a frightening reality that they must deal with every time they report for duty in emergency rooms and other parts of hospitals.</p> <p>"Not a shift goes by that we’re not exposed to workplace violence," an intensive care nurse recently said, adding that she has had to have four major surgeries as a result of <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workplace-Accidents/Nurses-Medical-Workers.shtml" >injuries sustained</a> in patient assaults.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>The Minneapolis nurse was one of hundreds who recently took part in a 7-day strike to improve working conditions that, they say, make life in the health care industry unnecessarily difficult and dangerous.</p> <p>"This is the type of thing that happens in all hospitals around the country," one nurse said.</p> <p>One ER nurse said that she and her co-workers must deal with violent patients and families "every shift."</p> <p>They complain that <a href="http://www.workdayminnesota.org/articles/striking-nurses-highlight-violence-they-suffer-job" target="_blank" >hospitals are reluctant or unwilling</a> to provide needed security staff stationed in the ER. Instead, the nurses rely on each other, emergency medical technicians and sometimes a hospital security officer, if she or he "happens to be in the (area)."</p> <p>One nurse told the story of a traumatic brain injury she suffered when a patient kicked in her in the right temple.</p> <p>Workers who have sustained on-the-job injuries due to violence in the workplace by either co-workers or members of the public are typically eligible for workers' compensation benefits. If those benefits are denied by an insurer or employer, appeal is possible with the assistance of a workers' comp attorney.</p> <p> </p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workers-compensation-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[New York workers' compensation deadlines]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2016/05/new-york-workers-compensation-deadlines.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2016:/blog//81520.3244504</id>
  <published>2016-05-17T15:31:22Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:41Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[It might seem unfair or unreasonable, but the reality is that as soon as you are injured in the workplace, the clock starts ticking. Injured workers have deadlines to meet, even if they cannot work. The deadlines are imposed by...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workerscompensation" label="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>It might seem unfair or unreasonable, but the reality is that as soon as you are injured in the workplace, the clock starts ticking. <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workers-Compensation/Workers-Compensation-Hearings-Appeals.shtml">Injured workers</a> have deadlines to meet, even if they cannot work.</p> <p>The deadlines are imposed by the New York State Workers' Compensation Board. In order to qualify for workers' comp benefits, you have to meet the deadlines. Of course, the first order of business when you sustain a workplace injury is to get needed medical treatment.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Then you must notify your supervisor about the accident, and how it happened. Within 30 days, you must also <a href="http://www.wcb.ny.gov/content/main/onthejob/HowSystemWorks.jsp" target="_blank">give your employer written notice</a> of the accident.</p> <p><b>More deadlines for employees and others</b></p> <ul> <li>The injured worker has to file a workers' comp claim with the Board District Office (within two years).</li> <li>Preliminary medical report must be filed by a doctor within 48 hours of the accident</li> <li>Within 10 days of the notification of the accident, your employer must report the injury to the insurer and workers' comp board.</li> <li>Within 18 days of receiving that injury report from your employer, the insurer begins payment of benefits&nbsp;-&nbsp;unless the claim is being disputed. If it's being disputed, the insurer has to notify you and the Workers' Compensation Board.</li> </ul> <p>So what happens when a claim is disputed? A workers' comp Law Judge decides on the matter after a hearing. These hearings are crucial. The insurance company will be there with its attorney, ready to deny you your claim.</p> <p>Experienced workers' comp attorneys know the law and how to apply it to your situation: crucial elements of preserving your claim and securing your benefits.</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workers-compensation-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Cath labs, radiation and health worker safety]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2016/04/cath-labs-radiation-and-health-worker-safety.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2016:/blog//81520.3244496</id>
  <published>2016-04-13T16:50:52Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:40Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Some modern medical treatments are very aggressive and can involve powerful substances or forces. Thus, some unique safety concerns can come up for medical workers, as their work environment can involve things that many other work environments don't. One such...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workerscompensation" label="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Some modern medical treatments are very aggressive and can involve powerful substances or forces. Thus, some unique safety concerns can come up for medical workers, as their work environment can involve things that many other work environments don't.</p> <p>One such thing is radiation. One medical work environment where radiation can be a factor are cath labs. In these labs, various radiation-related heart treatments are performed.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>A recent study looked at cath lab workers and health issues. In the study, which was done in Italy, researchers compared the health of medical workers who were exposed to radiation in cath labs and medical workers who weren't. The exposed workers were found to have higher likelihoods for various health conditions as compared to the unexposed workers, including: cancer, cataracts, orthopedic illnesses and skin lesions. Exposed workers that had been working for many years showed particularly high likelihoods.</p> <p>While this study involved medical workers from another country, it underscores some points that are worth keeping in mind when it comes to cath labs here in the U.S., such as that cath lab radiation can raise worker safety concerns and that workplace radiation safety is an important thing when it comes to such labs. </p> <p>One would hope all cath lab workers would be provided with proper safety equipment during their work and would be given proper radiation safety training. What sorts of radiation safety measures would you like to see taken here in the U.S. when it comes to cath labs?</p> <p>As this discussion underscores, there are many different kinds of health and safety issues that can arise when it comes to health care work. So, the range of different occupational injuries and illnesses medical workers could potentially suffer is pretty wide. Workers' comp lawyers can help medical workers with workers' comp issues related to injuries and illnesses developed on the job.</p> <p><strong>Source: </strong>Reuters, "<a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-radiation-cathlab-idUSKCN0X92J4" target="_blank" >Healthcare providers in cath labs may be harmed by radiation</a>," Kathryn Doyle, April 12, 2016</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workers-compensation-->
</entry>

</feed>