<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/includes/blog-feed/atom.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Construction Workers' Accidents Archives | Newburgh New York Workers' Compensation Law Blog]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/construction-workers-accidents/" />
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/construction-workers-accidents/atom.xml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2013-03-21:/blog/81520</id>
  <updated>2018-09-05T14:31:39Z</updated>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[This is the Construction Workers' Accidents archive for Newburgh New York Workers' Compensation Law Blog.]]></subtitle>
  <generator uri="http://www.sixapart.com/movabletype/">Movable Type Enterprise</generator>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Construction accidents in New York are on the rise]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/09/construction-accidents-in-new-york-are-on-the-rise.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3420881</id>
  <published>2018-09-05T14:32:39Z</published>
  <updated>2018-09-05T14:31:39Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Throughout New York, construction is seemingly constant. This is a positive as it provides jobs and other benefits. However, concerns about safety are ever-present and one of the most dangerous jobs that anyone can do is in construction. With...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="constructionworkersaccidents" label="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Throughout New York, construction is seemingly constant. This is a positive as it provides jobs and other benefits. However, concerns about safety are ever-present and one of the most dangerous jobs that anyone can do is in construction. With the heavy machinery, working on scaffolds and ladders at great heights, and the large tools that are inherent with construction work, a construction worker accident can happen for a variety of reasons. <a href="https://nypost.com/2018/09/01/construction-accidents-soar-amid-nyc-building-boom/" target="_blank">Research has found</a> that the number of construction accidents have been rising in a worrisome fashion.</p> <p>In New York City, there has been a rise in construction injuries and fatalities. Injuries have increased by 17 percent; fatalities have doubled. Through July, there were eight construction-related fatalities to workers. In 2017, in that same amount of time, there were four deaths. Regarding injuries, the first seven months of the year had 457 job-related accidents and 469 injuries.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>The Bureau of Labor Statistics says that the job with the highest risk in the city is construction work. Construction accidents led to more than 37 percent of the deaths on the job for 2016. At least 50 people have been hurt by falling debris thus far in 2018. Part of the reason there are so many accidents is the amount of construction that is taking place. With more than 45,000 construction workers in the city alone, accidents occur because of negligence, errors and accidents. Attempts to make the job safer have included increased training for construction workers, increased penalties for employers who shun proper safety and keeping better track of accidents as they occur.</p> <p>A construction worker accident can leave a person with the need for extensive medical care, lifelong injuries and the inability to get back to the same type of job, if the worker can get back to work at all. Whether it was a fall, burns, broken bones, joint injuries, spinal cord damage, head injuries or other issues, legal help can be essential to get workers' compensation benefits, coverage for medical care and help with lost wages. In some cases, there is a disagreement over issues such as how long the worker will be out and the amount of medical care that is needed. An experienced law firm can try to help with <a href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/Construction-Accident-Injuries/">construction accidents</a> and the legal claims that need to pursued.</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--construction-workers-accidents-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Work zone injuries a rising problem in New York]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/08/work-zone-injuries-a-rising-problem-in-new-york.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3402154</id>
  <published>2018-08-23T15:33:24Z</published>
  <updated>2018-08-23T15:32:24Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[When thinking about construction accidents and the dangers that a construction worker might face in New York, the immediate thought turns to constructing tall buildings, working on a roof, being stationed at great heights and dealing with heavy machinery....]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="constructionworkersaccidents" label="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>When thinking about construction accidents and the dangers that a construction worker might face in New York, the immediate thought turns to constructing tall buildings, working on a roof, being stationed at great heights and dealing with heavy machinery. However, road workers who are doing necessary construction to build, maintain and repair the state's infrastructure are in substantial jeopardy of being in an accident - perhaps more than other construction workers. Needing to navigate roadwork with drivers who might not pay attention to the dangers can lead to a construction worker accident and injuries. It can even cause death. Those who have been hurt must remember they are likely entitled to workers' compensation.</p> <p>According to the statistics, there were <a href="https://www.mytwintiers.com/news/local-news/nysdot-urge-caution-after-2017-saw-nearly-700-work-zone-crashes/1357519558" target="_blank">almost 700 accidents</a> in construction zones in New York in 2017. Distracted driving is believed to have been a cause in a significant number of them. Although the New York State Department of Transportation is entreating drivers to pay close attention to the road as they are supposed to, there are seemingly endless anecdotes from workers about drivers who are not watching what they are doing and are therefore placing workers at risk.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>A recent article noted how one worker who does maintenance stated that he witnessed a driver who was not using a smartphone while behind the wheel, but was using a laptop. This same worker was injured when his truck was rear-ended by a tractor-trailer. He suffered injuries to his neck that are still problematic. Initially, he had headaches, but treatment was effective in alleviating them. Another worker who did maintenance for the NYSDOT was hurt when a tractor-trailer ran into the work zone and he was hit by a sharp object. His helmet prevented long-term damage. The driver continued without stopping.</p> <p>Any worker who is employed in a construction work zone where vehicles pass should be aware of the chance that there could be a crash due to a driver speeding, behaving recklessly, driving under the influence or failing to pay attention. When suffering injuries on the job, there will be the need for medical care, coverage for the lost wages and other costs. Workers' compensation benefits are imperative to recover and to make ends meet. When seeking workers' compensation after suffering <a href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/Construction-Accident-Injuries/">serious injuries</a> when working on road construction, it can be beneficial to speak to a law firm experienced in representing injured workers.</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--construction-workers-accidents-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Construction site dangers cause many types of worker injuries]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/04/construction-site-dangers-cause-many-types-of-worker-injuries.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3244607</id>
  <published>2018-04-25T09:37:09Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:36:09Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[The hazards of working at a construction site are significant and when proper precautions are not taken New York workers can suffer injuries and death. There are a number of different ways that worksite deficiencies can cause injury-producing construction...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="constructionworkersaccidents" label="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>The hazards of working at a construction site are significant and when proper precautions are not taken New York workers can suffer injuries and death. There are a number of different ways that worksite deficiencies can cause injury-producing construction site accidents and this post will only touch on some of them. The information contained herein is not comprehensive on the topic of construction site accidents and should not be used as legal guidance.</p> <p>One of the most common ways that workers are hurt in <a href="https://injury.findlaw.com/workers-compensation/common-construction-injury-types.html" target="_blank">construction injuries</a> is through falls. Not long ago this post offered an article on a construction worker who fell down an elevator shaft while at work; falls can occur from buildings, off of equipment as well as from scaffolding. When workers are not properly tethered to heights they can suffer damaging and dangerous falls.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Accidents with vehicles and machinery are another common cause of construction site injuries. Workers can suffer injuries when work vehicles back into them and when vehicles pin them between their bumpers and other stationary objects. When workers are not properly trained to use the dangerous machines required of their jobs they can create significant hazards for themselves and others at their worksites.</p> <p>Exposure to chemicals and other substances can cause workers to not just suffer injuries but also to develop work-related illnesses. The types and causes of work-related illnesses are extensive, and as with all matters related to their health readers should seek help from medical professionals for their ailments. This post does not offer any medical advice but is intended to present its readers with a general overview of the many ways <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Construction-Accident-Injuries/">construction workers</a> can suffer harm while on the job.</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--construction-workers-accidents-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Assembly member urges rejection of Scaffold Law "reform"]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/04/assembly-member-urges-rejection-of-scaffold-law-reform.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3244606</id>
  <published>2018-04-25T09:36:20Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:35:20Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[New York State’s Scaffold Law has repeatedly been targeted by business interests for elimination that is often mislabeled as "reform." They argue that the law drives up construction costs and makes it more difficult for women and minorities to get...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="constructionworkersaccidents" label="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>New York State’s Scaffold Law has repeatedly been targeted by business interests for elimination that is often mislabeled as "reform." They argue that the law drives up construction costs and makes it more difficult for women and minorities to get into construction work, Assembly member Phil Steck wrote recently in Albany's Times Union.</p> <p>He argues in an op-ed piece that corporate America has been waging war on safety laws that it claims slow economic growth. Steck writes that the evidence shows that <a href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/Construction-Accident-Injuries/Scaffolding-Accidents.shtml" >the Scaffold Law</a> does not deter business at all. When a developer talks of a new project, there is no shortage of construction firms eager to bid on the work, he notes.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>At its core, the law requires construction firms to supply their workers with appropriate, needed safety gear and to direct workers how to use it. If an employer fails to do that, and a worker is injured in a fall (or by a falling object), the owner of the firm is liable.</p> <p>If a worker doesn't follow safety instructions, the law also provides the employer with a defense to liability. The worker cannot recover damages in those cases, Steck writes.</p> <p>He also notes that the law is clear and provides no loopholes for construction firms to use to dodge responsibility if they fail to provide safety equipment. "And that is as it should be," he points out.</p> <p>He concludes his <a href="https://www.timesunion.com/opinion/article/Commentary-Scaffold-Law-reform-calls-don-t-12778960.php" target="_blank" >opinion piece</a> with a warning that if the Scaffold Law is "reformed," it will be taxpayers who will foot the bill. Insurance companies will "save by paying out less to injured workers" and those workers (often disabled because of a fall) will be forced to rely on government programs.</p> <p>If you or a loved one has been injured in a fall on a construction site, speak with an attorney who can help you receive full workers' compensation benefits and discuss with you other legal options, including personal injury litigation.</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--construction-workers-accidents-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Construction accidents: Worker dies when knocked off forklift]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/03/construction-accidents-worker-dies-when-knocked-off-forklift.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3244600</id>
  <published>2018-03-20T16:56:22Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:52Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Forklifts can cause severe or fatal injuries if not used with the necessary care. Construction accidents involving lift trucks are frequent, and one such an incident claimed the life of a New York worker on a recent Tuesday. According to...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="constructionworkersaccidents" label="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Forklifts can cause severe or fatal injuries if not used with the necessary care. Construction accidents involving lift trucks are frequent, and one such an incident claimed the life of a New York worker on a recent Tuesday. According to the Department of Buildings, several open investigations are pending for safety violations on this construction site.</p> <p>Reportedly, the accident occurred at approximately 11 a.m. Authorities say two workers were using a forklift to move bundles of windows. A 34-year-old worker was standing on top of the fork of the lift truck that was being operated by a co-worker. Apparently, the driver put the forklift in reverse to back up, and the man standing on the fork failed to notice a beam that was part of a low ceiling.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>An incident report indicates that he suffered fatal injuries when he was struck against the head. The New York City Department of Buildings reports that the site was under a stop work order, which was one of multiple active orders against the company. However, such an order only prohibits construction and not storage, which was what the moving of the windows involved.</p> <p>New York families who have lost loved ones in <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Construction-Accident-Injuries/">construction accidents</a> are typically entitled to seek financial assistance to help them cope with the unanticipated costs of such tragedies. The workers' compensation insurance system typically offers survivors' benefits that cover the expenses related to end-of-life arrangements. Furthermore, a financial package to serve as wage replacement may also form part of the benefits, and this is typically based on the average weekly wage of the deceased worker.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>amny.com, "<a href="https://www.amny.com/news/queens-construction-worker-killed-1.17368883" target="_blank">Queens construction worker killed in forklift mishap, police say</a>", Alison Fox, March 13, 2018</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--construction-workers-accidents-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Practices to prevent serious injuries in hospital construction]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/02/practices-to-prevent-serious-injuries-in-hospital-construction.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3244597</id>
  <published>2018-02-26T17:49:51Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:51Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[The ever-growing population and the fact that many people live longer creates a need for more and improved facilities to provide health care services in New York and elsewhere. Because many projects involve construction on existing facilities, extra precautions must...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="constructionworkersaccidents" label="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>The ever-growing population and the fact that many people live longer creates a need for more and improved facilities to provide health care services in New York and elsewhere. Because many projects involve construction on existing facilities, extra precautions must be taken to prevent <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Construction-Accident-Injuries/">serious injuries</a> to patients, medical staff and construction workers. Careful planning is essential when expansions or renovations must take place where patients cannot be vacated.</p> <p>The first step is proper planning and anticipating every possible scenario before ground is even broken. While it is essential to ensure that every worker is equipped with the necessary personal protective equipment, adequate training is also vital. Working under circumstances where everybody is expected to tread softly is far removed from the more familiar construction sites, and briefing construction workers about how to consider the safety of the patients will be necessary.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>One of the biggest threats under these circumstances is the weakened or compromised immune systems of the patients. Containment procedures must be planned and executed with precision. These could include separate entrances for the construction workers, portable units to contain dust, temporary partitions that do not involve dust-producing dry walling&nbsp;and utilization of noise reducing technology. Furthermore, prevention of the usual construction site accidents must not be neglected -- fall prevention harnesses, hard hats and other protection will still be required.</p> <p>While construction company owners in New York would likely not want to see their employees admitted to the medical facilities where they are working, serious injuries may not always be prevented. Injured workers are typically entitled to claim workers' compensation benefits to medical bills and lost wages. Depending on the circumstances that led to the injuries, the claims process could be complicated. Securing the help of an experienced workers' compensation attorney is typically a wise choice.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>hconews.com, "<a href="http://hconews.com/2018/02/20/preventative-treatment-hospital-construction/" target="_blank">Reinforcing Preventative Treatment in Hospital Construction</a>", Kris Manning, Feb. 20, 2018</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--construction-workers-accidents-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Fatal construction accidents: New York City vs. New York State]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/02/fatal-construction-accidents-new-york-city-vs-new-york-state.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3244595</id>
  <published>2018-02-12T14:00:40Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:51Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Authorities want New York State to adopt a similar level of workplace safety standards as that of New York City. A recent study indicates that fatalities in construction accidents in the city numbered only 21 in 2016 -- four less...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="constructionworkersaccidents" label="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Authorities want New York State to adopt a similar level of workplace safety standards as that of New York City. A recent study indicates that fatalities in <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Construction-Accident-Injuries/">construction accidents</a> in the city numbered only 21 in 2016 -- four less than in the previous year. In contrast, the number of construction worker deaths that occurred in the remainder of the state in 2016 was 71, which is 16 more than in 2015, and the highest in 14 years.</p> <p>Reportedly, the fatality rate in the state ranks New York among the top 10 states in which the most construction workers lost their lives in on-the-job accidents. Some believe this follows the increase in building activities and the decrease in the number of Occupational Safety and Health compliance inspectors. During this time, the efforts of the New York City Council in collaboration with the Department of Buildings and the office of the Manhattan District Attorney have brought about significant improvements in the safety culture of construction in New York City.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>It is believed that the criminal charges that were filed against a construction company in 2015 after a 22-year-old worker died in a trench collapse led to the demand for stricter safety regulations. New regulations include requirements for 10- to 14-story projects to have a safety coordinator on site, and any buildings higher than that must have a safety manager present. Furthermore, construction workers who have not completed apprenticeships or have not received 100 hours of safety training will have to undergo 40 hours of such training within the next three years.</p> <p>While the hopes of workers in this industry in New York State may be on more compliance with stricter safety regulations, they might still be concerned about how their families will cope if they should lose their lives in fatal construction accidents. They may find comfort in knowing that an experienced workers' compensation attorney will be there to help. A lawyer can assist any family with the navigation of claims for survivors' benefits that will cover end-of-life expenses and lost wages.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>constructiondive.com, "<a href="https://www.constructiondive.com/news/report-ny-state-construction-fatalities-hit-14-year-high-in-2016/516198/" target="_blank">Report: New York state construction fatalities hit 14-year high in 2016</a>", Kim Slowey, Feb. 2, 2018</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--construction-workers-accidents-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Construction accidents: Worker survives fall down elevator shaft]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/01/construction-accidents-worker-survives-fall-down-elevator-shaft.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3244590</id>
  <published>2018-01-08T20:23:20Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:51Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Exposure to height hazards is par for the course in the construction industry, and employers must protect workers from all known dangers. Falls remain the cause of a significant percentage of severe injuries and fatalities in construction accidents in New...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="constructionworkersaccidents" label="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Exposure to height hazards is par for the course in the construction industry, and employers must protect workers from all known dangers. Falls remain the cause of a significant percentage of severe injuries and fatalities in <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Construction-Accident-Injuries/">construction accidents</a> in New York and elsewhere. In many cases, victims were not equipped with fall protection.</p> <p>A fall on a construction site in a neighboring state will likely be investigated by safety authorities to determine whether the injured worker wore a safety harness to arrest a fall. The incident occurred shortly after 7 a.m. on Jan. 2 at the site of a casino under construction. A spokesperson for the project said no information about the circumstances that led to the fall were available.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Reportedly, the worker fell down an elevator shaft from an unknown height. Although the severity of his injuries is unknown, authorities say the victim was alert at the time of his transport to a medical facility. This man is said to be one of over 1,000 employees who work at this construction site every day.</p> <p>The New York workers' compensation insurance program allows injured workers to pursue financial assistance when they are injured while working. Regardless of who was at fault, victims may file benefits claims for compensation to cover medical expenses related to the construction accidents that caused their injuries. This includes doctors, hospitals and therapist fees. An experienced attorney can help to navigate the claims process, which typically also covers lost wages -- the amount of which will be based on a percentage of the victim's average weekly wage.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>necn.com, "<a href="https://www.necn.com/news/new-england/Construction-Worker-Injured-in-Fall-Down-Elevator-Shaft-at-Wynn-Boston-Harbor-467670533.html" target="_blank">Construction Worker Injured in Fall Down Elevator Shaft at Wynn Boston Harbor</a>", Melissa Buja, Jan. 2, 2018</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--construction-workers-accidents-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Construction accidents involving scaffolds could be life-changing]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/11/construction-accidents-involving-scaffolds-could-be-life-changing.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244581</id>
  <published>2017-11-09T14:30:17Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:50Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Scaffolding can be life-threatening structures, and related safety regulations are strict. Many injuries in construction accidents result from collapsing scaffolds or falls from scaffolds due to safety violations. Victims of scaffolding accidents in New York may suffer long-term consequences. Along...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="constructionworkersaccidents" label="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Scaffolding can be life-threatening structures, and related safety regulations are strict. Many injuries in <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Construction-Accident-Injuries/">construction accidents</a> result from collapsing scaffolds or falls from scaffolds due to safety violations. Victims of scaffolding accidents in New York may suffer long-term consequences.</p> <p>Along with the Occupational Safety and Health Administration, state safety authorities work to improve safety and protect workers who are exposed to the hazards of scaffolds. Scaffolding must be carefully planned and designed to fit the requirements of the project for which it is required. Regulations show that the maximum intended load must be calculated, and the scaffold must be able to support four times that weight along with its own weight.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Furthermore, it must be fitted with toeboards, guardrails and midrails. Workers must be equipped with fall protection, and there must be secure anchor points for the lanyards that must arrest falls. The planks used for scaffolding must be of the appropriate standard and no boxes, barrels, loose concrete blocks, bricks or other unstable objects must be present on scaffolds. Also, the structures must be the required distance from any power lines.</p> <p>These are but some of the safety rules that may prevent scaffold-related construction accidents. Injured workers are entitled to file workers' compensation benefits claims with the state's insurance program. Many victims secure the services of an experienced New York workers' compensation attorney to assist them with the claims process and obtaining the maximum benefits. Along with medical expenses, benefits typically cover lost income, with the time period for coverage determined by the severity of the injury.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>consumersafety.org, "<a href="https://www.consumersafety.org/legal/scaffolding-accidents/" target="_blank">Scaffolding Accidents</a>", Lindsey Pasieka, Accessed on Nov. 3, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--construction-workers-accidents-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Construction accidents: Yet another life lost in New York]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/10/construction-accidents-yet-another-life-lost-in-new-york.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244577</id>
  <published>2017-10-10T16:18:16Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:49Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[The hazards on New York construction sites have given rise to many safety discussions in recent months. Despite all the talk about improved regulations, lives continue to be lost in construction accidents. One of the most recent fatalities occurred at...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="constructionworkersaccidents" label="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>The hazards on New York construction sites have given rise to many safety discussions in recent months. Despite all the talk about improved regulations, lives continue to be lost in <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Construction-Accident-Injuries/">construction accidents</a>. One of the most recent fatalities occurred at a site in Brewster.</p> <p>A report by the New York State Police indicates that an emergency call came in at approximately 7:30 a.m on a recent Wednesday. The caller was an employee who said a co-worker had fallen off a mobile scaffolding structure. Police and emergency services responded within moments to provide medical assistance.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>The victim had fallen from a height of ten feet, and authorities say he suffered serious chest and head injuries. Paramedics stabilized him and rushed him to a hospital. Reportedly, he remained conscious until they arrived at the hospital. Sadly, the victim then suffered cardiac arrest that caused his death. As with all fatal workplace accidents, the Occupational Safety and Health Administration will likely investigate the cause of this accident along with the safety compliance of the deceased worker's employer.</p> <p>Authorities often say that most construction accidents are preventable, which makes each fatality harder to accept. Some comfort may be provided by the workers' compensation system for surviving family members of workers who lose their lives in on-the-job accidents in New York. They can file claims for death benefits that will cover the costs of a funeral and burial. Furthermore, assistance may be provided by a wage-replacement package that can help with financial obligations and day-to-day living expenses in the difficult time after the loved one's death.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>Southeast, NY Patch, "<a href="https://patch.com/new-york/southeast/fatal-construction-accident-brewster" target="_blank">Fatal Construction Accident In Brewster</a>", Lanning Taliaferro, Oct. 4, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--construction-workers-accidents-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Noncompliance of safety rules can cause construction accidents]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/09/noncompliance-of-safety-rules-can-cause-construction-accidents.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244575</id>
  <published>2017-09-28T12:38:10Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:49Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Two deaths in one day -- only hours apart -- come at a time when there are calls for stricter safety regulations in the building industry. However, looking at the circumstances surrounding these construction accidents, it seems the calls should...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="constructionworkersaccidents" label="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Two deaths in one day -- only hours apart -- come at a time when there are calls for stricter safety regulations in the building industry. However, looking at the circumstances surrounding these <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Construction-Accident-Injuries/">construction accidents</a>, it seems the calls should be for more compliance with existing safety regulations. Two construction workers died in New York on a recent Thursday.</p> <p>The first accident happened when a 43-year-old worker lost his balance and fell from the 29th floor of a luxury condo under construction. The victim landed on the platform of a scaffolding structure that was erected above the sidewalk. According to firefighters who were at the scene, the man wore a fall harness but neglected to clip it into a secure anchor point.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Only hours later, emergency workers rushed to a scene of another construction accident. This time, two construction workers fell from a bucket lift which was at third-floor level. One employee, a 45-year-old man, did not survive the fall. Reportedly, witnesses said these workers also wore fall prevention equipment, but it appears their lanyards were also not secured.</p> <p>Even if New York building authorities enact stricter safety regulations, as long as compliance is not enforced, construction accidents will claim lives. Fortunately, the surviving family members can pursue financial relief through the workers' compensation insurance system. They can claim death benefits to cover the costs of end-of-life arrangements. Wage-replacement packages are typically also included in the benefits to assist with day-to-day living expenses in the difficult time after the deaths of loved ones. The lost income compensation will be based on the deceased worker's basic wages prior to the death.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>NBC New York, "<a href="http://www.nbcnewyork.com/news/local/Death-Luxury-Condo-Building-Manhattan-Emergency-446440413.html" target="_blank">2 Construction Workers Die in Separate Accidents Hours Apart in Manhattan: DOB</a>", Greg Cergol, Checkey Beckford, Sept. 21, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--construction-workers-accidents-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Will stricter regulations prevent construction accidents?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/08/will-stricter-regulations-prevent-construction-accidents.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244571</id>
  <published>2017-08-29T14:26:28Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:49Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Dozens of workers have died on construction sites in New York since the beginning of 2015. One of them was a 22-year-old worker who recently fell to his death down the shaft of an elevator in a condo tower under...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="constructionworkersaccidents" label="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Dozens of workers have died on construction sites in New York since the beginning of 2015. One of them was a 22-year-old worker who recently fell to his death down the shaft of an elevator in a condo tower under construction. Following the wave of <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Construction-Accident-Injuries/">construction accidents</a>, some unions have managed to persuade the City Council to demand significantly more training hours for all construction workers.</p> <p>Ten years ago, the mayor asked for a mandate that required 10 training hours for workers on projects that involved buildings of 10 stories of more. That was followed by the Buildings Department Commissioner requiring the presence of safety personnel on any project of four and more stories along with much steeper fines for violating contractors. Requiring 10 hours of training for all workers is also under consideration.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Safety authorities believe that stricter requirements for safety training can only benefit the industry. This is likely based on the Occupational Safety and Health Administration records of fines issued for inadequate safety training that formed part of the enforcement in 40 percent of construction worker fatalities that were investigated in New York. The fact that this is the most commonly cited safety violation raises considerable concern.</p> <p>Unfortunately, despite improved laws and safety requirements, construction accidents will likely continue to occur because some employers will always be tempted to prioritize profits over safety. Surviving family members of deceased victims of fatal construction injuries can pursue financial relief to help them cope with the high costs of funerals and burials, along with lost income. An experienced workers' compensation attorney is available to navigate any such claim on behalf of grieving family members.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>NY Daily News, "<a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/opinion/better-safety-blueprint-article-1.3443226" target="_blank">A better safety blueprint</a>", Aug. 28, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--construction-workers-accidents-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Lack of proper planning could cause fatal construction accidents]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/08/lack-of-proper-planning-could-cause-fatal-construction-accidents.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244568</id>
  <published>2017-08-10T11:10:52Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:49Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[When construction projects in New York are in the planning stage, developers should assess potential hazards and address those in advance. This particularly applies when projects include demolition, or for redevelopment projects. Being prepared may prevent fatal construction accidents like...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="constructionworkersaccidents" label="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>When construction projects in New York are in the planning stage, developers should assess potential hazards and address those in advance. This particularly applies when projects include demolition, or for redevelopment projects. Being prepared may prevent fatal <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Construction-Accident-Injuries/">construction accidents</a> like the one that happened in Poughkeepsie on a recent Thursday.</p> <p>Investigators of the Occupational Safety and Health Administration will be examining the circumstances of the tragedy to determine whether this death could have been prevented by following safety regulations. This project is the redevelopment of a lumber yard into a commercial complex that will also include some apartments. Reportedly, the incident happened soon after a massive load of soil was delivered to the site.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>The fire chief says an existing retaining wall supported the bulk of this load of soil. Unfortunately, it failed, and the wall collapsed onto two construction workers who were behind it. One man was fortunate enough to escape being trapped, but he had to be taken to a hospital for treatment of a broken hand and a suspected fractured leg. Sadly, the wall fell directly onto one worker, killing him before he could be extricated.</p> <p>When such construction accidents occur, it typically leaves injured workers with piles of medical bills and a shortage of cash. Families of deceased workers have to cope with unanticipated expenses related to end-of-life arrangements, often leaving them with financial problems. This is where the New York workers' compensation program comes in. Benefits are available for workers and grieved family members to cover medical expenses, funeral and burial costs and a portion of lost wages.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>poughkeepsiejournal.com, "<a href="http://www.poughkeepsiejournal.com/story/news/2017/08/09/dutton-accident-investigation/552257001/" target="_blank">Dutton: Investigation of the fatal lumberyard accident could take 6 months, officials say</a>", Abbott Brant., Aug. 9, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--construction-workers-accidents-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Serious injuries caused when wall collapses at construction site]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/07/serious-injuries-caused-when-wall-collapses-at-construction-site.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244563</id>
  <published>2017-07-06T12:35:27Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:48Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[The construction industry in New York and elsewhere continue to report preventable on-the-job accidents. The Occupational Safety and Health Administration is part of an investigation&nbsp;into an incident that caused serious injuries to a construction worker. The site where the accident...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="constructionworkersaccidents" label="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>The construction industry in New York and elsewhere continue to report preventable on-the-job accidents. The Occupational Safety and Health Administration is part of an investigation&nbsp;into an incident that caused <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Construction-Accident-Injuries/">serious injuries</a> to a construction worker. The site where the accident occurred is&nbsp;a residential home under construction in a neighboring state.</p> <p>According to authorities, the injured victim -- a 35-year-old man -- was airlifted from the scene in serious condition, though he is expected to survive. Reportedly, the worker's injuries were caused when a cement foundation wall collapsed at approximately 10:30 on a recent Monday morning. The worker was trapped under the wall.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Rescuers rushed to the construction site, but they were unable to extricate the worker right away because an excavator was teetering dangerously close to the injured worker. An excavator from another construction site was used to secure the machine so that the rescue workers could remove the man&nbsp;from under the collapsed wall. Reportedly, he suffered crushing injuries to the lower parts of his legs.</p> <p>The circumstances that caused the wall to collapse are still under investigation, and it is not yet known whether any safety violations were involved. However, that should not prevent the worker who suffered serious injuries from pursuing workers' compensation benefits to cover medical expenses and lost income. If any injuries caused permanent damage to the employee's legs, the insurance program will likely include additional benefits. With the support and guidance of an experienced New York workers' comp attorney, the administrative and legal proceedings of such a claim may be less complicated, and maximum compensation may be obtained.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>oshatoday.com, "<a href="http://www.oshatoday.com/news-digest-item/14164/" target="_blank">Federal agency to investigate Coventry construction accident</a>", Lynn Arditi, June 27, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--construction-workers-accidents-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Roof collapse lead to construction worker's serious injuries]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/06/roof-collapse-lead-to-construction-workers-serious-injuries.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244562</id>
  <published>2017-06-26T19:14:56Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:48Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[The New York Department of Buildings stopped work at a Queens residential home construction site on a recent Wednesday after a construction accident occurred there on the previous day. Building materials weighing thousands of pounds fell onto three workers when...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="constructionworkersaccidents" label="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>The New York Department of Buildings stopped work at a Queens residential home construction site on a recent Wednesday after a construction accident occurred there on the previous day. Building materials weighing thousands of pounds fell onto three workers when the building's roof collapsed, causing <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Construction-Accident-Injuries/">serious injuries</a> to one. The workers were members of a construction crew who were adding another story to an existing two-story residence.</p> <p>Authorities say a crane loaded construction materials onto the building's roof when they suspect the massive weight caused the partial roof collapse. Three workers were in the area when the rubble came crashing through the roof. One worker, age 37, managed to escape the building without being trapped while a 40-year-old employee was briefly trapped.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>A third worker, age 28, was less fortunate and remained trapped for almost two hours while rescuers worked on extricating him. Reportedly, they had to dig themselves into the rubble to reach the victim. He was then removed via a trench that they had to excavate to secure his rescue. Paramedics rushed the three critically injured victims to a hospital. The Occupational Safety and Health Administration has apparently joined the investigation into this construction accident.</p> <p>Whenever a New York worker suffers serious injuries and reports it to the employer promptly, he or she can file a workers' compensation benefits claim. While it is possible to navigate such a claim without legal counsel, the skills of an experienced workers' compensation attorney can ease the process. A lawyer can take care of the administrative and legal proceedings while the injured victim can focus of recuperating.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>dnainfo.com, "<a href="https://www.dnainfo.com/new-york/20170621/astoria/31-25-28th-road-construction-crash-violations-department-of-buildings" target="_blank">City Halts Work on Construction Site Where 3 Workers Were Injured</a>", Jeanmarie Evelly, June 21, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--construction-workers-accidents-->
</entry>

</feed>