<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/includes/blog-feed/atom.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Workplace Accidents Archives | Newburgh New York Workers' Compensation Law Blog]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/workplace-accidents-1/" />
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/workplace-accidents-1/atom.xml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2013-03-21:/blog/81520</id>
  <updated>2018-05-31T13:01:58Z</updated>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[This is the Workplace Accidents archive for Newburgh New York Workers' Compensation Law Blog.]]></subtitle>
  <generator uri="http://www.sixapart.com/movabletype/">Movable Type Enterprise</generator>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Electrical accident on the job hospitalizes Midtown hotel worker]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/05/electrical-accident-on-the-job-hospitalizes-midtown-hotel-worker.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3289684</id>
  <published>2018-05-31T13:02:58Z</published>
  <updated>2018-05-31T13:01:58Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[In New York, work accidents can happen in any kind of job whether it is work that is viewed as physical and dangerous or sedentary and safe. The aftermath of these accidents is universal regardless of the kind of...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceaccidents" label="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>In New York, work accidents can happen in any kind of job whether it is work that is viewed as physical and dangerous or sedentary and safe. The aftermath of these accidents is universal regardless of the kind of job it is. People who are injured after an accident on the job can be confronted with lost time at work, medical expenses and long-term problems as a result. Even jobs not thought to be significantly risky can have a safety hazard, an unsafe working environment or a mistake on the part of another worker or the workplace that causes the injuries. To ensure that the worker is compensated for all that was lost, a lawsuit is often necessary.</p> <p>A worker was <a href="https://patch.com/new-york/midtown-nyc/worker-injured-midtowns-roosevelt-hotel-fdny-says" target="_blank">seriously injured</a> in an electrical accident at a hotel in Midtown Manhattan after what was termed an "electrical incident." It did not reach the level of being considered an explosion. The Fire Department was called after it happened. The worker was found injured and transported to the hospital for treatment. He was in serious, but stable condition. It has not yet been reported what the cause of the accident was.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>People who are injured on the job should be cognizant of their rights to receive workers' compensation and everything that goes along with that. This is meant to pay for medical expenses, provide for lost wages and perhaps more. However, there are times when it can be difficult to get the benefits the worker believes he or she is supposed to get. It could be necessary to appeal a case if it is initially denied. Any injury can cause lifelong problems, pain and the inability to work the same job as before if the worker is able to work at all. Being protected by a legal professional is essential to making certain the maximum benefits are received.</p> <p>In this incident, a worker was injured in an electrical accident. He was said to have suffered serious injuries and hospitalized. The investigation into the case was continuing to determine what happened. The worker who was hurt should remember the importance of legal help in receiving compensation after a <a href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workplace-Accidents/">workplace accident</a> and contact a lawyer immediately.</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-accidents-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Fatal workplace accident claims MTA worker's life]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/04/fatal-workplace-accident-claims-mta-workers-life-1.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3244602</id>
  <published>2018-04-03T05:35:44Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:52Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[It was a horrific start to a workday when a group of MTA workers in New York witnessed one of their colleagues fall to his death. This workplace accident happened shortly before 5 a.m. on a recent Tuesday at a...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceaccidents" label="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>It was a horrific start to a workday when a group of MTA workers in New York witnessed one of their colleagues fall to his death. This <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workplace-Accidents/">workplace accident</a> happened shortly before 5 a.m. on a recent Tuesday at a subway station in East Harlem. Reportedly, the 23-year-old man had only been in this job for six months before he lost his life.</p> <p>Although investigators will likely seek answers to the cause of the incident, initial indications are that the worker leaned against&nbsp;a wooden railing that gave way. He fell nine feet to the railway tracks below and landed head first. Witnesses say the worker was still alive when he was pulled onto the platform.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Emergency workers performed CPR and did what they could to save the worker's life. Sadly, he succumbed to his injuries within about an hour. The worker's father noted that his son weighed about 270 pounds, and his height was six-foot-three -- suggesting that the protective railing might not have been strong enough to withstand his weight.</p> <p>Losing a loved one in a workplace accident is naturally a traumatic experience, and surviving family members typically have to cope with the unanticipated financial consequences at this difficult time. It might be comforting to know that the New York workers' compensation insurance program offers survivors' benefits to a deceased worker's dependents. The benefits typically cover the expenses related to end-of-life arrangements, along with a financial package to make up for lost wages -- based on the deceased worker's average weekly wage before death.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>New York Daily News, "<a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/new-york/manhattan/mta-worker-takes-fatal-fall-subway-tracks-railing-breaks-article-1.3885503" target="_blank">MTA worker takes fatal fall on East Harlem subway tracks when protective railing breaks</a>", Chelsia Rose, Marcius Dan Rivoli, Graham Rayman, March 20, 2018</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-accidents-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Fatal workplace accident claims MTA worker's life]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/04/fatal-workplace-accident-claims-mta-workers-life.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3244601</id>
  <published>2018-04-03T05:35:43Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:52Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[It was a horrific start to a workday when a group of MTA workers in New York witnessed one of their colleagues fall to his death. This workplace accident happened shortly before 5 a.m. on a recent Tuesday at a...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceaccidents" label="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>It was a horrific start to a workday when a group of MTA workers in New York witnessed one of their colleagues fall to his death. This <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workplace-Accidents/">workplace accident</a> happened shortly before 5 a.m. on a recent Tuesday at a subway station in East Harlem. Reportedly, the 23-year-old man had only been in this job for six months before he lost his life.</p> <p>Although investigators will likely seek answers to the cause of the incident, initial indications are that the worker leaned against&nbsp;a wooden railing that gave way. He fell nine feet to the railway tracks below and landed head first. Witnesses say the worker was still alive when he was pulled onto the platform.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Emergency workers performed CPR and did what they could to save the worker's life. Sadly, he succumbed to his injuries within about an hour. The worker's father noted that his son weighed about 270 pounds, and his height was six-foot-three -- suggesting that the protective railing might not have been strong enough to withstand his weight.</p> <p>Losing a loved one in a workplace accident is naturally a traumatic experience, and surviving family members typically have to cope with the unanticipated financial consequences at this difficult time. It might be comforting to know that the New York workers' compensation insurance program offers survivors' benefits to a deceased worker's dependents. The benefits typically cover the expenses related to end-of-life arrangements, along with a financial package to make up for lost wages -- based on the deceased worker's average weekly wage before death.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>New York Daily News, "<a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/new-york/manhattan/mta-worker-takes-fatal-fall-subway-tracks-railing-breaks-article-1.3885503" target="_blank">MTA worker takes fatal fall on East Harlem subway tracks when protective railing breaks</a>", Chelsia Rose, Marcius Dan Rivoli, Graham Rayman, March 20, 2018</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-accidents-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Workplace accident at recycling plant kills 26-year-old father]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/02/workplace-accident-at-recycling-plant-kills-26-year-old-father.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3244594</id>
  <published>2018-02-07T16:45:37Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:51Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[A tragic incident in another state underscores the potential dangers posed for workers in recycling plants in New York and elsewhere. A workplace accident resulted in the death of a 26-year-old father of a toddler in January. It's under investigation...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceaccidents" label="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>A tragic incident in another state underscores the potential dangers posed for workers in recycling plants in New York and elsewhere. A <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workplace-Accidents/">workplace accident</a> resulted in the death of a 26-year-old father of a toddler in January. It's under investigation by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration. The office of the county sheriff also launched a separate inquiry.</p> <p>It appears that nobody witnessed the incident that caused this young man's death. When his co-workers reported that he was missing, it was determined that he had fallen into a machine that shreds tires. It is believed that he got caught and pulled into the shredder. However, these are simply&nbsp;assumptions at this stage, and investigators delve into the details and also assess the level of safety compliance practiced at this plant.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>The surviving family members have announced their intention to file a lawsuit against the company. They believe that their loved one's death was caused by gross negligence. Their legal representative has launched an independent investigation.</p> <p>In New York, injured workers or the surviving family members of a deceased victim of a workplace accident are typically barred from filing claims against employers, unless there is evidence of gross negligence. under any circumstances, they can pursue financial relief through the workers' compensation insurance system -- regardless of who was at fault. However, if there is proof of egregious conduct by the company, the employer may face claims for financial damages that go beyond what are likely available through the workers' compensation system. Establishing gross negligence in such lawsuits is typically challenging, and the help of an experienced attorney may be necessary.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>New York Daily News, "<a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/news/national/young-father-dies-accidentally-falling-tire-shredder-article-1.3790292" target="_blank">Young father dies after accidentally falling into tire shredder at recycling plant</a>", Caitlyn Hitt, Jan. 31, 2018</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-accidents-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Workplace accident claims life of New York elevator technician]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/01/workplace-accident-claims-life-of-new-york-elevator-technician.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3244593</id>
  <published>2018-01-28T18:02:36Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:51Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Construction company owners and contractors are expected to protect their employees from harm. They must provide construction sites that are free of known hazards, and provide the necessary personal protective equipment for each worker according to the jobs with which...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceaccidents" label="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Construction company owners and contractors are expected to protect their employees from harm. They must provide construction sites that are free of known hazards, and provide the necessary personal protective equipment for each worker according to the jobs with which they are tasked. The New York City Department of Buildings has ordered an investigation into a recent fatal <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workplace-Accidents/">workplace accident</a> at a Flatiron construction site.</p> <p>According to an incident report by emergency workers who responded to the call, a 33-year-old elevator technician who was part of a construction crew fell nine floors to his death. They say the man fell down an elevator shaft on a recent Tuesday shortly before 9 a.m. DOB inspectors will investigate the circumstances that led to the tragedy.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Reportedly, authorities suspect that workers were exposed to dangerous site conditions. They added that the contractor at this building site had received approximately 20 citations for safety violations during the past year. Included were exposure to tripping hazards as well as 6-foot holes without guardrails.</p> <p>It is not known whether the worker who lost his life was wearing fall protection at the time of the incident. Regardless of the outcome of the inquiry into this tragic workplace accident, the surviving family members may seek financial relief through the New York workers' compensation insurance program. An attorney who is experienced in navigating death benefits claims can handle the complicated legal and administrative steps required to secure compensation for end-of-life expenses and wage replacement. The financial package will likely include a percentage of the deceased worker's average weekly wage to be paid over a predetermined period for assistance with day-to-day living expenses.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>Gramercy, NY Patch, "<a href="https://patch.com/new-york/gramercy-murray-hill/worker-falls-9-stories-down-flatiron-elevator-shaft-police" target="_blank">Worker Falls 9 Stories Down Flatiron Elevator Shaft: Police</a>", Kathleen Culliton, Jan. 23, 2018</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-accidents-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Every fatal work injury in New York is one too many]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/12/every-fatal-work-injury-in-new-york-is-one-too-many.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244588</id>
  <published>2017-12-26T18:40:54Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:50Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[The latest report of occupational injuries show that the number of workplace fatalities in New York was 15 percent higher in 2016 than in 2015. Every work injury that happens is one too many -- fatal or nonfatal. Data was...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceaccidents" label="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>The latest report of occupational injuries show that the number of workplace fatalities in New York was 15 percent higher in 2016 than in 2015. Every <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workplace-Accidents/">work injury</a> that happens is one too many -- fatal or nonfatal. Data was broken down into categories to give a clearer picture of the types of injuries that caused fatalities to assist in safety agencies to devise improved safety regulations.</p> <p>The analysis shows that 30 percent of 2016 workplace fatalities occurred in transportation accidents. Although that number is slightly lower than transportation deaths in 2015, other categories such as slips, trips and falls show significant increases. The total number of New York workers who died in 2016 was 272.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Authorities are particularly concerned about the opioid crisis that is growing and affecting more and more members of the workforce. In collaboration with the U.S. Department of Labor and stakeholders in the private sector, the Occupational Safety and Health Administration aims to devise methods to address this problem. OSHA endeavors to find innovative and groundbreaking ways to eliminate this life-threatening crisis.</p> <p>Any family who has to cope with the loss of a loved one due to&nbsp;a fatal work injury may be overwhelmed with the financial consequences of such a tragedy. Not only must they deal with the costs of end-of-life arrangements but also the loss of income from the deceased worker. The surviving family members may find comfort in learning that an experienced New York workers' compensation attorney can navigate a claim for death benefits to cover those expenses and losses on their behalf.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>timesunion.com, "<a href="http://www.timesunion.com/business/article/Number-of-fatal-work-injuries-in-NY-rises-12441908.php" target="_blank">Number of fatal work injuries in NY rises</a>", Madison Iszler, Dec. 19, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-accidents-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Adequate precautions may prevent wastewater plant work injury]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/12/adequate-precautions-may-prevent-wastewater-plant-work-injury.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244587</id>
  <published>2017-12-18T19:54:55Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:50Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Following up on our blog post about a fatality at a New York wastewater plant from Dec. 12 ("Workplace accident kills wastewater plant worker"), emphasizing the hazards present at these facilities may help prevent more such tragedies. The most important...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceaccidents" label="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Following up on our blog post about a fatality at a New York wastewater plant from Dec. 12 ("Workplace accident kills wastewater plant worker"), emphasizing the hazards present at these facilities may help prevent more such tragedies. The most important part of any company's quest to avoid fatalities is proper safety training. Such training must inform every employee of potential hazards and how to protect him or herself from suffering a <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workplace-Accidents/">work injury</a>.</p> <p>Wastewater plants have unique safety hazards and demanding conditions that require equipment and machinery that are properly maintained at all times. Any incident of equipment failure can have devastating consequences. Maintenance includes the appropriate labeling to indicate outlet and intake pipes along with any pieces of equipment that pose electric flash risks. Wearing the necessary protective gear and safety devices to de-energize equipment during maintenance procedures are essential precautions.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Elevated catwalks, often high above open pits and vats, pose different threats that make non-slip footwear and walking surfaces essential. Further protection in the form of harnesses that can arrest falls could prevent workers landing in the wastewater pits. Devices to assist the rescue must be readily available, and workers must know how to quickly retrieve any worker who falls into a vat. Furthermore, confined spaces also pose significant hazards and should be cordoned off as necessary.</p> <p>Wastewater plant workers in New York will always be vulnerable, and any victim of a work injury might be eligible for workers' compensation insurance benefits. This insurance program typically covers medical expenses and lost wages. However, prompt reporting of the incident to the employer is important, and there is also a time limit to the filing of benefits claims. Any injured worker has the right to seek the help of an experienced workers' compensation attorney to provide the necessary guidance and support with the navigation of a benefits claim.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>reliableplant.com, "<a href="http://www.reliableplant.com/Read/29966/wastewater-treatment-plants" target="_blank">Important Safety Tips for Wastewater Treatment Plants</a>", Jeff Maree, Dec. 15, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-accidents-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Workplace accident kills wastewater plant worker]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/12/workplace-accident-kills-wastewater-plant-worker.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244586</id>
  <published>2017-12-12T18:01:55Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:50Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[The Public Employee Safety and Health (PESH), which is the New York State's version of the federal safety agency, the Occupational Safety and Health Administration, is collaborating with police detectives in an investigation into the recent death of a worker....]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceaccidents" label="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>The Public Employee Safety and Health (PESH), which is the New York State's version of the federal safety agency, the Occupational Safety and Health Administration, is collaborating with police detectives in an investigation into the recent death of a worker. The incident, which police say was a <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workplace-Accidents/">workplace accident</a>, happened on Nov. 20. Emergency services say they received a 911 call reporting an incident in Watertown.</p> <p>A report indicates that a process worker suffered critical injuries under undisclosed circumstances at the wastewater treatment plant. Emergency workers responded to the work site, and the injured employee was rushed to a medical center by ambulance. Sadly, he did not survive, and authorities say he died at the hospital. Reportedly, the deceased worker was a 54-year-old man, born and bred in Watertown, who worked for the New York Upstate wastewater plant for the past 10 years.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>No details were reported about the circumstances that led to the incident that claimed this employee's life. Safety inspectors will likely determine what led to the accident. They will also focus on the general compliance with safety regulations at the facility and determine whether a safety violation gave rise to this tragedy.</p> <p>Following any fatal workplace accident in New York, the surviving family members may be entitled to seek financial assistance with the unanticipated expenses that typically follow such a sad incident. Eligible family members may file death benefits claims with the workers' compensation insurance program for the state. An attorney who is skilled in the navigation of such claims may provide valuable guidance and support in obtaining benefits to cover the costs of a funeral and burial along with a portion of lost income.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>wateronline.com, "<a href="https://www.wateronline.com/doc/worker-dies-at-wastewater-plant-in-new-york-0001" target="_blank">Worker Dies At Wastewater Plant In New York</a>", Sara Jerome, Dec. 5, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-accidents-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Employee dies in workplace accident at New York propane company]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/12/employee-dies-in-workplace-accident-at-new-york-propane-company.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244585</id>
  <published>2017-12-05T21:54:49Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:50Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[The reconstruction unit and the motor carrier unit of the New York State Police, along with the Occupational Safety and Health Administration recently responded after receiving an emergency call. The caller reported a workplace accident that took place at a...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceaccidents" label="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>The reconstruction unit and the motor carrier unit of the New York State Police, along with the Occupational Safety and Health Administration recently responded after receiving an emergency call. The caller reported a <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workplace-Accidents/">workplace accident</a> that took place at a propane company in Calverton. Paramedics also rushed to the scene.</p> <p>An incident report that was prepared by the local police indicates that the accident occurred shortly after 1 p.m. on a recent Tuesday. Reportedly, a 43-year-old employee who was the operator of a tank truck that belongs to the propane company accidentally knocked down a co-worker. Paramedics rendered aid to the 35-year-old employee who was struck.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Sadly, they could not save his life, and the victim's death was declared at the accident scene. The multi-agency investigation is ongoing. Authorities say no charges were filed against the truck driver, and police do not suspect any criminal intent in his actions.</p> <p>Whenever such a tragic workplace accident occurs, it is naturally traumatic for the surviving family members of the deceased worker. While dealing with their grief, they will also face the unanticipated financial consequences of their loved one's death. The workers' compensation insurance system is there to provide financial relief, and a&nbsp;New York attorney who is experienced in the navigation of benefits claims can provide guidance and support to obtain compensation for the expenses of a funeral and burial. Furthermore, he or she can work on securing survivors' benefits, which will cover a portion of lost wages to help covered dependents cope with day-to-day living expenses.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>North Fork, NY Patch, "<a href="https://patch.com/new-york/northfork/man-dies-after-being-struck-propane-truck-cops" target="_blank">Man Dies After Being Struck By Propane Truck</a>", Lisa Finn, Nov. 28, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-accidents-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Workplace accident at cosmetics factory kills 1 injures many]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/11/workplace-accident-at-cosmetics-factory-kills-1-injures-many.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244584</id>
  <published>2017-11-29T09:57:15Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:50Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[New York Gov. Andrew M. Cuomo recently initiated an investigation in which multiple agencies will take part to determine various aspects of a devastating explosion that took place at a cosmetics manufacturing plant in the town of New Windsor. Reportedly,...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceaccidents" label="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>New York Gov. Andrew M. Cuomo recently initiated an investigation in which multiple agencies will take part to determine various aspects of a devastating explosion that took place at a cosmetics manufacturing plant in the town of New Windsor. Reportedly, the <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workplace-Accidents/">workplace accident</a> occurred shortly after 10 a.m. on Nov. 20. Hazmat teams and firefighters rushed to the scene, and a second explosion rocked the facility while rescue workers were inside the burning building.</p> <p>Authorities say one employee was killed while between 25 and 30 others were injured. During the second explosion, seven firefighters suffered injuries, two of whom had to be rushed to a burn unit. According to the Occupational Safety and Health Administration, this company has been the subject of three investigations in 2012, 2013 and 2016. All those inquiries involved violations related to mismanagement of hazardous energy and flammable liquids, among other safety violations.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Along with OSHA, safety and health experts of the New York State Department of Labor will investigate the possibility of asbestos presence and boiler malfunctions. Additionally, the Department of State Division of Building Standards and Codes will examine code compliance. Facility operations, hazardous waste management and chemical storage will be inspected by the Department of Environmental Conservation.</p> <p>The investigations into this workplace accident could take months to complete, but in the meantime, the injured employees may need financial assistance to cover medical expenses and lost wages. Similarly, the surviving family members of the deceased worker will likely struggle to cope with the unanticipated costs of a funeral and burial. Fortunately, the New York workers' compensation insurance program aims to assist those in similar situations and will provide benefits to cover those expenses along with a portion of lost wages.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>ehstoday.com, "<a href="http://www.ehstoday.com/safety/explosion-kills-worker-injures-dozens-ny-cosmetics-company" target="_blank">Explosion Kills Worker, Injures Dozens at NY Cosmetics Company</a>", Sandy Smith, Nov. 21, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-accidents-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Witness: No precautions taken before fatal workplace accident]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/10/witness-no-precautions-taken-before-fatal-workplace-accident.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244579</id>
  <published>2017-10-23T20:54:17Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:50Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[New York construction workers frequently put their lives on the line when they have to work in dangerous circumstances. They often work without the necessary personal protective equipment. Both the New York City Department of Buildings and the Occupational Safety...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceaccidents" label="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>New York construction workers frequently put their lives on the line when they have to work in dangerous circumstances. They often work without the necessary personal protective equipment. Both the New York City Department of Buildings and the Occupational Safety and Health Administration have opened investigations into a deadly <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workplace-Accidents/">workplace accident</a> that claimed the life of a 60-year-old man.</p> <p>According to a police report, the incident occurred shortly before noon at a two-story home in Queens on a recent Thursday. A retired construction worker who happens to live across the street from where the man was working says he watched the worker yanking on anchors that were installed on the roof, to which they were going to secure solar panels. He was testing them for strength when something happened to propel him off the roof.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>The witness says that although there were various types of safety precautions that could have been taken to prevent this man's death, none of them seemed to have been made. He says the worker was not equipped with a fall harness, and there was no safe anchor point on the roof. Reportedly, paramedics rushed the roof worker to a hospital, but he did not survive his injuries.</p> <p>Regardless of the findings of the investigators, the family of a deceased victim of a workplace accident may pursue financial relief to help with the unanticipated economic consequences of such a tragedy. The New York workers' compensation insurance program offers death benefits to surviving family members. The expenses related to end-of-life arrangements are typically covered along with a financial package to make up for lost wages.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>New York Daily News, "<a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/new-york/queens/worker-dead-falling-roof-two-story-queens-house-article-1.3575395" target="_blank">Worker dead after falling from roof of two-story Queens house</a>", Rocco Parascandola, Ellen Moynihan, John Annese, Oct. 19, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-accidents-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Construction zone worker succumbs to fatal work injury]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/09/construction-zone-worker-succumbs-to-fatal-work-injury.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244572</id>
  <published>2017-09-06T11:02:11Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:49Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[New York workers who spend their days making the highways safer for road users put their lives on the line every day. Not only are they threatened by the equipment used in road construction but also by negligent drivers who...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceaccidents" label="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>New York workers who spend their days making the highways safer for road users put their lives on the line every day. Not only are they threatened by the equipment used in road construction but also by negligent drivers who fail to take due care when they travel through construction zones. On Aug. 23, a construction zone worker succumbed to a <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workplace-Accidents/">work injury</a> that resulted from an accident on Aug. 14.</p> <p>According to a report of the accident, the 55-year-old construction zone worker was part of a crew working on Route 12. She was tasked with directing traffic passing through the construction zone. While holding up a sign to stop or slow down northbound traffic, she was struck by a box truck.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Reportedly, the 19-year-old truck driver suffered no injuries, but the construction worker was critically injured. She was rushed to a hospital in the area, but the severity of her injuries caused her death within 10 days. No citations or charges were filed against the box truck driver at the time of the accident.</p> <p>While the New York workers' compensation insurance system offers financial support in the form of death benefits to the surviving family members of any employee who suffers a fatal work injury, they will only receive coverage for funeral and burial costs along with a percentage of lost income. However, if the death was caused by a third party, they can also pursue a civil wrongful death claim to recover additional damages by suing that driver and any separate owner of the vehicle. An experienced workers' compensation attorney can assist with the navigation of both the claims.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>NBC New York, "<a href="http://www.nbcnewyork.com/news/local/Construction-Worker-Gloria-Taylor-Hit-Box-Truck-Directing-Traffic-Coram-Work-Site-Dies-Cops-441592123.html" target="_blank">Construction Worker Hit by Truck While Directing Traffic at Work Site Dies: Cops</a>", Aug. 24, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-accidents-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Workplace accident kills window washer when fall protection fails]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/08/workplace-accident-kills-window-washer-when-fall-protection-fails.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244569</id>
  <published>2017-08-16T13:02:31Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:49Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Window washers in New York put their lives on the line every day. The biggest hazard they face is indeed falling, and one would expect the employer of any window washer to be aware of the importance of, not only...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceaccidents" label="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Window washers in New York put their lives on the line every day. The biggest hazard they face is indeed falling, and one would expect the employer of any window washer to be aware of the importance of, not only providing fall protection but ensuring that it is always in mint condition and replaced when it starts showing wear and tear. A fatal <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workplace-Accidents/">workplace accident</a> that involves a malfunctioning fall harness should not happen.</p> <p>Sadly, it did happen. On a recent Monday, shortly before 10:30 a.m., a 56-year-old window washer fell to his death. Reportedly, he was on a raised platform, busy cleaning the windows of the 12th story of a building in Midtown when his fall harness apparently malfunctioned. The interior courtyard landing on the building's 6th floor broke his fall, but could not save his life.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Emergency workers performed CPR in an attempt to keep him alive, while they rushed him to the hospital. Sadly, he succumbed to his injuries at the medical center. The victim's brother said the co-worker who was also on the platform called him immediately after the fatal fall.</p> <p>Authorities will likely investigate the employer's compliance with safety regulations to determine the cause of the malfunction of the personal protective equipment in this workplace accident. However, nothing could ease the pain of the deceased worker's surviving family members. They will be entitled to claim death benefits from the New York workers' compensation insurance program that may bring relief of the financial burden brought about by the tragic death of their loved one.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>New York Post, "<a href="http://nypost.com/2017/08/07/window-washer-dead-after-falling-from-platform/" target="_blank">Window washer dead after falling from platform</a>", Jaclyn Weiner, Daniel Prendergast, Aug. 7, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-accidents-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[OSHA says tree trimmer's fatal workplace accident was preventable]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/05/osha-says-tree-trimmers-fatal-workplace-accident-was-preventable.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244557</id>
  <published>2017-05-23T15:18:13Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:47Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Tree service companies are very active at this time of the year, and owners of these enterprises are responsible for the health and safety of the employees. Tree trimming is an occupation filled with hazards -- not only for those...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceaccidents" label="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Tree service companies are very active at this time of the year, and owners of these enterprises are responsible for the health and safety of the employees. Tree trimming is an occupation filled with hazards -- not only for those trimming the trees at dangerous heights but also the workers at ground level. A federal safety agency recently found a New York company responsible for a tree trimmer's death in a <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workplace-Accidents/">workplace accident</a> in a neighboring state last October.</p> <p>According to the Occupational Safety and Health Administration, a father of two was trimming a tree at a townhouse complex when a large tree limb struck him. Emergency personnel took the man who had suffered critical head and upper body injuries to a hospital after administering first aid. Sadly, his death was pronounced upon arrival at the medical facility.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>OSHA recently completed an investigation and fined the deceased man's employer over $25,000. Investigators say the equipment that is used to lower the limbs safely to the ground lacked sufficient rope wrap attachments, leaving the workers without proper control when the limb was lowered. This was when the worker was struck, causing fatal injuries.</p> <p>A New York family who has to cope with the unexpected loss of loved one in a fatal workplace accident may pursue financial assistance with the financial consequences of such a tragedy. An experienced workers' compensation attorney can help with the navigation of death benefits claims. Not only do survivors' benefits include coverage of the costs related to end-of-life arrangements but also a wage-replacement package to help with daily living expenses.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>Ramsey, NJ Patch, "<a href="https://patch.com/new-jersey/ramsey-nj/osha-fines-tree-service-company-25k-mans-ramsey-death" target="_blank">OSHA Fines Tree Service Company $25K For Man's Ramsey Death</a>", Daniel Hubbard, May 15, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-accidents-1-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[For cell tower workers, work injury is par for the course]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2017/05/for-cell-tower-workers-work-injury-is-par-for-the-course.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2017:/blog//81520.3244554</id>
  <published>2017-05-03T19:21:53Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:47Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[A former cell tower worker asked people&nbsp;in New York and other states to think of the men and women who see to it that they have constant cell phone contact with whomever they want, whenever they want. Their occupation has...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceaccidents" label="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>A former cell tower worker asked people&nbsp;in New York and other states to think of the men and women who see to it that they have constant cell phone contact with whomever they want, whenever they want. Their occupation has been dubbed the most dangerous job in the country -- one in which every worker&nbsp;could potentially&nbsp;suffer a <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workplace-Accidents/">work injury</a>&nbsp;that could be fatal. The 55-year-old is the author of a book describing the life-threatening conditions to which approximately 15,000 workers are exposed as they work on maintaining 215,000 cell phone towers at heights of up to 2,000 feet every day.</p> <p>He says these workers have to deal with gale-force winds, rain, snow and subzero temperatures while putting their lives on the line. He gives graphic descriptions of a co-worker's decapitation by a cable and says others have died after falling off towers and from baskets that were attached to cranes. Some lost their lives after being struck by falling debris, being electrocuted or struck by lightning.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>The man said seven tower workers lost their lives in 2016. However, he also stated that almost all deaths in this job are the result of faulty equipment or by workers misusing the equipment that is meant to keep them safe. Workers tend to get accustomed to the dangers, and that leads to them taking shortcuts -- often with fatal consequences.</p> <p>Cell tower workers in New York who have suffered any type of work injury -- or witnessed&nbsp;the traumatic death of a co-worker -- are entitled to seek the financial support offered by the workers' compensation insurance system. Victims of work-related injuries or post-traumatic stress may find that the most logical step to obtain benefits is to secure the services of an experienced workers' compensation attorney. He or she can advocate for the victim while navigating the complexities of the claims procedures.</p><p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>New York Post, "<a href="http://nypost.com/2017/04/22/keeping-up-your-cellphone-service-has-killed-35-people/" target="_blank">Keeping up your cellphone service has killed 35 people</a>", Michael Kaplan, April 22, 2017</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--workplace-accidents-1-->
</entry>

</feed>