<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/includes/blog-feed/atom.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Fatal Accidents Archives | Newburgh New York Workers' Compensation Law Blog]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/fatal-accidents/" />
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/fatal-accidents/atom.xml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2013-03-21:/blog/81520</id>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:25Z</updated>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[This is the Fatal Accidents archive for Newburgh New York Workers' Compensation Law Blog.]]></subtitle>
  <generator uri="http://www.sixapart.com/movabletype/">Movable Type Enterprise</generator>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Workplace accident kills man in Rockland County]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2012/12/workplace-accident-kills-man-in-rockland-county.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2012:/blog//81520.3244331</id>
  <published>2012-12-05T15:44:20Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:25Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Rockland County, just northwest of Manhattan, is bordered by the Tappan Zee and boasts slightly more than 315,000 in population according to the last census. It was here that a man from Bogotá earned his nursing degree recently and dreamed...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Fatal Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="fatalaccidents" label="Fatal Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="thirdpartyclaims" label="Third-Party Claims" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="workerscompdeathbenefits" label="Workers' Comp Death Benefits" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Rockland County, just northwest of Manhattan, is bordered by the Tappan Zee and boasts slightly more than 315,000 in population according to the last census. It was here that a man from Bogotá earned his nursing degree recently and dreamed of working in that profession. It is also here that the man from Bogotá was killed in an industrial accident.</p> <p>The 59-year-old nursing graduate was working at a temporary job loading pallets of computer equipment that came from an office building in the Pearl River section of Orangetown, New York. As he was loading and unloading, a 2,500 pound load of equipment on a pallet fell and crushed the 59-year-old. He died as a result of his crush injuries.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>As one might expect when there is a fatal accident, the Occupational Safety and Health Administration is investigating the accident. In particular, OSHA is investigated the workplace safety practices of the trucking company that had hired the 59-year-old man.</p> <p>Apparently the 59-year-old was involved in transferring the pallets of computer equipment from a small truck to a larger truck. The crates slipped and the 59-year-old became pinned.</p> <p>First responders used a rescue bar to pry away the pallet from the man, and he was taken to Nyack Hospital where he succumbed to his injuries.</p> <p>Should OSHA find negligence in this case, the 59-year-old man's surviving family members may be able to obtain wrongful death compensation due to third-party negligence as well as obtain workers' compensation survivors' benefits.</p> <p><strong>Source: </strong>NorthJersey.com, "<a href="http://www.northjersey.com/bogota/Bogota_man_dies_in_industrial_accident.html" target="_blank">Update: Bogota man who died in industrial accident wanted to go into nursing</a>," Abbott Koloff, Dec. 4, 2012</p> <ul> <li>At our New York law firm we represent individuals who have workers' compensation claims as well as third-party claims resulting from <a href="/Fatal-Accidents/Workers-Comp-Death-Benefits.shtml">fatal workplace accidents</a> such as the one mentioned in this post.</li></ul>]]>
  </content>
  <!--fatal-accidents-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Building Collapse Causes Fatal Accident At Manhattan Construction Site]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2012/03/building-collapse-causes-fatal-accident-at-manhattan-construction-site.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2012:/blog//81520.3244319</id>
  <published>2012-03-30T20:36:52Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:24Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[A warehouse being demolished to make room for a Columbia University expansion project recently collapsed, burying three construction workers in the rubble. Emergency crews were able to dig through the concrete, steel beams and other debris from the fallen 1915...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Fatal Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="constructionaccidents" label="Construction Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="fatalaccidents" label="Fatal Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="osha" label="OSHA" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="workerscompdeathbenefits" label="Workers' Comp Death Benefits" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>A warehouse being demolished to make room for a Columbia University expansion project recently collapsed, burying three construction workers in the rubble. Emergency crews were able to dig through the concrete, steel beams and other debris from the fallen 1915 building and eventually free each of them.</p> <p>The injured workers were taken to St. Luke's Roosevelt Hospital, but one did not survive the <a href="/Fatal-Accidents/">fatal accident</a>. Sixty-nine year old Juan Ruiz had been buried up to his chest after the collapse; he later died at the hospital.</p> <p>Investigators initially blame the collapse on a support beam that was part of the buildings structural support system being cut prematurely. However, the investigation is still ongoing.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>The Brooklyn company leading the demolition, Breeze National Inc., has a less-than-perfect past related to construction site accidents and worker safety. Breeze received a stop-work order in early March because it didn't let the City know about the planned demolition&nbsp;and had not put the appropriate safety harnesses in place for workers.</p> <p>Another Breeze construction worker was killed while working on the Columbia expansion in a construction site fall in 2010. Breeze was cited and fined by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) in the fatal construction accident for not having appropriate fall protection in place.</p> <p>The company is also on a "caution list" with the City of New York. Breeze currently has no contracts with NYC. Columbia required Breeze retain a risk management firm before it was allowed to work on the expansion project.</p> <p><b>Source:</b> The New York Times, "<a target="_blank" href="http://cityroom.blogs.nytimes.com/2012/03/22/construction-worker-killed-in-building-collapse-in-manhattan/">Construction Worker Killed in Building Collapse in Manhattan</a>," Al Baker, March 22, 2012</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--fatal-accidents-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Fatal Deutsche Bank Fire Trial: Construction Supervisors Acquitted]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2011/07/fatal-deutsche-bank-trial-construction-supervisors-acquitted.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2011:/blog//81520.3244308</id>
  <published>2011-07-08T17:02:30Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:23Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[While fatal construction accidents in New York City are fairly common, rarely do they result in criminal charges against the responsible parties. However, the horrific consequences of a construction error at the Deutsche Bank building prompted prosecutors to seek criminal...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Fatal Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
    <category term="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="constructionaccidents" label="Construction Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="fatalaccidents" label="Fatal Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="newyorkcity" label="New York City" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="wrongfuldeath" label="Wrongful Death" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>While fatal <a href="/Construction-Accident-Injuries/">construction accidents</a> in New York City are fairly common, rarely do they result in criminal charges against the responsible parties. However, the horrific consequences of a construction error at the Deutsche Bank building prompted prosecutors to seek criminal convictions against three construction supervisors.</p> <p>The prosecution sought manslaughter charges against construction supervisors deemed responsible for the removal of a large section of standpipe from the Deutsche Bank building. The decision to remove the standpipe - without replacing or moving it - caused the death of two NYC firefighters roughly a year later.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>The firemen were in the basement of the Deutsche Bank fighting a blaze in Aug. 2007,&nbsp;when the missing standpipe prevented the men from quickly getting water on the fire. Consequentially, the two heroes lost their lives.</p> <p>The Manhattan district attorney's office strongly considered naming NYC as a defendant but opted not to because of concerns over governmental immunity. Nonetheless, the government racked up $5.7 million in legal fees during the investigation and trial spanning nearly three years. The Fire and Buildings Department also endured heavy criticism, as a thorough inspection could have revealed the safety hazard.</p> <p>While the Deutsche Bank fire is an unusual accident, construction errors and safety oversight cost construction workers their health - or even lives - each year in New York. Most fatal construction site accidents involve <a href="/Construction-Accident-Injuries/Falls-from-Heights.shtml">falls from heights</a> (such as scaffolding or ladders), falling objects, trench collapses or improper excavation. Construction accident injuries and deaths usually occur when a safety measure has been disregarded or overlooked.</p> <p>If you have been seriously injured in a&nbsp;workplace accident, contact an experienced personal injury attorney to discuss what claims you may have, inside and outside of the workers' compensation system.</p> <p><b>Source:</b> The New York Times, "<a target="_blank" href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/07/07/nyregion/final-defendant-is-acquitted-in-deutsche-bank-fire-trial.html">Final Defendant Acquitted in Deutsche Bank Fire</a>," John Eligon, July 6, 2011.</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--fatal-accidents-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[The Triangle Shirtwaist Fire and Days of Less Workplace Safety]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2011/03/the-triangle-shirtwaist-fire-and-days-of-less-workplace-safety.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2011:/blog//81520.3244303</id>
  <published>2011-03-01T18:55:57Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:22Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[As we approach the 100-year anniversary of the Triangle Shirtwaist Fire, it is a great time to give pause and remember the countless deaths that occurred in New York's days of few workplace regulations. Men, women and even children -...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Fatal Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
    <category term="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="fatalaccidents" label="Fatal Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="laborunions" label="Labor Unions" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="newyorkcity" label="New York City" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="workplacesafety" label="Workplace Safety" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>As we approach the 100-year anniversary of the Triangle Shirtwaist Fire, it is a great time to give pause and remember the countless deaths that occurred in New York's days of few workplace regulations. Men, women and even children - many of them immigrants - endured horrific sweatshop conditions where they risked life and limb each day to bring home meager earnings.</p> <p>It was under these hazardous jobsite conditions that 146 people lost their lives on March 25, 1911. On that day, more than 600 people worked in the Triangle Waist Company factory in Manhattan busily making women's clothing. A discarded cigarette or match quickly caused a blaze after coming into contact with scraps of flammable cotton fabric.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Many workers needlessly died in the blaze, as they were obstructed from fleeing the fire because many of the factory doors remained locked during the workday. The tragedy is the worst industrial <a href="/Workplace-Accidents/">workplace accident</a> New York City has ever experienced.</p> <p>It would be an insult to all those people who have died in the Triangle Fire (and other New York factories) for the norm of deadly workplaces to continue. In the days following the Triangle Fire, many workers unified to gain leverage in improving jobsite conditions. The fire also spurred New York's passage of the most stringent fire-safety laws in the country.</p> <p><b>There's Still Room for Improvement</b></p> <p>While legislation, powerful labor unions and modern technology have played important roles in reducing workplace fatalities and serious injuries, there are still far too many deadly work accidents. While laws and unions work toward making New York employees safer in their vocations, ultimately the safety of workers falls upon the employer.</p> <p><b>Sources:</b> examiner.com, "<a target="_blank" href="http://www.examiner.com/historic-places-in-new-york/triangle-fire-kicks-off-month-marking-100th-anniversary-of-nyc-disaster">'Triangle Fire' kicks off month marking 100th anniversary of NYC disaster,</a>" 2/28/2011; nysut.org, "<a target="_blank" href="http://www.nysut.org/cps/rde/xchg/nysut/hs.xsl/nysutunited_16240.htm">Triangle fire galvanized labor unions</a>," 2/17/2011</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--fatal-accidents-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Recent Construction Worker Deaths Leave Families Devastated]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2010/12/recent-construction-worker-deaths-leave-families-devastated.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2010:/blog//81520.3244301</id>
  <published>2010-12-31T11:58:33Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:22Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[This is the time of year when families should be spending quality time together; unfortunately, several families have lost a beloved family member in December construction accidents. Scaffolding Collapse Kills 61-year-old Mason A Michigan man's life was cut short when...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Fatal Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
    <category term="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
    <category term="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="constructionaccidents" label="Construction Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="fatalaccidents" label="Fatal Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="workerscompdeathbenefits" label="Workers' Comp Death Benefits" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="wrongfuldeath" label="Wrongful Death" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>This is the time of year when families should be spending quality time together; unfortunately, several families have lost a beloved family member in December construction accidents.</p> <h3><b>Scaffolding Collapse Kills 61-year-old Mason</b></h3> <p>A Michigan man's life was cut short when scaffolding collapsed and fell on him. The <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Construction-Accident-Injuries/Scaffolding-Accidents.shtml">scaffolding accident</a> occurred at Pellston Regional Airport. The man was a husband, father-of-three, and a Vietnam Veteran. It's especially tragic that he was about to enter his "golden years" and enjoy the company of his sons and grandchildren.</p> <p>The accident is currently under investigation, but there is usually a failure to follow a safety precaution when such a devastating accident occurs; scaffolding shouldn't unexpectedly collapse and place workers in danger.</p> <h3><b>Construction Worker Dies in Trench Collapse</b></h3> <p>A horrific situation recently occurred when a trench collapsed in Pennsylvania, burying two construction workers. The injuries were serious, as the men were buried in heavy rocks, soil and rubble. A 20-year-old construction worker didn't survive the trench collapse; he is survived by a pregnant fiancé.</p> <p>The Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) is currently investigating into what caused the trench to collapse. Officials believe that the investigation will be a lengthy process as they try to determine why this tragedy happened and how it could have been avoided.</p> <h3><b>After a Fatal Construction Accident in New York</b></h3>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Losing a loved one in a <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Fatal-Accidents/">fatal accident</a> is an unimaginably painful experience. The grieving process is long and difficult and survivors need the support of family and friends to get through it. The last thing any grieving survivors should have to worry about is the legal recourse they are entitled to through losing their loved one.</p> <p>In New York, an experienced personal injury attorney can handle the investigation and legal implications of an accident so that the family can concentrate on healing. A skilled lawyer will focus not only on workers' compensation death benefits but will do a thorough investigation to examine whether the employer or a third-party can be held liable for wrongful death.</p> <p>Sources: 9and10news.com, York Daily Record</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--fatal-accidents-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Rigger Cleared of Criminal Charges: Awaits Dozens of Civil Suits]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2010/08/rigger-cleared-of-criminal-charges-awaits-dozens-of-civil-suits.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2010:/blog//81520.3244296</id>
  <published>2010-08-27T11:41:14Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:21Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Master rigger William Rapetti was cleared of seven counts of manslaughter in a non-jury trial on July 22, 2010. While criminal charges have been cleared, Rapetti still faces numerous civil lawsuits. Rapetti was charged for his involvement in the fatal...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Fatal Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="constructionaccidents" label="Construction Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="fatalaccidents" label="Fatal Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="newyorkcity" label="New York City" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="thirdpartyclaims" label="Third-Party Claims" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Master rigger William Rapetti was cleared of seven counts of manslaughter in a non-jury trial on July 22, 2010. While criminal charges have been cleared, Rapetti still faces numerous civil lawsuits. </p> <p>Rapetti was charged for his involvement in the fatal accident in March 2008 when a 300-foot tower crane collapsed in Manhattan, New York. Six workers and a tourist from Florida were <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Fatal-Accidents/Workers-Comp-Death-Benefits.shtml">killed</a> and two dozen others were injured. Rapetti's company, Rapetti Rigging Inc., was also cleared of all charges. </p> <p>The prosecution claimed the collapse was caused by Rapetti Rigging Inc.'s sparse and damaged equipment. The defense's investigation found the collapse was due to a poorly welded tie-in beam on the building under construction, which Rapetti had no control over. </p> <p>Rapetti still faces dozens of <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workers-Compensation/Additional-Claims-Beyond-Workers-Comp.shtml">civil suits</a> and at least 112 claims totaling $420 million have been filed against New York City. </p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<strong>The Difference Between Civil and Criminal Liability<br /><br /></strong> <p>In a criminal suit, a party is brought to court to upon being charged with a crime. To be found guilty of a crime, the jury or judge must find the case against the defendant to be "beyond reasonable doubt". Those charged as guilty of a crime in a criminal suit usually are penalized with monetary fines or imprisonment. </p> <p>In a civil suit, a party files a claim to collect damages from another party for either emotional or physical injury. In civil suits, the burden of proof is known as the "balance of probability", which is much lower than that in criminal suits. </p> <p><strong>Have You Suffered a Work Related Injury?</strong></p> <p>If you have suffered a <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workplace-Accidents/">work related injury</a> and have missed work or have unpaid medical bills, you could be entitled to financial help. Contact an attorney with experience in workers' compensation immediately. </p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--fatal-accidents-->
</entry>

</feed>