<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/includes/blog-feed/atom.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Newburgh New York Workers' Compensation Law Blog]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/" />
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/atom.xml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2013-03-21:/blog/81520</id>
  <updated>2018-09-20T15:36:45Z</updated>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[This Workers' Compensation blog offers news and other information Dennis Kenny Law hopes Newburgh, New York residents will find helpful. Please share your comments with us.]]></subtitle>
  <generator uri="http://www.sixapart.com/movabletype/">Movable Type Enterprise</generator>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Can you get disability if it was not a workplace accident?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/09/can-you-get-disability-if-it-was-not-a-workplace-accident.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3444389</id>
  <published>2018-09-20T15:37:45Z</published>
  <updated>2018-09-20T15:36:45Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Workers in New York who suffer an injury or illness on the job will generally be able to get workers' compensation benefits. This is essential for people who cannot work and need payments to make ends meet and to...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workerscompensation" label="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Workers in New York who suffer an injury or illness on the job will generally be able to get workers' compensation benefits. This is essential for people who cannot work and need payments to make ends meet and to cover medical expenses. What they might not know is that they can also get disability benefits if the injury or illness took place off the job. This is under the umbrella of the Workers' Compensation Board. Understanding what benefits are available if they were <a href="http://www.wcb.ny.gov/content/main/TheBoard/disability-benefits-fact-sheet.pdf" target="_blank">injured off the job</a> and how to go about getting them is critical to the process.</p> <p>Since most employers are required to have disability insurance, workers who became injured or ill off the job can receive temporary cash benefits if their issues stop them from working. For cash, the worker will get half their average weekly wages with a maximum of $170 weekly. This is based on what they earned in the previous eight weeks until the final day they worked before being injured or getting ill. There will be Social Security taxes on these benefits.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Workers must wait seven days before getting the benefits. The payments will start on the eighth consecutive day in which they were disabled. The initial benefit payment will be due within four days following the fourteenth day. While the worker is disabled, the payments will come every two weeks. While the worker is receiving these payments, quitting the job for a reason that is not linked to the disability can impact the payments.</p> <p>A pregnant woman can get disability during maternity leave. Since disability can take place during pregnancy or post-childbirth, these benefits will be available. It is required that a physician or a certified nurse midwife certifies that the disability is in place. Should a claim be rejected, a worker has the right to ask for a review. The request must be sent to the Disability Benefits Bureau at the Workers' Compensation Board.</p> <p>Disability benefits can be crucial to making ends meet after a worker has suffered an injury or became ill off the job. Understanding the benefits available and the steps necessary in any situation is imperative. A law firm that is experienced in helping workers with disability and <a href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workers-Compensation/">workers' compensation</a> can try to help with a claim.</p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Construction accidents in New York are on the rise]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/09/construction-accidents-in-new-york-are-on-the-rise.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3420881</id>
  <published>2018-09-05T14:32:39Z</published>
  <updated>2018-09-05T14:31:39Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Throughout New York, construction is seemingly constant. This is a positive as it provides jobs and other benefits. However, concerns about safety are ever-present and one of the most dangerous jobs that anyone can do is in construction. With...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="constructionworkersaccidents" label="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Throughout New York, construction is seemingly constant. This is a positive as it provides jobs and other benefits. However, concerns about safety are ever-present and one of the most dangerous jobs that anyone can do is in construction. With the heavy machinery, working on scaffolds and ladders at great heights, and the large tools that are inherent with construction work, a construction worker accident can happen for a variety of reasons. <a href="https://nypost.com/2018/09/01/construction-accidents-soar-amid-nyc-building-boom/" target="_blank">Research has found</a> that the number of construction accidents have been rising in a worrisome fashion.</p> <p>In New York City, there has been a rise in construction injuries and fatalities. Injuries have increased by 17 percent; fatalities have doubled. Through July, there were eight construction-related fatalities to workers. In 2017, in that same amount of time, there were four deaths. Regarding injuries, the first seven months of the year had 457 job-related accidents and 469 injuries.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>The Bureau of Labor Statistics says that the job with the highest risk in the city is construction work. Construction accidents led to more than 37 percent of the deaths on the job for 2016. At least 50 people have been hurt by falling debris thus far in 2018. Part of the reason there are so many accidents is the amount of construction that is taking place. With more than 45,000 construction workers in the city alone, accidents occur because of negligence, errors and accidents. Attempts to make the job safer have included increased training for construction workers, increased penalties for employers who shun proper safety and keeping better track of accidents as they occur.</p> <p>A construction worker accident can leave a person with the need for extensive medical care, lifelong injuries and the inability to get back to the same type of job, if the worker can get back to work at all. Whether it was a fall, burns, broken bones, joint injuries, spinal cord damage, head injuries or other issues, legal help can be essential to get workers' compensation benefits, coverage for medical care and help with lost wages. In some cases, there is a disagreement over issues such as how long the worker will be out and the amount of medical care that is needed. An experienced law firm can try to help with <a href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/Construction-Accident-Injuries/">construction accidents</a> and the legal claims that need to pursued.</p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Work zone injuries a rising problem in New York]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/08/work-zone-injuries-a-rising-problem-in-new-york.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3402154</id>
  <published>2018-08-23T15:33:24Z</published>
  <updated>2018-08-23T15:32:24Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[When thinking about construction accidents and the dangers that a construction worker might face in New York, the immediate thought turns to constructing tall buildings, working on a roof, being stationed at great heights and dealing with heavy machinery....]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="constructionworkersaccidents" label="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>When thinking about construction accidents and the dangers that a construction worker might face in New York, the immediate thought turns to constructing tall buildings, working on a roof, being stationed at great heights and dealing with heavy machinery. However, road workers who are doing necessary construction to build, maintain and repair the state's infrastructure are in substantial jeopardy of being in an accident - perhaps more than other construction workers. Needing to navigate roadwork with drivers who might not pay attention to the dangers can lead to a construction worker accident and injuries. It can even cause death. Those who have been hurt must remember they are likely entitled to workers' compensation.</p> <p>According to the statistics, there were <a href="https://www.mytwintiers.com/news/local-news/nysdot-urge-caution-after-2017-saw-nearly-700-work-zone-crashes/1357519558" target="_blank">almost 700 accidents</a> in construction zones in New York in 2017. Distracted driving is believed to have been a cause in a significant number of them. Although the New York State Department of Transportation is entreating drivers to pay close attention to the road as they are supposed to, there are seemingly endless anecdotes from workers about drivers who are not watching what they are doing and are therefore placing workers at risk.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>A recent article noted how one worker who does maintenance stated that he witnessed a driver who was not using a smartphone while behind the wheel, but was using a laptop. This same worker was injured when his truck was rear-ended by a tractor-trailer. He suffered injuries to his neck that are still problematic. Initially, he had headaches, but treatment was effective in alleviating them. Another worker who did maintenance for the NYSDOT was hurt when a tractor-trailer ran into the work zone and he was hit by a sharp object. His helmet prevented long-term damage. The driver continued without stopping.</p> <p>Any worker who is employed in a construction work zone where vehicles pass should be aware of the chance that there could be a crash due to a driver speeding, behaving recklessly, driving under the influence or failing to pay attention. When suffering injuries on the job, there will be the need for medical care, coverage for the lost wages and other costs. Workers' compensation benefits are imperative to recover and to make ends meet. When seeking workers' compensation after suffering <a href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/Construction-Accident-Injuries/">serious injuries</a> when working on road construction, it can be beneficial to speak to a law firm experienced in representing injured workers.</p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[How does workers' compensation cover Schedule Loss of Use?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/08/how-does-workers-compensation-cover-schedule-loss-of-use.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3385289</id>
  <published>2018-08-09T15:22:51Z</published>
  <updated>2018-08-09T15:21:51Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Workers in New York who suffer workplace injuries should understand the different categories of loss their issues might fall into. Every workplace accident is different and can impact a person in a variety of ways. Depending on the circumstances,...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workerscompensation" label="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Workers in New York who suffer workplace injuries should understand the different categories of loss their issues might fall into. Every workplace accident is different and can impact a person in a variety of ways. Depending on the circumstances, the workers' compensation benefits can change. There can even be more benefits. Understanding these factors is imperative to a workers' compensation case, especially when there is disagreement or an outright dispute. This is specifically true in cases where there is a <a href="http://www.wcb.ny.gov/content/main/Workers/ScheduledLossUse.jsp" target="_blank">Schedule Loss of Use</a>.</p> <p>With Schedule Loss of Use, referred to as SLU, the injured worker will receive more cash than would otherwise be provided under workers' compensation. When the worker has suffered an injury that diminishes the ability to use a body part and he or she cannot return to the previous level of use, it is a permanent disability. Then there might be eligibility to get SLU. The worker can get this payment regardless of whether work time was missed or if there was a return to work.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>The following body part injuries could result in a person being eligible for SLU: hand, foot, facial injuries with scars, scalp, neck, toe, eye with vision loss, ear with hearing loss, leg, arm and finger. Also included are joints. A permanent injury can be burns in the second and third degree, a crush injury, severe nerve damage, dislocation, amputated limbs, fractures and more. The amount the person can get will vary based on the injury. For example, an injury to the arm will warrant 312 weeks in total. If there was 50 percent loss of use of the arm, 312 will be divided in half. The pay will be two-thirds of what the person earned per week and that will be paid for what would be earned in 156 weeks.</p> <p>To get SLU, it is necessary to receive a doctor's opinion as to when maximum medical improvement has been reached. For people who fall into this category, the additional pay can be vital to their future. To ensure that all the benefits available can be received and maximized often requires legal help. A law firm that understands all areas of <a href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/Loss-of-Use.shtml">workers' compensation benefits</a>, particularly SLU, may be of assistance.</p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Managing a repetitive strain injury]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/08/managing-a-repetitive-strain-injury.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3383943</id>
  <published>2018-08-08T18:21:34Z</published>
  <updated>2018-08-08T18:20:34Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[When you imagine a person applying for workers’ compensation, you most likely imagine someone who works on a construction site. While jobs that require a lot of physical labor do cause injuries from time to time, more sedentary vocations like...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
  
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>When you imagine a person applying for workers’ compensation, you most likely imagine someone who works on a construction site. While jobs that require a lot of physical labor do cause injuries from time to time, more sedentary vocations like office work can also cause painful injuries that may put you on medical leave.</p> <p>As someone who does most of their work at a computer desk, it’s unlikely that you will fall off a roof while on the job. The office sector sees many more repetitive strain type injuries. According to <a href="https://www.medicalnewstoday.com/articles/176443.php" target="_blank" >Medical News Today</a>, these injuries can be the result of repetitive tasks or awkward body positioning and may be worsened by stress and fatigue.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>A repetitive strain injury can manifest in several different ways. Consider seeing a doctor if you begin suffering from:</p> <ul> <li>Soreness or tenderness in or around a joint</li> <li>Painful throbbing in a muscle or joint</li> <li>Unexpected tingling or numbness in fingers, hand or arm</li> <li>Feeling a change in temperature in a joint</li> <li>Swelling in an affected muscle or joint</li> </ul> <p>A doctor’s examination will be the final determination, but these are often early symptoms of a repetitive strain injury like tendonitis or carpal tunnel syndrome.</p> <p><strong>Responding to a repetitive strain injury</strong></p> <p>Your doctor will be able to provide you with the best medical treatment for your situation. Common treatments for early stages of repetitive strain injuries are varied. They may be treatable with simple anti-inflammatory painkillers, such as aspirin or hot and cold therapy. Giving your joints and muscles time to rest is also often an effective treatment.</p> <p>Don’t wait for your symptoms to become debilitating to see a doctor. Repetitive strain injuries can become chronic if not treated in a timely manner.</p> <p><strong>Preventing repetitive strain injuries before they start</strong></p> <p>Your body will often give you warning signs before an actual injury can take hold. As an office worker, some of the most effective steps you can take to prevent a repetitive strain injury are:</p> <ul> <li><strong>Take a break</strong> – Taking 5 minutes to move will keep your muscles more limber and blood circulating.</li> <li><strong>Shift positions</strong> – Don’t let yourself sit awkwardly for an extended period. This can isolate and strain your muscles, tendons and joints.</li> <li><strong>Customize</strong><strong> your</strong><strong> work station</strong> – Everyone works differently. Make sure your desk, chair, monitor and everything else at your station are ergonomically positioned to fit your needs.</li> <li><strong>Stretch</strong> – Taking a few minutes to stretch during a meal or coffee break can go a long way in preventing injuries.</li> </ul> <p>Living actively and eating healthy are two of the best things you can do to prevent injuries. Help your body out by exercising, stretching and eating well. It can keep your blood flow strong and your muscles healthy.</p> <p>Anyone can sustain an injury while on the job – even people with less physically demanding careers. Keep yourself safe and healthy, and speak to your doctor right away if you being to feel pain in your muscles and joints.</p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[What should I know about workers' comp for occupational disease?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/07/what-should-i-know-about-workers-comp-for-occupational-disease.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3367846</id>
  <published>2018-07-26T17:12:42Z</published>
  <updated>2018-07-26T17:11:42Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[New York State workers who suffer from an occupational disease should know that they can get workers' compensation benefits, just as a worker who suffered a physical injury can. However, it is imperative to understand that there are certain...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workerscompensation" label="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>New York State workers who suffer from an <a href="http://www.wcb.ny.gov/content/main/onthejob/OccDisease.jsp" target="_blank">occupational disease</a> should know that they can get workers' compensation benefits, just as a worker who suffered a physical injury can. However, it is imperative to understand that there are certain differences to consider when seeking those benefits. With an occupational disease, it must be an issue that has come about because of exposure to certain conditions on the job. It is vital to remember that the disease is required to have been produced naturally from the occupation itself.</p> <p>The workers' compensation benefits for an occupational disease are the same as they are for someone who was injured on the job. There is a different time limit when deciding to file the claim. It must be the later date of the following: two years from the date at which the disability came about; or two years from when the disabled worker knew or should have known that the disease came about because of the employment. The time limits are the same for family members if the worker has died. There can be a finding of disability if the person became ill and did not miss any work. A Workers' Compensation Law Judge will decide on the date at which the person became disabled.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>For people who have suffered occupational hearing loss, there are separate time limits. The worker has the choice of the following: three months from the date at which the worker was no longer working where the harmful noise is; or three months after leaving the employment where the noise was taking place. The last day of either of these three-month time frames will be the date at which the disability commenced. It is possible to file after the two years if it has been done within 90 days of the worker discovering that the hearing loss is because of the job.</p> <p>Often, people who have suffered an occupational disease will not even be aware that they are ill and can get <a href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workers-Compensation/">workers' compensation benefits</a>. In other instances, they miss the time limits for applying to get workers' compensation. When there is a belief that there is occupational disease, it is key to have legal assistance to pursue workers' compensation benefits. Calling immediately is a must.</p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[What if my New York workers' compensation claim is controverted?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/07/what-if-my-new-york-workers-compensation-claim-is-controverted.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3346038</id>
  <published>2018-07-12T14:27:24Z</published>
  <updated>2018-07-12T14:26:24Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[People who are injured in a workplace accident will expect that their workers' compensation claim will be approved, and they will receive the benefits they are entitled to for treatment and wage coverage as they try to recover. However,...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workerscompensation" label="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>People who are injured in a workplace accident will expect that their workers' compensation claim will be approved, and they will receive the benefits they are entitled to for treatment and wage coverage as they try to recover. However, not all cases are immediately accepted at face value by the insurance company, and they will <a href="http://www.wcb.ny.gov/content/main/Employers/claimsprocess4.jsp" target="_blank">controvert a claim</a>. When a claim is controverted (denied) and the worker has legitimate injuries stemming from the work he or she was doing, it is important to know when this might take place and what to do about it.</p> <p>There are many reasons why the insurer can controvert the claim. They might say that the injury did not happen due to work, the employee's injuries are being exaggerated, the injuries happened on a second job and more. It is also possible that the employer will request that the insurance company controvert the employee's claim. Still, it is ultimately at the discretion of the employer as the insurer has responsibility for the claim's liability. It does not need to adhere to such a request from the employer.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>After the claim has been controverted, there will be a hearing so a Judge will listen to the arguments of both sides. The New York State Workers Compensation Board can have a hearing or require that the hearings be held before a Workers Compensation Law Judge.</p> <p>At the hearing, there can be testimony, depositions, medical reviews and assessment of other evidence to determine if the benefits should be provided. If the Judge decides that compensation should be provided, he or she will decide how much it should be and for how long it should last.</p> <p>When a worker is injured and the claim is controverted, it can be a worrisome time for the employee as it is venturing into the unknown as to how the case will be decided upon. Fortunately, there are options when the claim is controverted and it is possible to receive <a href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workers-Compensation/Why-Do-I-Need-a-Lawyer.shtml">workers' compensation benefits</a>. To ensure that the process goes smoothly and the worker's interests are protected, a law firm experienced in workers' compensation benefits should be contacted immediately.</p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Workers investigating gas leak suffer burns in workplace accident]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/06/workers-investigating-gas-leak-suffer-burns-in-workplace-accident.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3324157</id>
  <published>2018-06-28T14:26:21Z</published>
  <updated>2018-06-28T14:25:21Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Keeping New York State running effectively and efficiently requires workers performing maintenance, repairs and construction. While these workers are generally competent and do their jobs safely, there remains an inherent danger in any task they are required to do....]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceinjuries" label="Workplace Injuries" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Keeping New York State running effectively and efficiently requires workers performing maintenance, repairs and construction. While these workers are generally competent and do their jobs safely, there remains an inherent danger in any task they are required to do. This is especially true when working with electrical and explosive materials. Those who are in an accident in these circumstances can face burns and other types of on-the-job injury. With the medical expenses and long-term damage that can result, workers' compensation and a legal filing are often the only available ways to cover what they lost.</p> <p>An explosion led to <a href="https://www.nbcnewyork.com/news/local/Manhole-Explode-Fire-Brooklyn-NYC-Injuries-NYPD-FDNY-Investigation-486232661.html" target="_blank">three utility workers being burned</a>. A gas leak is believed to have been the cause. The incident occurred in the early morning hours at around 1 a.m. The workers are employed by National Grid. After the explosion, the men were taken to the hospital for treatment. They were said to have minor burns. A spokesperson for the company stated that the workers were there to investigate a potential gas leak. As they dug, there was a spark and the subsequent explosion. Work in the area is ongoing to determine the source of the gas leak.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Burns can have a major impact on a worker's life. These can cause scars, damage to nerves, the body part being limited or outright useless and even result in infections and death. Even minor burns can have a negative effect on a person's life and ability to work. There will be medical costs, hospitalization and the potential issues getting back to work. Workers' compensation can help to cover the worker for the treatment and for the time missed on the job. If there are costs that are not paid, a legal filing can be pursued.</p> <p>For these workers, despite the reports that the burns were minor, they could still deal with long-term problems due to this accident. Regardless, for the medical expenses, lost wages and other problems that can and will come up due to this explosion, they should make certain they get the maximum benefits with help from a legal professional experienced in helping <a href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/Burns-and-Electrocution.shtml">injured workers</a>.</p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Tractor trailer rollovers and workers' compensation]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/06/spilled-milk-and-workers-compensation.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3317967</id>
  <published>2018-06-27T19:41:00Z</published>
  <updated>2018-07-03T11:43:22Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Most understand that when you get an injury at work you are eligible for workers' compensation benefits. People are less sure of that when it comes to injuries that happen when working from home or traveling for work. This begs...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
  
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Most understand that when you get an injury at work you are eligible for workers' compensation benefits. People are less sure of that when it comes to injuries that happen when working from home or traveling for work. This begs the question: are you eligible for workers' compensation if you get an injury while working outside your workplace?</p> <p>On June 18, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.wktv.com/content/news/Tractor-Trailer-Wedged-Underneath-Route-5-Bridge-on-Thruway-485807501.html">a tractor trailer driver</a> was killed when his truck rolled over crossing a bridge near Schuyler, New York. This accident can serve as an example of how workers' compensation covers accidents outside the workplace.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p><strong>What this can teach us</strong></p> <p>Workers' compensation does not&nbsp;<a target="_blank" href="https://statelaws.findlaw.com/new-york-law/new-york-workers-compensation-laws.html">consider fault</a>&nbsp;when it comes to providing benefits for injuries. So, because the truck driver was at work, even if he was not necessarily in an office, the driver may file a workers' compensation claim, up to and including death benefits.</p> <p>This principle works for a variety of injuries incurred outside the <a href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/Offsite-Accidents/">traditional workspace</a>, such as:</p> <ul> <li><strong>Remote workers: </strong>People who work from home spend a great deal of time typing and are at risk for carpal tunnel and other repetitive motion injuries.</li> <li><strong>Emergency medical technicians:</strong> These healthcare workers are at risk for back injuries and infections as part of their jobs.</li> <li><strong>Work-related travel: </strong>When you travel to other cities, states or countries, and you face risks of a variety of accidents that can keep you from working.</li> <li><strong>Delivery truck drivers:</strong> These workers spend their entire shift moving from place to place, and can get into accidents or hurt themselves moving equipment.</li> </ul> <p>All of these scenarios are covered by workers' compensation. The only consideration is whether this happened as part of your job.</p> <p><strong>Know your rights to protect yourself</strong></p> <p>Every worker has a right to coverage no matter what their workspace looks like. If your employer's insurer tries to tell you otherwise you have options.</p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[What are disability classifications for workers' compensation?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/06/what-are-disability-classifications-for-workers-compensation.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3307421</id>
  <published>2018-06-14T17:45:20Z</published>
  <updated>2018-06-14T17:44:20Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Suffering workplace injuries in New York can cause concern for the worker and his or her family. The missed time on the job, lost wages, medical costs and uncertain future will inevitably lead to the worker seeking workers' compensation...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workerscompensation" label="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Suffering workplace injuries in New York can cause concern for the worker and his or her family. The missed time on the job, lost wages, medical costs and uncertain future will inevitably lead to the worker seeking workers' compensation to provide for them as they recover. If they are unable to recover, workers' compensation benefits can help with that too.</p> <p>However, workers are often unaware of the different <a href="http://www.wcb.ny.gov/content/main/TheBoard/indemnity-fact-sheet.pdf" target="_blank">disability classifications</a> in which their injuries are placed. Knowing these classifications and how it can affect their workers' compensation benefits is important in a claim and knowing how to proceed. The classifications are: Temporary Total Disability; Temporary Partial Disability; Permanent Total Disability; Permanent Partial Disability, Non-schedule Loss; Permanent Partial Disability, Schedule Loss; and Disfigurement.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Temporary Total Disability means that the person is unable to work and therefore cannot earn wages. The person will have the right to get the full wage benefit under workers' compensation. Temporary Partial Disability means that the worker has lost a certain amount of ability to work and can get full wages. The benefits the person receives will equal the determined percentage of the disability. Permanent Total Disability means that the worker has lost his or her ability to work and earn wages. These benefits will be continuous for the duration of the person's life.</p> <p>Permanent Partial Disability, Non-schedule Loss means that the person has lost a portion of the ability to work. There can be as much as 10 years of lost wage benefits. During those 10 years, if they are going to expire, the person might be able to get lifetime benefits if more than 75 percent of earning potential has been lost. There will be lifetime medical care. Permanent Partial Disability, Schedule Loss means there is loss of a body part, sight or hearing. There will be a total of weeks for which the worker will get benefits and the Workers' Compensation Board will determine its duration. Finally, Disfigurement means they have been disfigured on the face, head or neck. They can receive up to $20,000. This is contingent on the extent of the injury.</p> <p>When there is a workplace accident or a condition that came about because of the work, <a href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workers-Compensation/">workers' compensation</a> can be a vital part of making ends meet and receiving the necessary medical care. There are many different factors that are part of the workers' compensation process. Included is the classification of the worker's disability. When there is a problem with this or a disagreement regarding the classification that affects the benefits, having help from a workers' compensation attorney is imperative.</p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Electrical accident on the job hospitalizes Midtown hotel worker]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/05/electrical-accident-on-the-job-hospitalizes-midtown-hotel-worker.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3289684</id>
  <published>2018-05-31T13:02:58Z</published>
  <updated>2018-05-31T13:01:58Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[In New York, work accidents can happen in any kind of job whether it is work that is viewed as physical and dangerous or sedentary and safe. The aftermath of these accidents is universal regardless of the kind of...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceaccidents" label="Workplace Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>In New York, work accidents can happen in any kind of job whether it is work that is viewed as physical and dangerous or sedentary and safe. The aftermath of these accidents is universal regardless of the kind of job it is. People who are injured after an accident on the job can be confronted with lost time at work, medical expenses and long-term problems as a result. Even jobs not thought to be significantly risky can have a safety hazard, an unsafe working environment or a mistake on the part of another worker or the workplace that causes the injuries. To ensure that the worker is compensated for all that was lost, a lawsuit is often necessary.</p> <p>A worker was <a href="https://patch.com/new-york/midtown-nyc/worker-injured-midtowns-roosevelt-hotel-fdny-says" target="_blank">seriously injured</a> in an electrical accident at a hotel in Midtown Manhattan after what was termed an "electrical incident." It did not reach the level of being considered an explosion. The Fire Department was called after it happened. The worker was found injured and transported to the hospital for treatment. He was in serious, but stable condition. It has not yet been reported what the cause of the accident was.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>People who are injured on the job should be cognizant of their rights to receive workers' compensation and everything that goes along with that. This is meant to pay for medical expenses, provide for lost wages and perhaps more. However, there are times when it can be difficult to get the benefits the worker believes he or she is supposed to get. It could be necessary to appeal a case if it is initially denied. Any injury can cause lifelong problems, pain and the inability to work the same job as before if the worker is able to work at all. Being protected by a legal professional is essential to making certain the maximum benefits are received.</p> <p>In this incident, a worker was injured in an electrical accident. He was said to have suffered serious injuries and hospitalized. The investigation into the case was continuing to determine what happened. The worker who was hurt should remember the importance of legal help in receiving compensation after a <a href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workplace-Accidents/">workplace accident</a> and contact a lawyer immediately.</p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[What if my workers' compensation claim is disputed?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/05/what-if-my-workers-compensation-claim-is-disputed.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3272242</id>
  <published>2018-05-18T04:53:50Z</published>
  <updated>2018-05-18T04:52:50Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[For New York State residents who are injured on the job or suffer a condition because of their work and it prevents them from working, workers' compensation benefits can be a lifeline. They can cover for lost wages, medical...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workerscompensation" label="Workers' Compensation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>For New York State residents who are injured on the job or suffer a condition because of their work and it prevents them from working, workers' compensation benefits can be a lifeline. They can cover for lost wages, medical expenses and more. However, there are times when there is a disagreement regarding the claim and it will be disputed. For those who file a workers' compensation claim and face a situation in which the insurer disputes it, it is critical to have legal assistance from an attorney who specializes in workers' compensation claims.</p> <p>If the insurer disputes the claim, it generally means that it does not agree that a work injury occurred, that it has not insured the employer, or there is another justification. Workers should understand that this does not mean that the case is over. The Workers' Compensation Board will have a hearing on the matter. At the hearing, a judge will examine the case with the medical records, wages the worker earned when working, and any other factor relevant to the claim. A decision will be made as to whether the worker should get workers' compensation or not.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Once the decision is made, the claimant or the insurer can file an appeal. It must be in writing and be done within 30 days of when the case was filed. The appeal will be reviewed by three Board members. It can be changed, rejected or there can be a request made for more hearings. While the case is in dispute, the claimant can ask to get disability benefits while it is heard.</p> <p>When the workers' compensation claim is disputed by the insurer, it can be a worrisome time for the claimant. The prospect of not getting the benefits can cause significant problems and the person might not know what to do if the claim is rejected. When seeking workers' compensation benefits, it is imperative to have legal help from the start to deal with any eventuality. A lawyer who is experienced in <a href="https://www.denniskennylaw.com/Workers-Compensation/">workers' compensation benefits</a> should be contacted immediately.</p> <p> <b>Source:&nbsp;</b>wcb.ny.gov, "<a href="http://www.wcb.ny.gov/content/main/TheBoard/file-claim-fact-sheet.pdf" target="_blank">What to Expect When You File a Claim -- If Your Claim Is Disputed</a>," accessed on May 16, 2018</p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[What can I do if there are toxic chemicals at my worksite?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/05/what-can-i-do-if-there-are-toxic-chemicals-at-my-worksite.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3252627</id>
  <published>2018-05-02T19:08:25Z</published>
  <updated>2018-05-02T19:07:25Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Dangerous chemicals at a worksite can be hazardous to the health and welfare of the workers who must do their jobs in the chemicals' presence. In New York and throughout the rest of the country workers have rights when...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="workplaceillness" label="Workplace Illness" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://employment.findlaw.com/workplace-safety/toxic-exposure-in-the-workplace.html" target="_blank">Dangerous chemicals</a> at a worksite can be hazardous to the health and welfare of the workers who must do their jobs in the chemicals' presence. In New York and throughout the rest of the country workers have rights when it comes to dealing with and avoiding chemicals that may do them harm. This post will briefly discuss a worker's options for working with toxic chemicals, but it does not provide legal advice or guidance on the topic.</p> <p>Any time that toxic chemicals are at a worksite an employer must make their workers aware of them. This includes giving workers information about the chemicals and can include providing workers with Material Safety Data Sheets. They may also use warning signs and chemical labels to provide information to their workers about the hazards present at their work locations.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>If a worker is asked to do their job with or in the presence of toxic chemicals there steps they may take to avoid exposure and possible illness or injury. They may seek guidance on whether safer alternatives may be used in place of the toxic materials. If safe options are not available, workers can make sure that they have the right safety equipment and training to handle those chemicals.</p> <p>When accidents with <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/">toxic chemicals</a> occur at work sites workers can pay a heavy price for the potential negligence of their employers. No worker should have to cope with the costs of a toxic chemical exposure on their own and some may have options for seeking compensation for their losses. Attorneys who handle toxic exposure cases can help those who have questions about their options for seeking damages in the wake of a damaging and dangerous exposure.</p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Surprising workplace injuries]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/05/surprising-workplace-injuries.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3252601</id>
  <published>2018-05-02T19:01:35Z</published>
  <updated>2018-05-02T19:00:35Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Any workplace has its hazards whether you are building a skyscraper or working in an office on the 66th floor of one. It is possible to get hurt anywhere, but some injuries are just surprising. The human body is strange,...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
  
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Any workplace has its hazards whether you are building a skyscraper or working in an office on the 66th floor of one. It is possible to get hurt anywhere, but some injuries are just surprising.</p> <p>The human body is strange, and long hours at work can take strange tolls on people. Here are a few of the ways <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/money/careers/2018/01/09/workplace-fatalities-25-most-dangerous-jobs-america/1002500001/" target="_blank">workplace activities</a> can cause injuries that you do not expect.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p><strong>Tennis elbow isn’</strong><strong>t just for athletes</strong></p> <p><a href="https://orthoinfo.aaos.org/en/diseases--conditions/tennis-elbow-lateral-epicondylitis/" target="_blank">Tennis elbow</a> doesn’t just affect people on the courts of Wimbledon. Mechanics, plumbers, machinists and anyone else who needs to have a strong grip is at risk. It’s a repetitive motion injury that can make holding anything excruciating.</p> <p><strong>Sitting in a chair can hurt your back</strong></p> <p>In offices throughout the world, people think they are safe from common back injuries. However, that is just not the case. Sitting doesn't strain you and<a href="https://www.healthline.com/health/workplace-health/things-that-happen-when-you-sit-down-all-day" target="_blank"> that’s the problem</a>. Without regular movement, the tendons in your hips can tighten up causing debilitating pain, and that is only one problem. There are many other health concerns with sitting.</p> <p><strong>Knee injuries are a roofing concern</strong></p> <p>For people would be the biggest problem for people working way up high falling is a huge concern, but proper safety precautions can mitigate that. What can’t be helped is day after day of kneeling as you hammer in nails. Your knees, even with proper protection, will start to ache and become painful to the point you may no longer be able to work.</p> <p><strong>Coaches are at risk</strong></p> <p>Standing on the sidelines means you’re out of harm’s way, right? Maybe. But mostly, it means that if anything goes off course or out of control you are right in its path. Coaches are often in a hustle to dodge players and objects from the field in order to stay safe. Sometimes it works. Sometimes it does not.</p> <p><strong>Unwelcome surprises</strong></p> <p>An injury you didn’t expect, is still an injury you must deal with. Finding help can be tricky, but there are definitely options.</p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[Construction site dangers cause many types of worker injuries]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2018/04/construction-site-dangers-cause-many-types-of-worker-injuries.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2018:/blog//81520.3244607</id>
  <published>2018-04-25T09:37:09Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:36:09Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[The hazards of working at a construction site are significant and when proper precautions are not taken New York workers can suffer injuries and death. There are a number of different ways that worksite deficiencies can cause injury-producing construction...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="constructionworkersaccidents" label="Construction Workers' Accidents" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>The hazards of working at a construction site are significant and when proper precautions are not taken New York workers can suffer injuries and death. There are a number of different ways that worksite deficiencies can cause injury-producing construction site accidents and this post will only touch on some of them. The information contained herein is not comprehensive on the topic of construction site accidents and should not be used as legal guidance.</p> <p>One of the most common ways that workers are hurt in <a href="https://injury.findlaw.com/workers-compensation/common-construction-injury-types.html" target="_blank">construction injuries</a> is through falls. Not long ago this post offered an article on a construction worker who fell down an elevator shaft while at work; falls can occur from buildings, off of equipment as well as from scaffolding. When workers are not properly tethered to heights they can suffer damaging and dangerous falls.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Accidents with vehicles and machinery are another common cause of construction site injuries. Workers can suffer injuries when work vehicles back into them and when vehicles pin them between their bumpers and other stationary objects. When workers are not properly trained to use the dangerous machines required of their jobs they can create significant hazards for themselves and others at their worksites.</p> <p>Exposure to chemicals and other substances can cause workers to not just suffer injuries but also to develop work-related illnesses. The types and causes of work-related illnesses are extensive, and as with all matters related to their health readers should seek help from medical professionals for their ailments. This post does not offer any medical advice but is intended to present its readers with a general overview of the many ways <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Construction-Accident-Injuries/">construction workers</a> can suffer harm while on the job.</p>]]>
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>