<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/includes/blog-feed/atom.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Toxic Exposure Archives | Newburgh New York Workers' Compensation Law Blog]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/toxic-exposure/" />
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/toxic-exposure/atom.xml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2013-03-21:/blog/81520</id>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:26Z</updated>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[This is the Toxic Exposure archive for Newburgh New York Workers' Compensation Law Blog.]]></subtitle>
  <generator uri="http://www.sixapart.com/movabletype/">Movable Type Enterprise</generator>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[OSHA releases initial post-Sandy toxic exposure report]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2013/01/osha-releases-initial-post-sandy-toxic-exposure-report.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2013:/blog//81520.3244336</id>
  <published>2013-01-17T22:23:33Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:26Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[In late December, we wrote about a warning released by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) regarding potential mold exposure risks for post-Sandy cleanup workers in New York, New Jersey and other affected areas. OSHA recently released its initial...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Toxic Exposure" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="osha" label="OSHA" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="superstormsandy" label="Superstorm Sandy" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="toxicexposure" label="Toxic Exposure" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>In late December, we wrote about a warning released by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) regarding potential mold exposure risks for post-Sandy cleanup workers in New York, New Jersey and other affected areas. OSHA recently released its initial findings about the rate of <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/Toxic-Exposure.shtml">toxic exposure</a> these workers are experiencing. Thankfully, the news is good for now.</p> <p>Currently, none of the sites surveyed by OSHA have toxic exposure limits that exceed ordinary workplace standards set by the agency. That means that at this time, post-Sandy cleanup sites are free from dangerous levels of toxins, as far as OSHA is aware. It is worth noting however, that certain sites like public roads, parks, private businesses and private homes are still in the process of being tested and thus statistics about toxic exposure limits at these sites have yet to be released.</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>Granted, toxic substances were indeed present in either the air, water or both at many of the dozens of landfills, public gathering areas and beaches that OSHA tested. These found substances included asbestos, silica, carbon monoxide, mold and lead. However, none of the substances found exceeded acceptable limits.</p> <p>Of course, certain toxins develop over time and mold exposure in particular may become more of a significant danger as semi-frozen worksites thaw out. But for now, workers are most likely in a fairly safe position with regards to post-Sandy toxic exposure.</p> <p>However, OSHA's New York regional administrator recently explained the most important aspect of the findings as follows, "These initial results should not be taken by employers as an "all clear" signal regarding potential exposure to health hazards. It is important that each employer continually ensure that workers are not overexposed."</p> <p><strong>Source</strong>: Star Tribune, "Tests at NY, NJ Sandy cleanup sites show contaminant levels below federal exposure limits," Katie Zezima, Jan. 9, 2013</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--toxic-exposure-->
</entry>

<entry>
  <title><![CDATA[OSHA warns about Sandy cleanup workers and mold exposure]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/2012/12/osha-warns-about-sandy-cleanup-workers-and-mold-exposure.shtml" />
  <id>tag:www.denniskennylaw.com,2012:/blog//81520.3244333</id>
  <published>2012-12-27T16:45:39Z</published>
  <updated>2018-04-25T09:22:25Z</updated>
  <summary><![CDATA[Just as the first responders did when SuperStorm Sandy hit, post-storm cleanup workers are facing dangerous hazards as they attempt to serve their communities. In addition to navigating unstable structures, interacting with dangerous equipment and so on, the U.S. Department...]]></summary>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[On behalf of Dennis Kenny Law]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
    <category term="Toxic Exposure" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
  
  <category term="superstormsandy" label="Superstorm Sandy" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" /><category term="toxicexposure" label="Toxic Exposure" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
  <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/blog/">
    <![CDATA[<p>Just as the first responders did when SuperStorm Sandy hit, post-storm cleanup workers are facing dangerous hazards as they attempt to serve their communities. In addition to navigating unstable structures, interacting with dangerous equipment and so on, the U.S. Department of Labor's Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) has recently warned that Sandy cleanup workers may be in danger of developing serious illness due to a certain kind of <a href="http://www.denniskennylaw.com/Work-Related-Injuries-Illnesses/Toxic-Exposure.shtml">toxic exposure</a>.</p> <p>As large portions of the Northeast dry out after being battered by water and submerged for some time, mold is growing steadily in buildings that have been condemned and also in many that remain occupied. In order for cleanup workers to avoid becoming ill from breathing in toxic mold spores, OSHA's New York regional administrator has warned that workers must remain educated about "the hazards of mold, developing an effective mediation plan, the use of effective controls, work practices and personal protective equipment, and training employees to recognize and protect themselves against mold."</p>]]>
    <![CDATA[<p>By remaining vigilant about taking mold-related safety precautions and having a strong sense of what consequences may occur in the absence of such vigilance, workers can help themselves remain safe and healthy on the job.</p> <p>OSHA is releasing a mold safety fact sheet on its website in order to help workers remain educated about this critical safety hazard. However, an OSHA spokesperson recently reinforced that the fact sheet and employee education efforts do not replace employer obligations to protect workers and provide them with protective equipment designed to limit mold exposure.</p> <p><strong>Source</strong>: United States Department of Labor, "US Labor Department's OSHA issues new fact sheet on mold hazards and safeguards for workers during Sandy cleanup," Dec. 5, 2012</p>]]>
  </content>
  <!--toxic-exposure-->
</entry>

</feed>